hey everybody john wagon here with dev
central we're coming to you with another
light board lesson and today we're gonna
go over the Oh wash top ten
vulnerabilities and we've we've got had
a couple other videos on this today
we're talking about the four the number
four vulnerability on that list and it's
the XML external entities or it's the
acronym that they use is X X which by
the way I don't know why they they call
it X X C because it's XML external
entities but nonetheless somebody named
it xx see that's what it is
essentially what this vulnerability does
is it takes advantage of XML processors
or XML parsers in your web application
that might process or parse some bad
data so let me give you kind of a kind
of an example here let's say you have a
web application here and that web
application is built with the foundation
of you know a lot of different stuff but
one of the things that it has the
capability of or that it allows things
to do or that it takes advantage of is
an XML parser and I'll just put XML
parser and and this web app again it's
gonna it's gonna be you know built with
lots and lots of different things but
one of those things again is an XML
parser
all right so let's say you have an XML
parser and you either I'll say accept
XML input directly XML directly or maybe
you take some some other XML input and
then you let the XML parser parse
through that input so again the web
application it may directly accept XML
and process it itself or you have an XML
parser that is a part of your web
application that would parse XML input
or an XML file so nonetheless you've got
XML going on on your web application
okay sometimes these XML documents will
contain or a reference to an external
entity so as the XML document
self is built then you know you may have
like you know XML I'll just say you know
doc right here and it's got lots of
different things you know that make up
the XML document but I'll and and this
is certainly not perfect syntax you can
go into XML syntax to figure out exactly
how XML documents are built but let's
say that there's a that there's a
reference here to an external like an
external entity and so I'll put that
right there or like an external type
document in the in the XML document
alright what this what this could allow
an attacker to do is put some kind of a
malicious payload in that external
entity and then if the XML parser or the
XML documents that is that it's parsed
or processed by your web application if
that doesn't check things properly on
this external entity reference then the
bad payload that's in that thing could
get run and then it could do bad things
for the the contents of what your web
application would hold so things like
let's say for example that this that
some bad guy put in some malicious
reference here to say hey I want to try
to run a system command on your web
application and I want to I want to
trick it into giving me all your
passwords that are stored on your web
application for example or maybe I want
to run some other system command that
would do some kind of malicious
something or another if if the XML
parser is not configured properly then
then it's going to run that command and
it's going to you know spill all that
data and so that's not a good thing
there are a lot of Java XML parsers that
have xxe enabled by default that's just
the way that they're built because xxe
in and of itself is not inherently a bad
thing and certainly with some of the
older versions of xml they were it's a
necessary thing so you've got to go
through and look at you know how these
things are configured and so anyway so
sometimes java will have that
enabled by default one one specific
example of an attack that could happen
with with these XML external entities is
is an attack called the billion laughs
so I'm gonna put I'm gonna put this up
here and I had to I had to kind of laugh
a little bit when I read about this and
kind of kind of do a little research on
this basically what happens here what
the what the attacker bad guys gonna do
I'm gonna kind of write out the XML file
that would be sent into this XML parser
that doesn't validate things properly
it's not going to be perfect syntax but
you'll get the idea
all right let's say you have this XML
file and it's XML version 1.0 and then
you've got it it defines the document
type all right so it's gonna have that
and this one is going to be called lol's
you know cuz lols and then there's going
to be some entities defined in here
entity and one entity is going to be lol
one then there will be other entities
and this will be lol too lol 3 all the
way down to lol 9 alright so there's all
these entities there's also an element
that's defined called lol's as well
anyway the point is the the the way that
this works is the entity lol 1 is going
to is going to have the contents of its
have the contents of that is going to be
lol 1
semicolon lol 1 so forth and so on it's
going to have like 10 of these out there
and in lol 2 is going to have lol - lol
- anyway these these entities are going
to have the definition of what this
entity contains is all these little lol
s all the way all the way across so
whenever you send this malicious payload
basically you're going to send ello
z lolz it's gonna look something like
this you're gonna have this little and
ampersand and then you're gonna send it
this LOL nine alrighty and then you'll
have lolz to close it out alright I know
that's not great penmanship basically
you're gonna say hey run this lol nine
well lol nine is going to be it's going
to consist of a bunch of lol eights and
then the lol eights are going to consist
of a bunch of lol 7s and then six and
five and four and all the way all the
way up when it's all said and done you
would have sent a document that's less
than one kilobyte in size and you're
going to make this parse or this XML
processor on your web application have
to crunch through approximately three
gigabytes of memory or use up three
gigabytes of memory to crunch through
this entire document so in effect it's
like a denial of service attack it's
this completely asymmetric attack you
send it one little bitty file and ask to
crunch through like three gigs of memory
all right so that's that's just one
example of what may happen here if you
don't have the XML parser configured
properly so the question is well what do
we do to help with this one thing is you
can disable xxe completely on your web
application and if you can't do it
completely then you would look at all
the different parts and pieces of your
web application basically and go through
each one and say hey how can i disable
this you know per you know per parser
another thing that you can do is disable
what's called DTD processing and and
that again if you can do it across the
entire web application then that's good
otherwise you go through each individual
XML processor or parser to say hey how
do I disable DTD on each of these
another thing you can do is you can
implement some positive server-side
input validation so as you as you accept
these XML inputs into your web
application do some input validation
before you just run the commands another
thing you can do is what's called source
code analysis
this tools or sassed and you can run
source code verification and testing
against your source code in your web
application to see if any of this is
vulnerable another thing you can do is
dine it what's called dynamic
application security testing or DAST and
you can run that against your web
application to say hey as we send things
like xxe you know attacks against it is
it vulnerable to those kinds of things
so anyway so those are a few things that
you can do to help mitigate this problem
another thing you can do is you can
implement what's called a web
application firewall or a laugh and that
helps with a lot of these things so if
you can't fix the problem in the code in
the web application itself then you can
add on a web application firewall which
is really handy as well so anyway so
again xxe that's the number for
vulnerability on the OWASP top 10 and we
just want to make sure you understood
what goes on here the problems that
could arise and hope you guys stay safe
out there and thanks for watching this
lightboard lesson video if you liked
this one make sure you subscribe to our
YouTube channel and we'll see you guys
out there in the community
you