you
hey everybody john wagon here with dev
central we're coming to you with another
light board lesson video and today we're
gonna talk about sensitive data exposure
this is one of the wasp top 10
vulnerabilities the new OWASP list was
just released the 2017 version and this
was number three on that list so it's a
pretty significant vulnerability out
there and so so we want to talk about it
so sensitive data exposure basically the
bottom line on this is where you have a
web application you have sensitive data
that's stored as a part of that and you
allow that sensitive data to be exposed
which is something you don't want to do
we hear about the stuff in the news like
all the time you know company acts just
got hacked and everybody's credit card
number is now you know available or
social security numbers or you know
whatever so you see it all the time in
the news so let's not be that guy let's
not be the one that allows the sensitive
data to be exposed here's kind of the
bottom line or a very generic sort of
description of it or a or a you know
scenario if you have a user out here in
the internet you have a web application
so I'll put web app right here user
wants to access the web application and
maybe there are you know several pages
you know that this web application has
that's you know it's built so you got
example.com example.com slash credit
card number example.com slash sensitive
data information page or whatever so you
know there's several pages that comprise
this whole web application you may also
have a couple of databases that this
thing utilizes all put database here
maybe a database here and let's say this
one is all of your you know username and
password all that stuff and then this
one over here of course is your credit
card numbers you know everybody's credit
card number that you do business with of
course you store all that maybe you
shouldn't store all that but anyway the
the issue is the user comes in they
access your web application and they
want to buy something on your online
marketplace for example they've
authenticated via the username and
password of course and you've stored
their credit card number for them so
that
they don't have to mess around with
looking at their credit card number on
their actual credit card they can just
one click purchase this thing you've
already got the credit card details
stored for them so super super nice for
them all right well the of course with
all that niceness comes potential
vulnerabilities and so you have bad guys
that want to come in and they want to
expose all of these credit card numbers
and all these usernames and passwords
and all that stuff and they use
different attacks to make that stuff
happen and and you know and then bad
things happen all right
a few different things I wanted to point
out as we look at the details of this is
let's say that of all these different
you know pages that comprise your web
applications some of them are use
encryption and some of them do not so
let's say that this one right here and
this one right here both use TLS
encryption and this one is just straight
you know HTTP with no encryption because
this is just like a page with some
pictures on it or something you know
it's not a big deal so maybe not all
your pages use that well as you develop
these sometimes you may you may sneak in
some some data onto a page that doesn't
use encryption but that data may be
sensitive so you need to be careful with
that also even with the pages that do
use TLS or SSL encryption maybe they use
weak cipher so I'll put weak ciphers
right here all right and the problem
with using weak ciphers is that they're
weak and bad guys could come in and say
hey I am going to use some different
tools to forcibly downgrade this
connection that the user would have with
this page from TLS back down to just
HTTP so even though this is sensitive
data on this page and you set it up with
TLS encryption debate the the fact that
you have weak ciphers could expose you
to the vulnerability of saying hey I'm
gonna bad guy could come in and force
this down to just HTTP instead of HTTPS
and then thereby I get get the data that
would be on that page so so that's a
that's a potential issue the another
another scenario might be that let's say
you had some kind of a like a file
upload flaw
for all these credit card numbers that
were stored in a file somewhere and the
user the bad guy was able to get in and
grab that file and upload the file and
let's say you even encrypted it you know
because you thought ahead like hey this
is sensitive data but but if you didn't
encrypt it very well then they could use
something like a rainbow table which is
a known list of you know password crack
that that they could run against that to
try to crack the password for that
encryption and then gain access to the
sensitive data and then once they have
the sensitive data especially if it's
like a social security number then that
that type of data doesn't really change
when you get you get that assigned at
birth and then that's yours for the rest
of your life
credit card number is going to change in
at least every few years so anyway so a
couple of things that you would need to
do to guard against this sensitive data
exposure other than you know you need to
build the web application properly of
course you need to you need to encrypt
all of the pages that need to be
encrypted maybe even encrypt all of them
you need to encrypt the sensitive data
at rest that sits there as a part of
your web application but I'm just going
to list a few sort of best practice or
mitigations that that you might have and
the first one that I would say is
classify your data so classify data all
right so we all know that not all of the
data that you would necessarily work
with is sensitive data again you may
have some like pictures that you have on
one of your websites that's not
necessarily sensitive data so classify
the data some a sensitive some is not
and then you need to apply controls
I'll put apply controls to that data so
if it's very sensitive then you need to
make sure it's very well you know
protected it was not sensitive at all
then maybe you don't have to worry as
much about it all right another one I
just mentioned this a second ago encrypt
data at rest so I'll put data at rest
okay so the data at rest again that
would qualify based on your data Kalasha
fication that data you need to make sure
and create you encrypted and you encrypt
it well with some strong encryption that
way if it's ever you know if anyone ever
gets that file or whatever it would be
then the data is encrypted and the other
thing you need to use is strong ciphers
and this gets back to the experience
that the user has with your web
application to begin with this
connection needs to be protected with
TLS encryption and you need to make sure
you use strong ciphers as you build out
that that TLS you know connection with
your end user again if you use weak
ciphers or if you have any weak cipher
at all in your cipher list then that
exposes you potentially just a problem
so make sure you use strong ciphers on
your web server because the web server
gets to determine what ciphers are used
in that TLS connection another one that
I'll put is I'll put possible or maybe a
consideration for I'll put P F S which
is perfect forward secrecy and then I'll
say and or H s T s which is HTTP strict
Transport Security perfect forward
secrecy is deals with this TLS
connection we've got some other light
boards on that that we can link to but
basically it it doesn't it's a it's a
stronger form of communication using the
TLS protocol between the user and the
webserver and then the HSTs basically
says hey if you want to communicate with
my web application then you have to do
it the HTTP it has to be an encrypted
communication there are some some little
gotchas on that one if once you go
h.t.t.h HSTs
then you can't really go back so you
know you can't put the toothpaste back
in the tube as it were on that thing so
once you make that decision which is a
decision towards security towards
strength you need to make sure you have
everything ready to go when you flip
that switch or else you could black hole
some things you could break some things
so just be careful on that one if you
want to go that route I'm not saying
don't use it just be careful when you do
alright so again sensitive data exposure
you have this sensitive data and you
don't want to expose it another thing
that I would say quickly is don't store
sensitive data
you absolutely have to store sensitive
data so if there's a if there's an
absolute requirement where you have to
sit there and store this data as part of
your web application or a database that
you control or whatever then okay but if
it if it is at all possible to you know
use the sensitive data and then delete
it and get rid of it and you know throw
it away you know right after that moment
that you needed it then do that so don't
don't hold on to this any longer than
you absolutely have to
so anyway because if the data is not
there then it can't be you know it can't
be exposed so that's kind of the the
idea behind that all right so again this
is the number three you know
vulnerability on the OWASP top ten on
this list that just came out sensitive
data exposure so it's happening a lot
again all you have to do is watch the
news these days and you see this kind of
stuff happening so do these things build
your web applications properly there are
some other things like you could put a
like a web application firewall in line
that may help with this you know help
help secure a lot of this sensitive data
exposure but nonetheless be careful out
there make sure you do things properly
and and let's be safe on the internet
today so thanks for watching this light
board lesson and we'll see you guys out
there in the community
you