hey everybody John wagged on here with
Deb central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video and
today we're back in the OWASP top 10 in
fact today we're at the very end of the
list we finally made it to the very end
this is the number 10 security risk on
the 2017 list and this security risk is
entitled insufficient logging and
monitoring it's interesting that they
mentioned both of those on this security
risk logging and monitoring they're
definitely connected but they're kind of
two different things you know you can
think of logging as when you have an
issue or an event that takes place in
your web application then you create a
log event for that monitoring is where
you need to take the extra step to
monitor those logs so it's not good
enough just to log you got to look at
the logs and we'll talk through that a
little bit but before you can look at
the logs you've got to make sure your
logs are set up correctly so we're gonna
talk about insufficient logging and
monitoring today and how you can how you
can guard against making that an issue
for your web application all right so
let's say you know we've talked a lot of
examples along the way but let's say you
have your web application here so I'm
gonna put web app and it's awesome and
people visit this thing every day and
they love it so you've got users coming
in you know and it's built with all
these different components and we've
talked about all these things on the top
10 list along the way but in terms of
logging and monitoring we'll talk about
logging first let's say that you have a
user out here and this user tries to log
into your web application and let's say
there is a failed login so I'm going to
put failed login all right well that
would be one event that you would want
to potentially log so I'm gonna say when
something like that happens in the
context of your web application that's
gonna that's going to create an event or
that will be an event so that's gonna
I'm gonna just put this event here in
the web application and that needs to
kick off some sort of log entry alright
so from a very broad context
if a if an event happens with respect to
your web application that you care about
then it needs to kick off some kind of a
log and then that log needs to be sent
to where it needs to be sent to in the
proper format in the proper way and all
that and then of course the monitoring
part comes in on top of that where you
got to have somebody or something that's
going to monitor that stuff so that you
can take the appropriate action as as
necessary okay so there are there are
certain things when you talk about all
right well what do we need to log you
know in the context of logging there are
several things that you would want to
that you would want to log and I'll and
I'll make a I'll tag a link on to this
but just to give you an idea of the
OWASP organization has a great cheat
sheet as it were that says hey this is a
cheat sheet for all the items that you
should be that you should care about
with respect to logging so anyways so
we'll we'll link to that but just so you
know it's out there a few of them are
certainly fail logging would be one but
any kind of from a from a larger broader
perspective any kind of warnings that
would happen you know in your web
application things like error messages
and I'll just put error messages those
are things that you would want to log as
well you would want to have alert
thresholds so I'll put alert thresholds
set appropriately and effectively
imagine the scenario where you know
maybe a user tries to log in with this
failed login thing again and you don't
have any kind of alert setup or your
thresholds or not
or not tuned correctly then it's not
gonna kick off any kind of alert or
maybe it's not gonna you know create a
log entry to begin with and so you want
to make sure that any kind of log or
alert thresholds are tuned properly so
that you can so you can have the proper
kind of logs another thing you want to
do is you don't want to spill
information in these logs so that if an
attacker were to try to gain access to
the log file itself then the attacker
would not be able to look at that log
file but
you know by virtue of the the things
that you're trying to log you're gonna
log things like you know these warnings
or fail logins or whatever imagine an
attacker actually getting access to the
log file itself and and being able to
read that then let's say for example the
attacker is trying to do something bad
and then they can read all your logs and
then they see in the logs that hey
you're you're checking all these failed
logins well then the attacker knows that
you're sort of on to him and it's like
okay I need to back off of that then
they can kind of tune their attack
vectors as it were so the bottom line on
all that is you don't want to have this
information from the log file itself
spilled so that someone else can read it
so as you as you store the logs or maybe
if you send the log files off to some
other you know centralized logging
system or service then you want to make
sure that you do that securely as well
so you don't you don't give away the log
information just to give you a couple of
statistics or maybe once one quick
statistic back in 2016 so a couple of
years ago the average time between data
breach and actual you know knowledge of
or discovery of the of the data breach
was just over one hundred and ninety
days that's over six months so I guess
from a strict time perspective over half
of the data breaches that we found out
about in 2016 didn't even happen in 2016
they haven't you know way before that
the the issue there of course is that
these these data breaches are happening
these attacks are happening and we just
have no idea that they're even out there
for four months so I mean these
attackers are just having their way with
these web applications for months and
months before we even have a clue that
they're in there so we need to shorten
that time to discovery and and then that
way our web applications will be a whole
lot safer or we can certainly respond a
lot quicker and that's what we want to
do just to give you one scenario of how
an attacker may come in and attack your
web application where this logging and
monitoring would come into play is let's
say for example you have an attacker who
either has access to your usernames
maybe a list of usernames on your
application or they're guessing the
usernames either way then they can run a
scan against your web application for
possible passwords and so they can use
maybe common passwords or you know some
kind of a dictionary attack whatever
that would be like hey let me try to do
some commonly used passwords against
this web application using the usernames
that you have or than I'm guessing so
let's say that they do that and let's
say that out of I don't know they'll say
you have a thousand of these things and
out of a thousand they get a hundred of
them that they're successful and in
matching password with username then
that's a great why it's great for them
it's not good for your web application
so then at that point they can
legitimately log in with those usernames
but the other thing is on the other nine
hundred they would only have guessed
that password one time against each of
those other nine hundred that they were
unsuccessful with so it would have
created a failed login but it would only
create one failed login attempt on your
web application for that specific
username so what you should be doing at
that point is if those if that was
logged then maybe maybe on one hand you
would say well there's only one failed
login attempt is that a big deal but
when you look at it in the aggregate if
you look at it collectively then you'll
see hey all these were failed logins you
know maybe in a very short amount of
time or you could start to see the
patterns there and that's why you need
to monitor your logs so so not only log
but monitor and if you do that
insufficiently which is this security
risk then you run into problems okay so
that's just one little scenario that
could happen the the thing that you want
to keep in mind and I'll just mention a
few things in terms of defending against
this and things that you ought to be
logging and monitoring for keeping in
mind as you go through this is the any
kind of any kind of login failure or
access control failure or server-side
validation failure those things need to
be logged and of course they need to be
monitored but they also need to have
sufficient User Content so that you can
actually take action against them so
I'll just make a little list of things
that you need to consider when you log
so I'll say sufficient sufficient
content alrighty so when you create that
log file you want to make sure it has
enough content so that when you come
back and monitor it then you'll know
what's going on in that thing you want
to have I'm gonna say good format all
right or usable format and basically
what this means is that you know you can
have all kinds of different formats when
it comes to log files let's say that you
have security logs and you have other
user you know user type you know access
logs or whatever it is then you want to
make sure that all those are in a proper
format so that when you compile those
together or if or again you're using
some kind of centralized you know
logging service then then they need to
be in a format that's that's easily
consumable that's in a good format that
that service can read all of the
different types of logs so keep that in
mind one of the things in terms of
content and content that I'll mentioned
again is that too much content is not a
good thing and too little content is not
a good thing if you have too much then
you can fill up these log files like
crazy quick and or you just use tons and
tons of space and and you may get just
you may just get drown and all the data
that you have
likewise if there's too little then
you're gonna look at it later needing to
say I have no idea what's going on here
because there's not enough information
to take action against so it's there's
an art to this there's a balancing act
between too much and too little
I guess personally what I would say is
maybe maybe lean a little more toward
the hey let me let me do a little more
content than I need and I can always
back off of that a little bit if there's
too much if it's filling up too quick
you certainly don't want the you don't
want the scenario where you try to come
in and you say hey let me take action
and I just have no clue what's going on
in this log side there's not enough
information there I would say another
thing that you need to consider is
integrity controls and I'll just write
this integrity controls and this gets
back to the situation I mentioned
earlier where you if you're going to
send your log files off especially kind
of high high value transactional logs
then you want to make sure that there's
sort of integrity controls or integrity
checks on the log file itself so that if
you send it from your web application to
some external source or even even if you
store it locally if that log file ever
gets changed then you want to know that
that has been changed that that data has
been compromised the integrity of the
data is not there anymore and you
certainly want to know that that means
there's something crazy going on some
nefarious act are doing something crazy
so put some integrity controls in place
on your log files and then finally
output I'll just put a response plan
response plan and this one is really
critical as well and the the essence of
this is that but let's say that you've
got your logs you figured out exactly
what you want to log you've run that
checklist and I talked about a second
ago I've you've looked at all these
different things that you need to
consider with format and integrity
control that the right amount of content
you've got all that now like I said you
need to monitor those so whether it's a
person that you've hired that just goes
through all these logs all the time or
maybe maybe you've automated that
whatever it is you need to be monitoring
these logs and it needs to happen all
the time and this needs to be a regular
thing that you do is monitor these logs
you don't want to be one of those 191
days it's like hey yeah it's been 191
days I finally got around to check-in
the logs and we've been breached you
know six months ago anyway so you have
monitored these things now it's time to
respond to the thing so some people may
say hey I just found out about this big
data breach that we had and I checked
the logs I monitored them I found out
about them now what in the world do I do
with it you know so some people are kind
of in that spot where they just have no
clue what to do next that's where you
need to have a response plan in place
like an incident response plan a
disaster recovery kind of a plan and
that's something that you can talk about
prior to all this or kind of outside
outside of setting all this up you can
say hey what when this happens if this
happens what are we going to do and what
are the steps that we're going to take
so people need to be aware that the
right people that are doing these things
need to be aware of this plan and then
they need to follow that plan if and
when the incident happens so hopefully
you won't be the victim of one of these
but chances
if you have a web application people are
gonna come attack it at some point so
better to be prepared than to you know
be caught completely off-guard you have
no idea what to do so so thanks for
sticking in there with us on this OWASP
top 10 thanks for watching the
insufficient logging and monitoring
light board that we did today and hey if
you liked this one you can you can click
the little DC ball up here and subscribe
to our deaf central youtube channel and
we will see you guys out there in the
community
you