hey everybody John wagged on here with
dev central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video and
today we're gonna talk about another one
of the OWASP top 10 security risks out
there in the world today and this one is
the number seven risk on the list
delicious came out in 2017 late 2017 so
it's the latest and greatest and this
security risk is titled cross-site
scripting or sometimes it's written as X
SS but anyway cross-site scripting it's
interesting that this is number seven on
the list because the last time the OWASP
list came out in 2013 it was the number
three security risk out there and in the
time before that the 2010 version it was
the number two so so actually it's kind
of moved down the list a little bit
which I guess in a sense is good it
means we're getting better at defending
cross-site scripting but anyway today
we're gonna talk about what it is and
how you can defend against it so
ultimately cross-site scripting is
client-side code injection is kind of
the the overarching idea of what it is
and essentially an attacker is trying to
steal your stuff and the attacker is
gonna send this code that he wants your
browser to execute in order to send him
all of your secret stuff so again the
question is how does all that work and
all that so let's let's kind of write a
or I'll draw kind of a an example of how
this may work there's a lot of different
types of cross-site scripting but I'm
gonna give you a scenario of one that's
pretty prevalent and and one where the
attacker is trying to steal your session
cookie so that the attacker can then
impersonate you to the website that
you're going to and and then he can do
all kinds of stuff you know when he has
your secrets so alright so the the
cross-site scripting vulnerability
really takes three things to to happen
it takes an attacker so I'm going to put
the attacker right here so attacker
and then it takes a web application so
here's a web app over here alright and
and then and in this case the web
application is vulnerable and then it
also takes a victim so I'm gonna put the
victim over here this is the this is the
unsuspecting person that is about to get
attacked and doesn't even know it all
right so the attacker what the attacker
is gonna do is he's gonna find a web
application that is vulnerable to
cross-site scripting and he's gonna send
it some code so this web application I
mean let me just kind of draw it out
here a little bit it consists of several
different parts and pieces and all that
but one of the things it has is a
database so I'm gonna put a DB right
here it's a database and then it also
has let's say some HTML code all right
which is very common in a web
application all right and let's say that
this that this HTML code allows for
scripts to be run in it which is one
thing that you may not want to do in
this case but but anyway I'll kind of
run through a scenario of how this
attacker is gonna get the victims
secrets and it's gonna get it through
this vulnerable web application all
right first thing it's gonna do is it's
gonna send a post to this web
application and the post is going to
include I'll put a little script right
here so it's gonna have script you know
dot dot dot whatever and then it's gonna
you know the end of the script script
like that alright so what this script is
is trying to do is trying to say hey I
want to get the cookie from the victim
and I want that victim to send its
cookie up to me and it's going to post
that to the database of this web
application and so ok it's it does that
so that's where the database could say
hey I'm not going to allow you to you
know post scripts into the database and
let's say this web application for
example allows users to comment on stuff
or maybe post a question or post of you
know hey I really loved that picture
that you got or whatever it is which is
very common today but anyway
nonetheless it's the attackers gonna
post the script and then the database is
gonna have that post the latest comment
or the latest posts in that database is
going to be this script and then where
the HTML code comes in is let's say that
the HTML code allows for the printing of
the latest comment in this database so
as the HTML code runs if someone were to
access this web application and say hey
I'd love to see the latest comment on
that awesome picture that we've just
posted then this HTML code that runs the
comment from the database allows the
database comment to be you know posted
kind of thing again a fairly common type
scenario all right well what the victim
is going to do I'm gonna put a couple
little boxes around the attacker and the
victim what the victim is going to do is
he is going to send a get request yet to
this web application and so it's gonna
be you know maybe HTTP example.com
whatever and then and maybe maybe also
at the end of this it's going to say you
know maybe DB DB comment
all right so hopefully can read all that
penmanship there
all right so example.com / DB comment
and it's gonna send that to this web
application and essentially what that is
trying to do is it's going to say hey I
want the latest comment from the
database and then this HTML code is
gonna is going to allow to print you
know the DB comment and it's going to
send that back with a I'm gonna say a
200 okay because it's like hey you
you've requested a valid page from me
and when it says that 200 okay it's also
gonna send the contents of this HTML
code and it's gonna say you know HTML
you know header 1 this is the latest DV
comment and then the next HTML line it's
going to print the latest DB comment
which the latest DB comment is the
script that this attacker put in the
database and so ultimately it's going to
on this victim's browser it's gonna have
this HTML code that has the script that
the attacker sent that he ultimately
wanted the victim to you know to execute
in the browser so once that script
executes so the script is going to be
there's gonna be since that's script
it's going to be sent as part of this
okay message in the HTML code that now
gets executed on the victims browser so
that script right there is going to be
run on the victims browser and then what
the the one of the questions is well
what's in the script
well the script let's say that the
script is written to say that it wants
the it wants the cookie from the victim
and it wants it to be sent up here so
it's going to send a get request let's
say to the attacker and it's going to
send it to you know to the website so
it's going to be you know HTTP evil.com
slash you know cookie
equals the value of the cookie so let's
say in a one-two-three-four you know
whatever it is all right so I know that
that's a lot going on here again the
attacker sends a or posts a script into
the database of this vulnerable web
application the HTML code allows for the
user input to be executed whenever it
sends it to the unsuspecting victim once
that script is over here on the victims
browser the victim's browser then runs
and executes the HTML code that was sent
to it the HTML code includes that script
and then that script automatically kicks
off a get request to the attackers
website that he has up here already set
up and it sends along with the gits you
know to the attacker it includes the
cookie from the victim from the victims
machine a couple of things that you
could ask is well hey how does the
victim know to even send the get request
over here to this web application that
the attacker has infected that gets in
the you know social engineering spear
fishing fishing whatever it is you know
you guys have seen that all the time hey
don't click on any link that you don't
trust or you know any number of ways
that the attacker could coerce the
victim to click on this link which would
then kick off this entire thing another
issue is the victim's browser has to be
willing to run this script in the HTML
that comes over if for some reason the
victims browser is like hey this HTML
code has this has this script stuff in
it that I don't really feel comfortable
with and it doesn't run that then you're
okay and I think that's part of the
reason that cross-site scripting has
come down that list so much from used to
be number two number three now it's now
it's number seven our browsers have
gotten a lot better in in recent past or
in recent history whatever also the web
application so that's one way to defend
against this is make sure you use a
modern browser that kind of inherently
protects against cross-site scripting
another one is if you're building this
web application you need to you need to
separate untrusted data from active
browser content and any kind of user
input data needs to be considered
untrusted data so you
two separate active browser content from
untrusted data so that's kind of a very
overarching way to approach this whole
cross-site scripting issue all right so
you need to you need to make sure that
your web application is secure and then
on the victims side if you're just a
typical user out there and you have no
idea all this stuff's kind of going on
make sure you use a browser that's that
inherently tries to defend against
cross-site scripting all right so that's
kind of that's that's one one sort of
overarching example in a nutshell there
are other ways to defend against this
you can put a web application firewall
in front of your web application and in
any kind of potential cross-site
scripting attack that comes in from the
attacker that web application firewall
is going to kill it before it even gets
to your web application so there's a
number of things you can do but
nonetheless cross-site scripting still
out there can be very dangerous if it's
if it's allowed to run its course so so
thanks for watching this lightboard
lesson video and if you like this make
sure you subscribe to our youtube
channel here at dev central and we'll
see you guys out there in the community
you