hey everybody John wagging on here with
Deb central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video and
today we're back in the wasp
top 10 and this is the number 9 out of
10 security risks out there on the list
and this list or this this security risk
is called using components with known
vulnerabilities so I guess the easy the
easy thing to say and many people would
maybe think well hey just don't use
components in your web application that
have known vulnerabilities right well
that's easier said than done typically
when you build out your web application
you're gonna pick and choose different
things that you need to create that web
application and inevitably something is
going to have a vulnerability that is
known so let me I'll just draw a couple
things up here we'll talk through you
know kind of a situation and how to have
a guard against it so let's say you have
your awesome web applications so here's
your web your web app out here that that
everyone loves and they visited all the
time and you get a million you know hits
a day or whatever so whenever you build
this thing it has some fundamental
components to it right so maybe you have
a maybe you have a web server of course
right maybe you have a cenar maybe you
have a I'll put a DB like a database
server and let's say this web server
let's say you choose to use Apache
that's a pretty pretty common one let's
say for database use Oracle that's
another pretty common one let's say that
because you're all interested in
security you want to make sure that the
clients that access your web application
come in encrypted so we're going to use
tls/ssl capabilities so that's so your
web address is gonna be HTTPS you know
web app comm kind of thing alrighty so
that's just a very basic list of course
but you can start to understand that
there's a lot of different components
that go into your
application I went out there and looked
recently and and checked out like say on
the Apache web server our Apache web
servers you know do they have any known
vulnerabilities on them there's there's
a pretty common one out there that's
it's called the struts I'm just gonna
kind of start writing all this across
here so there's a stretched
vulnerability that's unique to the
Apache web server it's it's based on the
different verb AIST on what you know
version you have an Apache web server
could be vulnerable to this struts
vulnerability another one say for Oracle
there's a there's a java java vm oracle
database server known vulnerability out
there and by the way there are many many
many known vulnerabilities that i could
list here unique to apache or oracle or
any number of components that you might
use for tls/ssl there's a pretty common
one back in april of 2014
called heart bleed and if you did not
configure your tls/ssl configuration
correctly you may be vulnerable to
what's called heartbleed and you guys
probably remember that one interestingly
there's a website called show Dan and it
does a scan of all the all these
internet websites web applications
whatever I did one literally today and
check to see is anyone still vulnerable
I mean this thing's been out there for a
number of years now is anyone still
vulnerable to heartbleed and and the the
list that I came up with today there was
almost a hundred and twenty thousand web
applications still vulnerable to
heartbleed today so so just because it's
an old one out there and it's like you
know you may think hey that one's kind
of I'm kind of gone and we're not
worried about that one anymore the truth
is that many you know web applications
may still be vulnerable these legacy
applications or whatever all right so so
you start to get the idea that as you
build your web application you're going
to probably be forced into a situation
where you have to use components that
have known vulnerabilities there's kind
of some good and bad with that the good
part of the known vulnerabilities is we
do know about them so we know what to
you know to protect and fix and all that
stuff the bad part about it is we do
know about them and so if we know about
them then the bad guys know about them
and they know to go and exploit those so
so let's say for example you've got a
web application using these different
things and for one reason or another the
attacker bad guy is going to say hey I
know that you're using an Apache web
server maybe you're disclosing too much
information or that kind of thing and
they understand that the version that
you're using and then they can go and do
you know a Google search for hey how can
i exploit this Apache web server on that
version they find out that you're
vulnerable to the struts vulnerability
and then they can know exactly what to
go after so again the good part is if
you use a vulnerable version of this
you'll know what to protect for if you
but if you use the vulnerable version
then the attacker knows what to attack
for kind of things so he knows the exact
attack space as it were all right so
that's the situation known are
components with known vulnerabilities a
couple of things to consider here is in
terms of guarding against this is I'm
gonna say continuous inventory of your
clients and servers so I'll just say
I'll just put inventory up here
inventory and I'll put clients and
servers alright so which by the way in
your business you know from a business
perspective you've got a lot of clients
out there - that may be vulnerable with
various components so it may not just be
web servers that we're talking about
here so from a business perspective from
a total ownership perspective you need
to you need to constantly be committed
to inventory incluso that's you control
and then that way you can know you know
what's what's out there what to look for
all of that so do a continuous inventory
as it were and then I'm gonna say
download components from trusted sources
or official sources so I'll just put
I'll put downloads
I'll just put downloads for now but
basically the idea here is if you are
going to download some software
you know you're not necessarily gonna
walk down the street and buy it at the
at the you know at the counter to offer
whatever with the person standing there
maybe you are but likely you're going to
download the software right so when you
download this software maybe it's a
patchy or Oracle or whatever it is then
make sure you get it from a proper
official channel you may even want to
make sure that it's digitally signed to
ensure that it's coming from a reputable
source if you're downloading a bunch of
stuff off of some crazy websites that
you don't even know where they're coming
from then you know then that opens up
the chance that your downloads your
software maybe I don't know maybe full
of holes or it may not be exactly what
you wanted it to be so that could be
problematic
so make sure you download from the right
places I'm gonna say I'm just gonna put
plan over here plan for things like
monitoring
I'll put monitor I'm gonna put patch
we're gonna say config those kinds of
things so have a plan in place to say
hey I know what my components are that
that make up the entirety of my web
application and I'm going to monitor
those those components I'm going to
patch those components so as a patch
comes out from the you know let's say in
Apache whatever Apache releases a patch
to handle this stretch problem so we
need to patch that we need to configure
our clients and servers properly and we
need to stay on top of that but all of
this goes back to let me have a plan and
make sure that I've that I you know that
I do things according to the plan that I
have in place all right so with all of
this like I said I know that it's it's
inevitable that you're going to put
components in your web application that
have known vulnerabilities so it's it's
really hard to get around that so what
we need to do is we need to come down
here and just make sure that we're
constantly checking these things a
couple of couple of things that I'll
finish up with are some databases one is
called the C V II and then another one
is the in V D alright the C V E stands
for common
vulnerabilities and exploits and then
the nvd is the national vulnerability
database so I'll put links to these you
know with this video but you can go and
if and you can check hey here's the
companies are the components of my web
application let me let me check against
these two databases as it were to see if
there's any vulnerabilities that are
known with the components that I have so
again number nine on the list of the top
ten o wasp fusing components with known
vulnerabilities it's an inevitable thing
so while they're all while while there
are vulnerabilities out there we can
still take steps to mitigate those and
and ensure that that we that we stay on
top of this as much as possible so
thanks for watching this light board
lesson video hey if you liked this video
you can click Subscribe right here on
this DC ball and we'll see you guys out
there in the community
you