hey everybody John wagging on here with
Deb central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video and
today we're gonna go over another one of
the OWASP top ten security risks out
there and the new version just came out
recently and back in 2017 today we're
going to talk about the number five
vulnerability out there the number five
security risk and it's called broken
access control which very quickly this
is not to be confused with
authentication some people confuse
authentication and access authentication
is verifying your identity like hey if
I'm gonna access something someone needs
to make sure hey are you John or not
that's authentication access control is
as about giving me access to the
different resources that I need to gain
access to or frankly keeping me away
from the resources that I don't need to
be touching so so when we talk about
access control it is it is taking the
access that you need to give some users
allowing them to access functions and
features and then keeping everyone else
out so all right so with that said let's
say you have your your world class web
application here and it is comprised of
a whole lot of different stuff but built
into this thing you have different
functions and different features and and
those kinds of things so let's say for
example you have like some admin
functions so here's an admin little
chunk right here let's say you have I'm
gonna just call it like you know normal
normal user functions that you would
want anyone to have this is kind of like
that public facing stuff let's say you
have some auditing features with like
logs and you know all kinds of different
stuff all right so you maybe you have
different parts and pieces or different
features of your web application that
you want to give certain people access
to or not
well so out here people that are going
to be accessing this web application
there's a lot of different types of
users so you
I'll just put I'll put normal user out
here this is your everyday you know
let's say your web application your I
don't know you're selling something
that's that's what you do that's what
your web application does and you want
all kinds of people in the public to
come out here and access your web
application and buy all your stuff you
know so you have all these typical
normal users and you want them to do
these normal user features and functions
of course but let's say you also have
some admins let's say you have like some
super users super users let's say you
have maybe like an audit group or an
audit you know type of a user that wants
to you know do some log analysis or
whatever so you know you've got all
these different different types of users
out there well for the admin functions
you may only want the admin guys to
access that the normal users only need
to have access to this part of your web
application and actually the admin can
do the normal user functionality and
they can do that you can maybe they can
access the audit stuff maybe the audit
guys can only access the audit stuff you
get the point here so there's different
types of users that can access the
different parts and pieces and features
of your web application one of the one
of the things to check for this broken
access control the problem that we're
talking about today and again the broken
access control is where let's say for
example a normal user or what would
appear to be a normal user gains access
to admin functions on your web
application or they gain access to some
audit log files or that kind of stuff
places that they don't need to be so the
access controls that you have put in
place would then be broken of course one
of the one of the things that's
interesting about this as some people
say we'll use these use these different
tools like DAST
the DAST tool is the dynamic application
security testing tool or sass is another
one and sass is the static application
security testing tool some people call
that the source code analysis tool but
anyway - and sassed one of the issues
would ask
sass is that they can they do a good job
of identifying whether an access control
is in place or not whether it's present
or absent and they'll let you know that
but if it's present let's say they they
don't do a great job necessarily of
telling you how functional it is or how
effective it is so so one of the things
that you really need to do with broken
access control is to do a lot of manual
testing and a lot of manual checks to
make sure that you've got this thing
under control I'm going to give a quick
example of this web application of
someone that may come in there and be
able to access a spot or a thing that
they don't need to gain access to so
here's an example a bad hacker guy comes
in to your you know web web app dot-com
all right and that's let's say that
that's the URL for your web application
and you want all your normal users to be
able to access that and buy a bunch of
stuff and do great things but let's say
the bad guy comes in and he puts this
slash and he changes the URL and he puts
admin info all right so let's say that
admin info is a place on your web
application that a normal user does not
need to get to well if a normal user can
access that URL right there then that's
a problem that means you've probably had
some broken access controls another
example let's let's just do this again
what about dot-com and let's say someone
tries to change some query parameters so
let's say they want some they're trying
to get to somebody's account information
so let's say account info all right so
they're gonna try to get there and then
they're gonna do a little parameter and
then they'll say account equals and I'll
just put like one two three four all
right so if I'm a user and I do not own
account one two three four and I type
that in and I can get to that then
that's a problem that means you got some
broken access control so those are a
couple of different things that maybe
some checks or some ways that
that that this broken access control
would manifest itself all right so what
are some ways to to get around this or
to help with this a few are that you
need to enforce all of this in what I'll
call trusted server-side code all right
so do do all of these checks or the
access control features in trusted
server-side code first of all I talked
about Dass and SAS tools where those
those are effective tools to use but
don't count on those exclusively for
broken access control you know checks or
functionality another thing that you can
do is deny by default so other than this
like normal user stuff that you want the
entire public to see then deny
everything else by default and then only
give it out to who needs who needs to
use it implement these access controls
one time and then reuse them so rather
than building access control features
and functionality around save this part
of your web application and others
around this and others around this build
them one time make sure that they make
sense and they're secure in there
they're powerful and then reuse those
across the web application so that's
that's another good way to to you know
secure yourself against broken access
control another one is log your your
failures and alert your admins whenever
that happens so you can shoot off you
know emails or you know different
notification warnings to your admins
whenever failures are logged you can
also rate limit access to some of these
different features so let's say an
admins try to get in and let's say let's
say a bad guy is trying to get into a
spot that they're not trying to get into
and it's an automated kind of a tool
well if you rate limit the access to
that then you'll minimize your your
exposure and your your problem areas and
then the last thing that I would say is
this concept of least privilege least
privilege is is the idea that you're
only going to give someone access to the
minimum extent that they need it to do
their job or to do that function and
beyond that you're only going to give
them that access for the minimum amount
of time that they need to do the job
so that really limits the exposure and
the problems and all that so you know
again if an admin only needs to do this
one thing or maybe a super user whatever
it is only needs to do this one thing
then only give them minimal access to
that one thing for the minimum amount of
time unnecessary
so again broken access control the
number five security risk out there on
the Internet today based on the OWASP
top 10 list this is kind of what it is
there there are also some other things
like web application firewalls that can
help with some of this I won't say it's
the end-all be-all but there are some
there are some things that those can
help with as well with regards to to
broken access control so thanks for
hanging in there today with us learning
about broken access broken access
control stay safe out there on the
internet if you enjoyed this video make
sure you subscribe to our dev Central
YouTube channel and we will see you guys
out there in the community
you