hey everybody john wagon on here with
deaf central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video today
we're gonna be in the old wasp top ten
again today is the number eight out of
ten security risk on the OWASP list the
name of this risk is insecure
deserialization
and this is new to the top ten actually
this year it was not on the last top 10
list mainly partly because it's so hard
to say no I don't think that's actually
true but anyway but it's a it probably
takes the award for the hardest security
risk to say I'm it on the entire top 10
list
anyway insecure deserialization so many
of you may be asking what is insecurity
deserialization and i guess to talk
about that we need to back up and talk
about the concept of serialization and
in web applications you'll have an
object so I'm just gonna write a couple
things here so you'll have an object out
here maybe you have like a you have like
a PHP you know site or PHP forum that's
you that you want to host and you have
this object and then you want and then
you need to send it across a network to
another place or whatever maybe need to
store it in a database or store it in
memory or that kind of thing the the
concept of serialization is taking an
object and transferring it or turning it
into what I'll call a byte stream or a
stream or a stream of bytes so that it
can be in the proper format in order to
traverse things like an HTTP network or
so that it can be stored in a database
or to maybe save the memory that kind of
thing some of the reasons that you would
use serialization is because you can
save or persist the state of the object
so that whenever you send it across the
wire then you know then this then the
state of the persistence is still there
so when you when you take an object and
you turn it into a stream of bytes or
into byte stream format
then that is the process of
serialization so just like in most
things networking whenever you do
something one way and then you send it
across and the person receiving it is
going to have to undo that and so the
same is true here so when you take that
stream of bye to that byte stream and
then you turn it back into that that
same object then that turning it from
bikes treatment back into object is
deserialization
many many programming languages today
utilize this or have the capability to
serialize objects for the for the
reasons that I stated plus many others
so this this concept of serialization
deserialization is out there in web
applications today so the the question
is how could this be a problem and the
kind of the bottom line answer is this
gets back to other security risks that
we've kind of seen a pattern of as we
walk through this top 10 and that is if
you take untrusted user input and you
don't validate that and then you allow
that untrusted user input to be
deserialized from byte stream back into
object then an attacker could take
advantage of that and throw an insert
untrusted untrusted input and the this
process of D serialization could cause
that attackers you know attack vector to
do bad things to your web application so
let's say for example I'll go back to
this PHP let's say we have a PHP forum
so I'm gonna and it uses these objects
and let's say that as a part of that
forum we want to save a save I'm gonna
say this cookie that includes a lot of
different things and the things that it
includes I'm going to write them right
here I'm gonna say user ID I'm gonna say
it includes they're maybe their password
or I'm sorry maybe a role that they have
maybe it includes like some password
hash information things like that maybe
the state of the
you know whatever it is so let's say
that there's a super cookie that is used
in this PHP forum that includes all
these different you know attributes of
what this object would have all right so
let's say that in a typical scenario you
have Alice who is going to save her
cookie here and so the the the proper
format would be you know Alice and then
her role let's say is user and then
maybe her password hash is you know one
two three four and then maybe like it
maybe you save some state type
information and you know that's X Y Z
whatever it is all right so that's a
that's a typical user in this forum and
that's the that's the super cookie as it
were object that's that's saved well
let's say that an attacker comes in and
your web application does not validate
the user input and so an attacker is
going to be able to insert this
serialized data and then as you
deserialize it then it's gonna run some
malicious stuff so let's say that the
attacker comes in and is able to put
information in this super cookie and
let's say that is Eve now they change
the user name to Eve and maybe they
changed the role from user to admin and
then they keep the same password hash
because they know that it that it gets
them in and then the state is going to
be the same as well alright so
effectively what the attacker has done
is taken taken this object taking
advantage of the fact that it is
serialized and of course deserialized
and then when when they insert this
malicious code as it were now they have
effectively when this is deserialized
because this user input is not validated
on the web application side then they've
given themselves admin access into that
into that web application effectively so
what are some of the things that could
happen with this well ultimately you
could have things like remote code
execution that could start happening
here that would be a really bad thing of
course you could do some denial of
service attacks using using
vectors like this any number of things a
couple of things that I'll say about
insecure deserialization is that it's
not that easy for most people to find
these because it's kind of this niche
area so you would need to you need to
really scrub the code you would need to
use a lot of scanning tools and frankly
some human intervention as well to say
hey are we deserializing and proper
things and doing it in an insecure way
so this does take a little more human
interaction to to check it out and to
make sure or to know if you're
vulnerable to this but nonetheless it is
it is a threat out there it's on the top
ten so so we need to make sure that
we're prepared to guard against this
again I've said it before I'll say it
one more time the the main I guess if I
if I could say one thing overall on this
it's do not accept untrusted user input
or make sure you validate any kind of
user input so so anyway so that's that's
just a good approach to take that I'll
handle actually more than one of the top
ten list security risk there are some
other things that you could do in
addition to you know fixing this on the
web application side of course and in
the code itself like a Web Application
Firewall you could put that in front of
your web application and so as a
potential deserialization you know
insecure deserialization attack is
attempted at your web application then a
web application firewall could could
notice that and could stop that before
it ever gets to your web application so
that's that's another thing you could do
so again number eight on the list
insecure D serialization it's out there
it's a problem it's gaining traction
frankly so I wouldn't be surprised if
it's actually higher on the list the
next time the top ten comes out so so be
aware of this guard yourself against it
and thanks for watching this light board
lesson video today hey if you liked this
one make sure you subscribe to our
YouTube channel you can click the little
DC ball here and subscribe to our
YouTube channel and we will see you guys
out there in the community
you