hey everybody john wagon on here with
deb central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson video and
today we're gonna do another one of the
top ten security risks out there today
is risk number six on the list of the
ten and and risk number six is called
security miss configuration
alright so big big words for for the for
this latest one all right basically what
this is what this the the the
fundamental problem that exists with
security miss configuration is that you
have a web application and it is
comprised of several different things
and there are default accounts there are
you know standard things that come
shipped with various parts and pieces
and you don't reconfigure those or you
don't configure your web application
properly so let me just draw a little a
little example here so let's say you've
got your world class web application
here and it is comprised of a lot of
different stuff so i'm just going to
draw kind of this this box that
represents your web application let's
say you have a web server that is part
of this of course right let's say you
have a database I'll put DB server
alrighty let's say you have maybe some
kind of authentication capabilities so
the point is you've got a web
application you've got a lot of
different parts and pieces that comprise
this web application alright so let's
say on your web server you have chosen
to deploy the Apache web server so
Apache here
Apache alrighty which is a very common
web server alright
the Apache web servers and granted there
are many versions and all that kind of
stuff
Apache I went looked earlier today and
it has over 200 known vulnerabilities
depending on the version and all that
but if you look at the patch is in
general there are over 200 known
vulnerabilities with Apache web servers
let's say you have Oracle for example
for your data
server alrighty there are like 50 some
some odd Oracle known vulnerabilities
authentication may be used in sam'l or
authorities with all of those things so
the point is that whenever you build
your web application and you build it
with these parts and pieces then
whatever you have chosen to use to build
this whole thing you need to understand
there are there are vulnerabilities
right out of the box with these with
these different you know features or
with this with this different software
okay some of the things that could
happen in terms of security miss
configuration is maybe you have some
unnecessary features enabled on your web
application so again let's go back to
the web server for example Apache you
deploy it right out of the box maybe
it's got some features that just it
comes you know defaults configured but
you don't need that for your web
application so it is a good idea to go
through and say hey what do I actually
need and what do I not need and if you
don't need it then it is a good idea to
turn it off to delete it whatever it is
so don't use what you don't need because
think of it as hey if I have something
enabled then that is a potential risk
that is a potential door to allow the
bad guys to get in so if I don't need it
then I need to turn it off default
accounts would fall underneath that so
like an admin account let's say with you
know with a certain server that it comes
with you know admin and the password is
admin and everybody on the internet
knows that so if you don't change that
admin account and certainly the password
then you open yourself up there are some
error handling things that may happen
where let's say that a user comes to
access your web application and they get
some kind of an error page and the way
that you handle those errors let's say
that you give them back a page that says
hey I'm sorry you have reached the page
that doesn't exist or whatever but as a
as a part of that error page that you
present back to the user
maybe you list hey by the way I'm using
Apache version blah blah blah or I'm
using Oracle you know this came from a
database Oracle database it's version
this and then that gives an attacker it
would be attacker
the exact you know type of software that
you have used to build this web
application and then they don't even
have to guess anymore what kind of web
server you have now they know the type
and the version and all that stuff and
then they can say hey tell me the
vulnerabilities on that specific one all
right so so as you handle errors or
error pages in your web application you
need to make sure that you don't over
share information there are security
features that come you know naturally
with these different servers or code or
whatever and let's say Apache releases
an update then you need to make sure
that you put that update on your web
application so all the latest security
patches and features need to be enabled
so again don't don't just use the
default another one that that is
problematic is whenever your web server
responds back to a client maybe it does
not send any kind of a security header
you know on the HTTP response back to
the client so there are these security
headers that you can use in an HTTP
response and you should use those so
those are those are some things that in
terms of configuration of the web
application itself those are things that
you need to to keep in mind one thing
that can help with this is an automated
scanning capability so like a like a
dashed
tool I could come in and check in ahead
you have default account set up do you
have the latest patches on your on your
different servers or your web
application in general so a you know an
automated testing tool is a good thing
to use alrighty so those are some of the
problem areas that could happen with
security mists configuration some things
that that I'll list in terms of how to
help with this is I'm gonna say
repeatable repeatable processes
repeatable process and I'll just put
that all right and what I mean by that
is you need a a hardening process I
don't want to write that all up there
but you need a repeatable hardening
process that will say hey how do i
hardened my web application from all the
things that we've already talked about
you know the default password
the security or the the error handling
all those different things I need to I
need to figure out a process that will
harden this down and it needs to be
repeatable it needs to be easy to to to
do to automate that kind of our
automation would be nice to be able to
do so you need to be able to run this
process against your web application and
do it repeatedly all righty
another one is all servers I'll say all
servers need to have let's say same
config alright and what what I mean by
that is you have your maybe you have
your development server that you're
developing all this stuff in then you
have like a QA or like a test server
that you want to test everything in and
you have your production server that
that's facing the internet all of these
servers from from a security
configuration perspective need to have
the exact same configuration that way
when you run these repeatable processes
these these hardening actions against
them then all of these servers need to
look exactly the same from a confirm a
configuration perspective alrighty I'll
say minimal minimal platform and I'll
just I'll just say minimal platform for
now this goes back to what I talked
about a second ago if you don't need the
feature or the capability that is
shipped out of the box with this thing
then you need to turn it off so your web
application needs to do exactly what it
needs to do but it doesn't need to do
any more than that so have a minimal
platform you know footprint as it were
as you build out your web application
I'm gonna say security security headers
or security directives is what output
directives alrighty
security directives and this goes back
to what I was said earlier that if a
client accesses your web application
then you can go back and use different
security headers for example I'll put a
couple of them up here HSTs is one so
you can include H
ekp is one let's see there's a X frame
options one there's a bunch of these
bunch of security headers that you could
use but those are a few examples but you
need to take advantage of those that hey
when you when you send the response back
then you're using those security
directives okay so those are just a few
of the ways that you can harden or
configure your security on your web
application and not have security miss
configuration alright so again the
overall idea here is that you are going
to use different parts and pieces
different code to build out your web
application and you need to understand
that there are vulnerabilities
inherently you know tied to those parts
and pieces of code and even if you write
it yourself I mean there's there's going
to be some security issues alright so
you can do some of these things there
are other other other ways to help
harden or or help with the security
every web application like with the Web
Application Firewall that's that's
another thing that you could implement
to help with some of these things but
nonetheless it's a it can be a dangerous
world out there in the in the internet
with your web application so so make
sure that you configure your web
application securely repeatedly check
that harden it as much as you can and
only use exactly what you need to use
and nothing more so thanks for watching
this lightboard lesson video today make
sure you subscribe to our YouTube
channel and we will see you guys out
there in the community
you