hey everybody John wagging on here with
dev central we're coming to you with
another light board lesson and today
we're gonna talk about some a wasp top
10 vulnerabilities and the wasps top 10
just came out the 2017 version so the
latest and greatest and the number one
vulnerability which has been the number
one vulnerability for many many years is
injection attacks so injection attacks
can happen from database injections LDAP
there's all kinds of different injection
attacks but the but the basics around
the injection attack is is relatively
similar across all the different types
of injection attacks so I'm going to
kind of draw a couple of quick scenario
here talk about how these things happen
and maybe some ways to to guard against
these all right so let's say you have a
user out here in the internet and that
user wants to access your web
application so you have a web
application out here and this web
application has you know a page you go
to WWE app comm and it's got a page and
maybe it's got like a you know user name
field right here and like a you know
password field right here and let's say
that part of the part of the design of
this web application is certainly a lot
of the HTML and CSS and you know
JavaScript and all that kind of all the
different components that go into this
but there's also a database back here so
I'm gonna put DB that contains you know
all kinds of stuff and maybe there's a
whole bunch of different databases but
let's say for example there's one that
has all of the usernames and all the
passwords and it's stored here in this
database alright then what happens is
when a user accesses the web application
you know here's the username right here
and here's the password field so they're
gonna type in their username and type in
their password and then this page is
going to send a request down to the
database and it's going to say hey I've
got this input too
to get the username and password is that
one of our you know accessible usernames
and passwords well when it does that it
uses a certain type of you know language
to communicate with the database and and
there's a very very common one most of
you probably know what what we're
talking about here but if you don't know
there's this language called structured
query language SQL and so a lot of these
injection attacks focus on sequel
injections it's what there is the way
you kind of pronounce that well see what
what SQL is is that's the language used
to talk to this database and there may
be the the structure of this may have
something that says something like you
know select you know star from you know
users with you know user name this and
then you know return whatever so but if
you say something like select star then
that means select everything from say
this user name/password database
well typically you don't want to return
that unless that is a valid request and
so what what these malicious users will
do is they'll say hey I'm gonna inject
maybe some kind of malicious code in
here to trick this back-end database to
return all of this data so then that way
I as a bad guy can see all of your in
this case usernames and passwords and so
so anyway and then and then even beyond
that sometimes you can you can type in
these these you know sequel commands so
that it actually even tricks the system
into running like system commands you
know so so there's a lot of different
things that could happen from these
injection attacks you could you could
you know have a leakage of usernames and
passwords credit card numbers you know
other kind of sensitive data you could
run system commands off of these things
so the bottom line is whenever a user
you know inputs say a username and
password and and it could be more than
just username and password fields in a
web app but I'm using that as an example
here whenever they input data into that
and then that ultimately kicks off a you
know a sequel
request to a back-end database you want
to make sure that all that is is good to
go from an authorized valid user so the
question is how do we guard against this
kind of stuff
and the short answer is make sure that
you build your web application properly
with proper access controls and proper
you know proper defense mechanisms in
place to allow this to not go on because
frankly anytime there is a user input
that needs to be assumed to be untrusted
data so you need to you need to make
sure that that is valid before you run
any kind of back-end database commands
all right so a couple of things that you
could do to guard against this is a
concept called query parameterization
I'm not gonna write it up here because
it's big words query parameterization
and basically what that means is that
the commands that are sent from the say
this front-end you know web app page to
a back-end database there are parameters
that are involved in that and then there
is the there's the very basic sequel
command itself and so what you want to
do is you want to separate the sequel
statements from any kind of parameters
that would be included in a call back to
the database so query parameterization
is a huge one kind of kind of above that
I would say that you need to validate
any kind of user input so for example if
this is a user name and you know that
based on your web application you only
allow characters that are not numbers
not special symbols you know that kind
of stuff then you need to make sure that
whatever is put in here you know
conforms to the you know to the to the
requirements that you have for that
specific field the same thing with the
password so so anyway so you need to you
need to make sure that those are in
place as well there are other there are
other kind of controls if you will that
you can put in place from a sequel
perspective
I'll put I'll put limit on here Li m.i.t
so you can do you can use some limiting
different commands or different features
in these databases and database calls
that if you were to be exposed and you
know someone did get your entire user
name and password list then you can put
some limits in place so that hey when
data is is sent back from a database
call then it only limits it to certain
amount of data that's ever sent back at
any one time so again in the indicates
that you are actually exposed and you
can actually limit the exposure so
anyway so there so that this is a very
very common attack method - to use you
know an injection into a vulnerable
database and man it happens all the time
out there so again the the number one
answer is build your web application
properly using the proper controls and
then and and there are some other
answers like web application firewalls
that you can put in place and and some
other things that you can do but at its
heart build this thing correctly so that
any kind of malicious or nefarious type
of access is not going to be able to get
to it in the first place so so injection
attacks huge thing they've been the
number one vulnerability on the OWASP
top ten for many many years it's still a
big deal it's still you know it's still
out there still used all the time so be
careful out there build your web app
properly and and let's be safe on the
internet today so thanks for watching
this lightboard lesson video and we'll
see you guys out there in the community
you