hey everybody John wagged on here with
dev central and we're coming to you with
another light board lesson and today
we're gonna talk about broken
authentication this is one of the OS
top 10 vulnerabilities OWASP top 10 list
just came out brand-new one in 2017 and
a broken authentication was actually the
number two vulnerability listed on that
on that new list so what is broken
authentication the the essence of broken
authentication is where you allow your
users or a bad guy user to get into your
web application without the proper
credentials so so I'll draw a couple
little or a little scenario up here
let's say you have a user out here in on
the internet and he wants to come in and
access your web application so you got
your web app here and in your web
application you know you have a you have
a username and a password that you use
to access your web application so the
user would enter his username and his
password and if it's good then it gets
in if it's not then he then he doesn't
get in right all right well these
username and password are stored back
here and some you know some database
that's a DB of you know usernames and
passwords back here so as he as he
accesses the web application
he's going to enter that that's gonna
make a call back here to this back-end
database and if it's good then you get
access if it's bad and you don't kind of
thing alright so if if this
authentication is successful then there
is there's this idea of a session ID so
I'm going to just put that right out
here so session ID that is given to the
specific session so again the user tries
to access the web application puts in
the proper credentials those are
authentic it's the users authenticated a
session ID is created to allow that user
to experience this web application for
that for the duration of that session
okay that's important because that's
going to come in in this broken
authentication discussion what could
happen here is if you have not built
your web application properly then then
a bad guy could come in and do several
nefarious things to try to get access
into this web application a few things
that could be tried are what's called
credential stuffing so I'm gonna write
this here credential stuffing what
credential stuffing is is essentially
where a bad guy has a known list of
usernames and passwords that maybe he's
stolen from you know some exploit that
happened way back you know at some other
place maybe Yahoo or Target or whatever
you know when these companies gets gets
hacked so he's got a bunch of
credentials and he stuffs those into
this username and password field of your
web application hoping to gain access to
you know your your web application the
the idea of this is that typically the
bad guy's going to use an automated you
know system and automated tool to just
stuff a bunch of these in and just try
over and over with tons and tons of
different usernames a password you know
you know to try to get in so so anyway
so that's credential stuffing there's
also automated attacks so I'll put
automated attacks this is kind of more
general automated attacks this is where
maybe you would just use random
usernames and passwords not necessarily
credential stuffing is where you have
known usernames and passwords this one
would be maybe you just try random
usernames and random passwords and you
just start stuffing them into this you
know username password field and you're
in the web application and if one of
them takes then then you're golden
you're in you're good to go
there are also things like default
passwords which could be used default
that's an F sorry default passwords and
usernames based in by the way that could
be tried in this thing let's say you
know you have a brand new machine and
you know based on the manufacturer that
the default usually a password is admin
admin or you know admin password or
whatever so the bad guy could try a
bunch of those and try to get in theirs
let me let me give you one scenario this
kind of ties back to the session ID
let's say that you're a user and you
at a public library and or you're at a
public place and you you type in you
know you use them a password to your web
application and you gain authentication
you're good to go
you do your thing and then you close out
your tab and but maybe you don't close
out the browser you know completely just
close out the tab and maybe you get up
and you walk away and you're done and
and you move on about your day well then
another bad guy slips in behind you a
few minutes later notices that even
though that tab was closed the browser
is still open well maybe that session ID
has been saved on the browser and that
session ID even though it's been let's
say 10 minutes or whatever that session
ID is still stored and the bad guy can
open up a new tab go back to that same
web application and gain access based on
the stored session ID that's still in
that browser so that's another another
little way kind of in so all of this
falls under the umbrella of broken
authentication because we're allowing
and our web application all these
different attacks to allow you know bad
guys access into our web application all
right so what do you do how do you solve
this thing there are a few different I
guess best practices if you will one
would be I'm gonna kind of draw a line
right here so these are like the attack
attempts and these are gonna be sort of
the you know the best practice what we
need to do I'm gonna put multi-factor
off short for authentication
all right multi-factor authentication
this is where you would use maybe a
token like a software token or some kind
of a you know token on your on your cell
phone or whatever maybe use a you know a
thumbprint or a you know I scan or
whatever so you've got not just your
user name and password but but it's it's
multi-factor so you could use that also
password checking so I'm going to put
password checking and what this is is a
sort of a proactive approach where you
as the owner of the web application
could say I'm gonna go in with like the
top 10,000 best known pass or or you
know most commonly used
passwords out there in the internet
today and I'm going to proactively check
my database of usernames and passwords
and make sure that none of those top
10,000 are on my system if they are I'm
gonna shoot a little note to that user
that has that password and say hey once
you think about changing your password
and oh by the way you use a better
password next time which brings us to
another one and that is password
complexity password complexity and this
is basically where you're saying hey
users whenever you establish your
password you have to have you know
certain complexity requirements on your
password and that makes it harder for
stuff like this to happen well some of
these things that happen like the
default password you know check you can
also have limits on on failed logins so
limit failed login I'm writing what this
is is if I'm using say some kind of
automated attack or maybe a credential
stuffing and I'm just throwing a ton of
different usernames and passwords at
this then if I use the same username and
I use a different you know I try like
save one or two or three passwords or
whatever after a certain number then
that ought to just say hey your account
is locked out now and so you can't even
get in until you send a note to the
administrator and all that kind of stuff
there's also an idea that's called
server-side session management and
basically what that is is on this back
side of your web application the the
server that controls all this you can
you can set up a server-side session ID
manager that basically says when a user
gains access to my web application and
this session ID is created then what I'm
going to do is I'm going to essentially
throw that away but I'm going to create
a new random session ID that's going to
be used to interface with the web
application and they're there certain
criteria that you need to make sure you
have for that as well but but the idea
is that this initial session ID is not
used it's a brand new random one that
the server-side would create and in that
way if another user comes in tries to
use that initial session ID it's
using it's not usable because there was
a new one that was created on the
backside so so anyway so this is this is
kind of the idea of broken
authentication if we're your web
application allows for a lot of these
attacks to to come in and if these would
be successful then hey you're you're
probably not set up the way that you
need to be and you need to start using
some of these other things to take guard
against this I just give me there are
there are some things like a web
application firewall that you could put
in line with all this that would help as
well but the bottom line is whenever you
design and build your web application
and all these different components that
are part of it then you need to do it
correctly and you need to put these you
know these controls in place so that
you're not susceptible to these attacks
so so be careful out there with broken
authentication it's a it's a huge attack
huge vulnerability that's exploited all
the time these days and and so yeah
let's so let's be safe out there on the
Internet thanks for watching this
lightboard lesson and we'll see you guys
out there in the community
you