level 23 of natus for the over the wire
war game gets into a little bit of PHP
variable type misunderstanding cuz see
I'm actually looking at the source code
in the webpage here because they're
doing a little bit of the PHP highlight
file where they're they throw a bunch of
like span characters or HTML stuff
that's not that good to look at in
sublime text so I'm back in the web site
here in in the Firefox in a web browser
but we're determining okay if we've
submitted to the form here which asks us
do we want to enter a password and the
PHP code tests if that key exists if
we've actually submitted the form is
there a stir stir or a string string
whatever PHP function that is and is the
request password greater than 10 so this
stir stir looks like it's kind of
comparing something like the requested
password with a string I love you and
and so and obviously this both of these
conditions must be returned true to
actually be retrieving the credentials
for the next level password for NAT is
24 so I want to check out what these
things were I wanted to see okay what is
PHP stir stir and it looks like that
will find the first occurrence of a
string and it will return part of a
haystack string starting to something
from and including the first occurrence
of the needle to the end of the haystack
okay and that greater than 10 thing is
interesting because that's expecting
that request password to be an integer
but we're using it as a string over here
in this context so how do we get around
this interesting thing is that PHP type
conversions PHP doesn't entirely care
really what your variable really is it
all depends on what context you're using
it in there how you're testing things
with it PHP does not require support
explicit type definition variable
declarations the variable types
determined by the context in which the
variables being used so that is to say
if string value is assigned to variable
var var becomes a string if an integer
variable as a sign of our it becomes an
enter that's cool because it's dynamic
type setting and stuff like that but
it's also
interesting when you're using comparison
operators or just assignment operators
on them so I'll shut up and I'll show
you what I mean if we get back into our
Python code we'll go ahead and request
this page with the get function but if
we wanted to post to this page we can
change the method there set data to have
the password and we'll set it to that
string I love you so this will return
wrong after I include a comment or a
comma there because we're not getting
that same greater than 10 thing in this
case we're seeing that string I love you
that the string password interpreted as
a string and when it's being tested as
less than or greater than 10 it's just
gonna be nothing really or a zero I
don't I don't entirely know I'll admit
what PHP will evaluate it to however if
we were to give it some numbers here
like if we were to say 10 PHP is gonna
start to think that this first part here
when you're interpreting it as a number
as an integer that's gonna be what takes
precedence if you interpret it as a
number so weird thing right what if I
were to say oh 11 I love you because 11
is greater than 10 and the i-love-you
string is still in there it'll return
true on both of those cases 11 is
greater than 10 and I love you is in the
string it's returning that needle and
the rest of the haystack so it gets it
just fine here we go the credentials for
the next level are password for NAT is
24 okay let's snag that but keep that in
mind because PHP type juggling is seen
like everywhere and a lot of web
challenges and in CTF style stuff and
I'm sure you'll probably run into it in
the wild because PHP is still out there
like crazy so definitely keep that in
mind weird weird oddities with PHP that
stuff gets into like magic hashes etc
and PHP is just a bundle of bugs
depending on on who you ask and what
opinions you get but that is the
solution for natus 23 let's save this
for a script from natus 24 and we will
move on to see what's next in this level
are we getting the page perfect all
right thank you guys so much for
watching hope
you're enjoying these if you did like
the video please do press that like
button if you want to comment tell me
what you think what you like what you
didn't like what I can do better much
how much I suck etc if you want to
subscribe and if you would like to
support me please do check out my
patreon account want to send a special
shout out to the people that are
supporting me already spencer clark
thank you for supporting me on patreon I
try to shout out everyone who does
support me if they give anything more
than just a dollar and five dollars or
more we'll let you all showcase
everything that I upload to YouTube as
early as I can so even if it's scheduled
for upload later I'll give it to you
early access so thanks for watching guys
see you soon