hey what's up YouTube this is John
Hammond I come back at to another video
for natus this time level 12 was part of
the over the wire wargames looking at
web application security
so what we're greeted was here in this
level is what looks like some file
upload functionality the prompt here is
choose a JPEG to upload a JPEG file jpg
image and I poked around with this a
little bit I gave it some like default
files that I had like something I'd safe
and like a Python challenge video or
something whenever I would try and
upload this it wouldn't actually work I
don't know why says there's no error
uploading the file please try again
whatever so we can get back to the page
and we can view the source like the same
kind of functionality all the other
levels have had for us but let's take a
look at this in sublime text or in our
editor so we can see with syntax
highlighting and it looks pretty good so
I've got the same like skeleton code
I've had before the username and
password we're using requests and
regular expressions to scrape stuff out
and I just make get requests to page so
here we can see it lets up the syntax to
like HTML whatever and now we can go to
that view source like index source page
cool alright that's kind of messy so
let's Deanna ties it just like we've
been doing before and there are a ton of
break characters that aren't really
important for some reason so we can see
the PHP code behind this application and
it looks like just looking at the
original HTML for us we have a form
that's doing a multi-part form data so
it's able to take in files and it looks
like there are hidden values that get
posted along with the request or maximum
file size maybe we can tinker with that
a file name looks like it is actually
going to be using a function called gen
random string or I'm assuming generated
random string and it just tacks on a jpg
extension here and then it elect it
actually allows us to browse to a file
with that file input type and the
variable name is uploaded file so we can
upload that and maybe it will happen or
maybe it won't let's see why our
previous one didn't work it looks like
it
a bunch of functions up top in the PHP
code but the actual logic right now to
the start with is to testing if a file
name exists in the post request so if we
actually posted to the follower into the
forum sorry to the web page it gets a
target path based off of a make random
path from file name upload and the post
file name so make random path from
filename looks like another function
that we have here and that takes in a
directory which we know is just upload
right now we can see that string and I'm
assuming F N for filename so the post
filename that it gets here and in the
function we run this ext variable looks
like it's running PHP function path info
getting out I'm assuming the extension
of the file type extension for the file
name that we pass in and looks like by
default it's jpg but we can probably
change that if we get in the middle of
it and then it will return make random
path on this and make random path looks
like another function here where it will
create a path over and over again with a
random string until the file does not
exist so while the file exists that path
it will keep creating a new one over and
over again and it'll keep trying to
generate a new random string until it
hits something that it hasn't randomly
gotten before and generate random string
that function up top just looks like it
creates a uses all the letters and
numbers lower case
grabs a random one ten times and puts it
together to create a random string so it
must be creating your random filename
and we could see that even in the source
code if we wanted to
like when we zoomed in took a look at
that file name input in the HTML it is a
random file name if I keep refreshing
this page but by default always has a
jpg value but it looks like that
functionality in the PHP code actually
keeps track of the extension that is
given so what if we were to give it
something that wasn't a jpg image like
what if we were to give it PHP code that
it could actually execute let's try that
I guess let's find out I'm gonna go
ahead and create a new file and that can
be just a simple PHP reverse shell
so I have this already saved as rub
shell from some previous testing but
it'll just have our PHP open and close
tags and we will echo out the system
output of our get request C and C can
just be the variable that we want to
have here and I think echo will also
display it while system already does to
begin with so we can probably just run
system get C and let's just do that
experiment to see if it will display it
out on the screen for us so let's try
that I don't know how in the request
module we can't upload a file but let's
go find out we can just use some simple
Google thing Python requests get to the
documentation let's look for file upload
control F we get the quick start I
wanted to be at the quick start upload
okay cool so there's a documentation
here looks like we can give in our post
requests all that would we make that
function call we can just give it
another keyword argument files and
that's just another dictionary with the
file like name that that variable name
for the HTTP POST and then just an open
object like a Python file object created
with the open function so just a file
name really sweet let's go ahead and do
that let's go back to sublime text and
let's try and do a new function rather
than yearning the get pH the get HTTP
method would front post keep the off
that we need but let's say our data like
we have for a normal post call or post
method we have file name and that can be
Rev shell dot PHP because we're going to
try and do something other than a jpg
file but some PHP code we want to be
able to have it execute for us and that
max file size will include that just to
be safe that was by default a thousand
or so right yeah
okay so there's the data but let's get
the files in there as well since this
form that we're working with can
actually interpret those a okay so files
can equal uploaded file and that was the
variable name if you check the source
that's what it's using to read in that
variable and the HTTP method that post
requests so we want to open up our Rev
shell dot PHP and the documentation said
down below here try and make sure you
open this in binary mode so R be the
mode here for that file okay
now let's run this see what we get and I
think I posted that to index source so
let's not do that now let's run this
function we have different build output
looks like it did upload though all that
other other page here let me open that
source code backup sorry so the response
was the file dislocation so this must be
the random string that we had given to
us dot PHP so it kept our extension
because that's how the source code
explained it and that's been uploaded
successfully okay cool
so let's go to that location and let's
see if we can get it to run system
commands for us because that's what we
just told PHP to do so response can
equal session get get the URL plus the
upload and auth can do the same username
and password that we've been working
with all along so now when we run this
we get some PHP notices and warnings so
notice undefined index see in this PHP
okay so that we because that's because
we didn't supply the variable and we're
getting a warning because system can't
execute a blank email so that's C
variable that get variable that we
wanted to include we'll have to include
it now so
question mark see so we're going to note
some HTTP GET variables and C will equal
like Who am I
let's run this and we get NAT is 12 okay
so that's our user awesome
looks like we have training securin we
can run ID run this and got output again
perfect now let's try and go ahead and
do the good stuff let's try and get or
cat out the password for the next level
nat is 13
run this cat etc natus web past NAT is
13 and we've got the password just like
that so cool we totally just took
advantage of some file upload
functionality where we were able to keep
our file extension and upload something
that it didn't expect like maybe it
wanted a JPEG does that's how the
application it asked for that that's
what it requested but we gave it some
PHP code and we're able to take
advantage of that get it to execute that
and run the system commands or shell
commands stuff like you'd see in bash so
we got remote code execution on that box
if we wanted to we create our own
reverse shell like through like through
our bash terminal like create a net cat
session and stuff like that but for this
RCE
or remote code execution this is just
fine for us we were able to get the
password for the next level and we can
move on here let's go ahead and save
this as natus 13 and let's see what that
levels asking for us cool now we only
accept image files okay so we got a
similar vulnerability or at least a
similar task but maybe there's something
else here that we and can work with to
find a vulnerability and get remote code
execution one more time
cool thanks for watching this video guys
hope you're enjoying these if you are
please like the video maybe leave me a
comment what you think what else I can
do what else you'd like to see share the
video tell your friends subscribe if
you'd like and if you thanks for
watching guys again hope you're enjoying
these and I'll see you in a later video