that is level 20 introduces the page in
a different way than the previous levels
like natus 18 and natus 19 did
immediately we are already logged in as
opposed idli as a regular user but we
have to modify the credentials and login
as admin to retrieve credentials for
natus 21 the next level so we have a
form here that allows us to post another
HTTP method to index.php this home page
here and the functionality looks like
it's asking for a name like we can
change our name of whatever user were
logged into to verify this let's take a
look at the index source we can go ahead
and browse to that page here with our
python script and let's go ahead and
take this remove all of the brake lines
that are in the way and let's do ties
this thing I did that out of order so
diantha ties does that work hello okay
cool I don't know why I said he'll only
talk on the phone here alright so the
source code that we have gives us a
debug message that looks like it's
enabled once we actually run get
requests with the variable debug and if
that's present normally I've ignored
this but we are going to need it in this
level so that'll get a better idea of
what's really happening here the
function print credentials looks like it
is being run because it tells us
originally your login as a regular user
login as the admin to retrieve
credentials so we're trying to determine
whether or not the session little
dictionary in PHP has this admin index
of this admin admin value and make sure
that that is set to 1 there I guess it's
an associative array in PHP whatever but
we want to make sure that such an admin
is set to 1 okay that's the goal here
and then we get the password for the
next level so it looks like that this
program defines a lot of boilerplate
functions that are trying to handle how
a session or a PHP session is stored and
saved we can scroll down a little bit
earlier we see other functions like my
destroy my garbage etc and these are set
as the handlers for the default PHP
session
handler or how that's really operated
and done in PHP so since we're using
these custom-made functions we have the
code here that's visible and we might be
able to do something villainous if we
really wanted to so things like my open
my clothes might destroy my garbage
they're noted as we don't need these
things they just kind of return true and
they aren't really anything interesting
but what we have here is this
functionality that lets us change the
name variable just like we saw in that
form if we actually post the page make a
request and set the name it will go
ahead and create a session variable for
that it displays the credentials and if
they key exists it gets it etc etc and
we just have our form so the interesting
things here are these custom functions
am I read in my write because they're
the only valuable ones really being used
for handling our session so my read is
interesting because it says okay I'm
gonna read out of a session ID and it
tests is the string matching these
characters here or they not equal to the
length or whatever and it looks like
that just determines whether or not it's
a valid session ID so some kind of
handling determines in a write form and
then it stores these in a file a
filename that it determines a path for
and whether or not it exists it will
handle it appropriately if it does exist
it will read from it it looks like it
gets the contents of it it creates an
array for the session variable and it
will process it bit by bit that explode
function in PHP will take a string and
explode or split up in into an array or
a list given a DES specific delimiter so
our new line here just breaks it up line
by line and you can see this debug
statement here it's reading each line by
line and then it explodes by spaces and
it determines each specific part or
segment of a line that it's reading so
if it's not nothing if it's not an empty
line it sets a session variable to the
other part of that line like key value
we have a key pair here
okay that looks peculiar because that
can probably be taken advantage of so
it's reading out of that session file
now let's determine how is it getting
written to how how does the my write
function work we get our debug message
we test if it's in the correct form
again we get the same file name saving
and we sort by keys the session variable
for each session variable that we have
we to note that the bug here and we add
it to a string that we're originally
appending to as from nothing and we
build out a new file based off of that
because we're using file put contents
okay so let's actually play with this
now in code now in experimenting with
the level because we're in Python
because we're using this response dot
text session that we're able to work
with we can handle multiple calls all in
code because we're doing this this code
like this
so let's actually have a divider here
because I want to show you the
development and in this by default we
are still going to the source code so
let's first fix that let's go to the
original page it tells us you're logged
in as an individual as a regular user
nothing special let's turn those debug
methods on by changing this link here to
include HTTP GET variable so so
following with the question mark debug
can equal really anything but I'll just
say true readability and we'll check out
what this content is it says okay debug
my read blah blah blah this must be the
random thing that's created it says okay
this session file doesn't exist so it
must have been created and that's why at
the very end of the page we see the my
write function being ran and saving it
in varlyn PHP so whatever whatever file
on the server that this session is being
stored into so we're operating in a
session right every time I run this
program run this Python script we're
gonna get a different string as our
session string so what I'm going to do
is just make multiple calls but I'm not
going to I'm gonna keep adding to the
current script we're working with let's
go ahead and see if we can change our
name or let's before
we get into that let's see are we
keeping the same session following this
or after we if we get another request
here we say ok let's get a random one
the session file doesn't exist we write
to it and then in the second call using
our dividers to tell that's a second
call we see ok now that file does exist
because we created it there's nothing
really in there so it was able to read
nothing but we should have some other
variables we can put into it because of
that change name functionality now let's
try and include a name that we can post
to it let's make a call to post with
data being name can be close up now that
we've posted to it again session file
doesn't exist it will create it now that
we've made a post we have set debug
statements out here name is set to
please sub and we write in here the in
the session file we're setting name a
string a 6 character length to contents
please sub final call once we run get we
are reading here reading from var Lib
read name is please sub ok so we were
able to do that and in the my write
function it still keeps the name here
now let's see if we can inject something
or get in the way of this read and write
function because it doesn't look like
they're sanitizing anything at all in
that in that source code if they're just
splitting up variables line by line and
with a space in between each thing we
could just as easily add a new line and
change whatever session variables we
really wanted to oh you know like admin
and set admin equal to 1 so let's go
ahead and try that in our code when
we're making our post request
we can say name please sub or whatever
we really wanted to but if we had a new
line character backslash n now we can
set any other session variable to
whatever we want because we're getting
in the way of that session Handler admin
and set it to one right cool let's go
ahead and take a look if I run this code
at the very very end after we've
established the session and then after
we've modified it now we can check back
it says awesome you are an admin the
credentials for the next level are NAT
is 21 and the password right here so I
hope that makes sense because we were
able to just read the source code see
how its determining these variables
getting saved and loaded essentially
from the PHP session with those custom
handlers and we're able to take
advantage of them so sweet let's go
ahead and save this now create a new
script and that is 21 and we don't need
all this junk but we do want to move to
the next level here and we've got the
next level okay so thank you guys for
watching I hope you enjoy this if you do
like these videos pre please press that
like button and I'm getting my words
tumbled maybe leave me a comment let me
know what you think what you'd like to
see next what I can do better how else
you solve this if you're willing to
subscribe and if you really really want
to support me please check me out on
patreon on that note I want to give a
special shout out to Spencer Clark who
is currently supporting me on patreon if
you do support me I'll give you a shout
out and literally every single video $5
or more I'll give you early access to
just about everything I release on
YouTube so thanks for watching
see you soon