this video showcases an interesting
trick with the sequel select statement
where we exceed the maximum character
lengths get a string truncated and use
that to leak out another accounts
password from a database keep watching
to learn how to do this and more right
now what's up YouTube now we're looking
at natus level 27 and this is a peculiar
one because we're looking again at some
more like username password credentials
and so we're gonna be trying out a user
and password set that I guess we can
login with I don't know so I'll just try
John and the password like wins or
something and it looks like okay user
John was created interesting let's
refresh the page and if we were to login
with that again if we some requested
that same John and login it'll say okay
now that you're logged in here's the
data that you're receiving you can see
your username and your password so
that's an interesting thing small
applications looks like it used the
sequel database to just check whether or
not there is a user in the database if
it isn't there it will create one and
then if it is there it will just tell
you a little bit about the account in
that it will give you the password so
our objective is to check out the
password for natus 28 to beat this level
and move on so i've got the source code
pulled up I've got a sublime text ready
to rock with our Python script and let's
take a look at the source code it looks
a little bit better in sublime text for
this level because I don't have the
syntax highlighting in the regular page
so here I am in sublime text again so
we've got the same user schema that
we've seen the database that we've seen
before and other previous levels
username and password strings or vark
are 64 in length and not null blah blah
blah a bunch of functions that are
created but I want to at least take a
look at the top level code that runs
before everything else if we are
requesting something so if we actually
submit the username and password it will
connect the database with the password
not specified here select a database to
use and then it will run a couple checks
it'll run valid user which looks like a
function up top on the username that
were that we're selecting or entering
and check prudential x' another function
that's to scale this displayed up top
again it's using the request username
and request password and it says welcome
the username here's your data and dump
data looks like it will display the user
name and password like we saw in the
application so HTML entities is pH P's
notion and attempt to secure things down
like remove all the HTML entities if you
were to try and do like cross-site
scripting or inject HTML elements or
JavaScript code into an input field so
HTML entities is going to be a
mitigation technique that is harming us
here as the attacker we're not able to
run any of those things like injecting
script tag HTML tags etc so it looks
like they do a good job of noting HTML
entities and everything else they're
trying to display otherwise it'll give
us a wrong password if the user doesn't
exist it will create it like you saw
with my John account that I showed
earlier and we can actually see if I
were to log out here or if I can I don't
think it will let me very easily I don't
have that I don't have that option
that's fine I can do it in the source
code actually when we try and attack it
with our Python script so the functions
that we want to take a look at up here
or check credential looks like we have
the user and password that are being
passed to this function just as
variables and they're using the my
sequel real escape string function on
them again that's another PHP mitigation
function that will try and lock down or
protect a lot of regular sequel
injection techniques so we don't have
that at our disposal they are doing that
to lock us down
you can probably research and Google and
find a lot of bypass options or ways to
evade this function and maybe that's
worth your while it's not what I've
found as a solution to this challenge
but I think that's something that would
be really interesting if you do want to
look into more of the bypassing this
function so it goes ahead and runs a
query here determining whether or not ok
does this username exist do the
credentials work are we going to get a
results just like that and that looks
like all that function really is valid
user is another function that does
the same thing but it's selecting only
the username to determine whether or not
this user already exists right we saw
that down below they're checking if
valid user ok comment the user exists if
not it will create it so check
credentials is just determining whether
or not you have the right password and
that is the check credentials up here ok
so that looks like it occurs in any case
just it whether it gets a correct result
it will return true
that's the peculiar thing to note and
dump data is really where it will just
display out that username and password
for us so that's where and the magic
happens where we can potentially get the
password but again they're still using
the real escape string so we're
preventing our regular sequel injection
however what they do here is they do an
interesting thing after they execute
this query they determine whether or not
we've got a result do we have things
that we can actually look through did we
get data back from the database and it
will return a number of rows and if it's
greater than 0 ok we have multiple
results so what it does is it does this
a while loop that it iterates through
every single row this is peculiar right
because we only expected it to return
one result like if if there's only one
user we're trying to login as a specific
user that would probably just be one but
what if we are in the case if there are
multiple results if there are multiple
rows to look through and that is kind of
the spark of ingenuity that will lead to
the toying around tinker and
experimenting to find us a trick and a
technique that can let us attack this
this application so the create user
function is simple that will just insert
into the database and again if it
actually successfully executed it will
return true otherwise false etc so let's
poke around at what would normally be
this database in the schema because
there are some interesting tricks and
techniques we can use to get around that
notion of ok we don't know the password
for natus 28 the next level but because
maybe we could get it to return multiple
results in some cases let's try
just sending that string over here if I
run get requests I can instead post now
where data can equal I'm gonna put this
on a new line so I can bring these
side-by-side trying to minimize my mouse
movement because I know that's pretty
annoying when I'm trying to fly in and
out of different panes between the
script results in the actual source code
and we don't need the first thing here
we can just post this get our return
output and you can see I have posted the
page it gives me wrong password for user
and natus 28 so I wasn't able to success
to authenticate in there if I try John
wins just go back to it okay user John
was created the database must have reset
we saw a comment that we didn't get it
earlier the database will reset every
five minutes so if I run this again we
are logging in and it gives us our
password and credentials but NAT is 28
not working for us cuz we don't know the
correct password
so now let's tinker a little bit I want
to show off an interesting tool called
sequel test net where we can just
experiment with sequel database and a
quick and easy way without spinning up a
server so the top right you can select
the database we're just using my sequel
I'm going to change this to table name
as users and we'll just use the user
name as the actual field that we want to
work with because that's the peculiar
one that we are determining when we are
running that check credentials or valid
user function here all the valid user
function is testing is whether or not
the user exists and that's the first
test here okay
do we have a valid user well yes we can
have a valid user because Matt is 28 is
always gonna have to exist but then we
have to get checked credentials to work
so check credentials is the hard part
but maybe we could have multiple results
or multiple rows for natus 28 so I'm
just going to show this example where I
use if our car of 10 as our size so we
can experiment with that and I'll insert
into users values
subscribe cuz ok so subscribe is nine
letters long right yep so that's an
interesting thing let's go ahead and
select all from users to just get
results here I scroll down there's a
button execute sequel down on the very
bottom and okay so we get a result
subscribe so interesting thing to note
here is that I set the length of this
column the length of this field to only
ten characters keep in mind for the
actual application ours is 64 characters
long but maybe it will act strangely if
we give it some data that's longer than
that length that's setup so let's say I
have our car 10 right so let's insert
another row subscribe space please right
cool now that way can execute that again
execute sequel we can see we have
subscribe and subscribe it's returning
both of those peculiar but there's the
space kind of at the very very end there
that's fine it looks like it got
truncated the word please just cut off
so it's being returned with the space
okay so let's get let's just narrow this
down to see if that space will go away
if we were to ask for select all from
users where username is equal to
subscribe go ahead down execute this
Peggy's do this I am executing it but
you're not seeing the results change
because of a really interesting bug here
not a bug but a strange trick and
functionality so I just removed the the
results that you can see for real but if
I just
Rikka meant that and turn the execution
back on we are getting both of the
results subscribe on its own and
subscribe with a whatever amount of
padding using spaces to like exceed that
number the maximum length for us but the
spaces are still going to be returning
it on its own interesting thing right so
what if we could take advantage of that
what if we could say all right we want
to insert into the database because we
know there's already an out of 28
username and pass from the database what
if we had NAT is 28 inserted with
however many spaces whatever we need to
break it up to 64 characters and then
exceed that and then we could have
literally anything following this
because anything will be truncated but
the spaces will remain intact and the
Select statement will still execute and
get us what we're looking for
execute sequel natus 28 both of these
are going to be returned and because
we're using that my sequel fetch
associative because we're looping
through every single row we may still
get a result that's an interesting thing
let's try it what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna use natus 28 over here
our first insert into and we're gonna
need to make this an insert into because
we have to create the account the
register the user that has more than 64
characters in the name so this is seven
characters long so 64 minus 7 or you
know 54 57 so let's go ahead and I'm not
good at math we're not good at quick
math on YouTube with people are watching
so let's multiply some spaces
let's go 58 or something to be safe and
then we'll just tack on anything so it
will be truncated we'll go ahead and
post this make this call and you'd see
user now does 28 blah blah blah anything
was created okay so user now does 28 is
in there now that's been created and now
we can try and log in which is the
regular natus account with our anything
password the password that we used
previously because remember in the
source code this check credentials will
work on anything where username and
password is going to get a result that
select will still have it get the native
28 we inserted previously with the
truncated spaces and it will still
return true great now valid user since
that's going to work through the
associative all of these rows here it's
going to loop through all of these query
that's gonna return true and then we'll
be able to see the password let's try
this we got it alright welcome to natus
28 here's your data array this guy right
here is our password for natus level 28
cool let's save this as in out of 28
script so we can keep in mind for that
and we're gonna move on but thank you
guys so much for watching I hope that
was kind of cool I hope that was kind of
interesting I hope I didn't drag it on
for too long but I thought that was a
really interesting technique honestly
I've never seen that before other than
just digging at this and poking at it
until we got it
but that's a really peculiar thing is
hacking away at that maximum length
character seeing what strange things
happen when you experiment with it when
you exceed when you get your data
truncated and how come the spaces just
didn't didn't get evaluated or
considered in that select statement
interesting bizarre thing that sequel
does but really cool to know for us and
the capture the flag and pentesting
scene so hey I gotta give a shout out to
my supporters here this list is getting
longer and thank you so much for you
guys I really can't say it enough that's
why I do this in every videos because I
cannot say thank you enough thank you so
much for being willing to go on this
journey with me and helping support it
really helps grow me and the channel it
helps motivate me to keep working and
keep pumping out really cool things
hopefully they are really cool for you
hey one month on patreon $1 a month on
patreon will give you a shout-out just
like this at the end of every video $5
and more a month will give you early
access quote-unquote to the videos that
I'm uploading to YouTube in case I
record in bulk in mass and they schedule
them on YouTube and they're really
slowly so thank you guys again if you
did like this video please do press that
like button maybe if you're willing to
leave me a comment let me know what you
think what you liked what you didn't
like what we could do better what else
you'd like to see how you solved this if
you'd like to subscribe and if you
really want to support me please check
me out on patreon cool thanks so much
guys see you in the next video