what's up YouTube this is John Hammond
coming back at you with natus level 14
from the over the wire wargames some web
application and security stuff so in the
last couple videos we've been doing some
file upload vulnerabilities let's clean
up some of that code and let's check out
what level 14 is asking for us and going
dead and to run that script
it looks like the page is pretty simple
there's just a forum post method with a
username and password and a login button
so nothing else let's take a look at the
source code and see what this is really
doing here thankfully over the wire
levels for our learning and our
education is giving us the source code
so once we download that will again use
sublime text to diantha ties all those
HTML entities and will remove all those
break statements so I'm gonna save this
in a new file or a new pane and sublime
text so we can keep the source code okay
so it looks like the PHP code here
determines if we are supplying the
username so if we've actually kind of
filled out the form or done what we
expect it to do it makes a connection to
a my sequel database so a database that
has you know and anything in it maybe
credentials
maybe credit cards maybe passwords maybe
social security numbers the potential
for databases is crazy crazy big like
that could be an airport that could be
at a bank who knows so there's normally
a lot of good things stored in a
database at least good in the eyes of an
attacker so let's take advantage of some
vulnerabilities here and see what we can
break see what we can leak out we are
selecting the nads 14 database and we're
making a query select all from users
where username and we're just
concatenated on the username and
password equals concatenating on the
password so this is bad like this should
be firing alarms in like security
professionals Minds because you should
never ever ever be concatenated for like
variables that you control like the user
has full control over like at the raw
level requests variables get HTTP POST
stuff they're concatenated them into a
sequel query or thing that's going to be
run on a database there's
Oh sanitation there's no actual
verification of this data and it's super
duper bad so that will lead to things
like sequel injection like in inputting
sequel commands and sequel code into a
query in making the database do
different things and leak out
information you're tricking the back-end
database where you as the attacker are
replacing what would normally be data
that the user would supply or
information and replacing it with code
we're tricking the database and to think
that our data and it's actually going to
be executing code so we can see the
query that we're working with and we can
use this debug functionality that it's
testing looks like a little hidden
easter egg to show us what the query
really looks like when we're at the when
we're executing it and then it will show
us okay if we actually get a result if
the number of rows returned from
executing this query is more than 0 or
if we get any results if we get one or
more then we will be a success to logged
in and we'll get the password otherwise
access denied
so we don't know when a user name and
password we're we literally don't know
credentials so we can't login but we can
take advantage of this sequel injection
and maybe get it to return something and
ok
login get the password for the next
level so let's go ahead and try this
let's change this URL up here to set
debug equal to true or really anything
and then when we run this nothing's
gonna happen to start because we're not
actually posting to the webpage but now
let's go ahead and post to the webpage
and pass in a username and password as
variables here so comment this out
change this to a post request and let's
say data can equal username can equal
please and password can be subscribe ha
ha shameless plug cool run this let's
see what we get here oh I forgot a comma
man my
moment of glory with the police
subscribe digger this totally ruined
alright don't forget your commas and
your keyword arguments kids stay in
school so here's the debug information
executing query select all from users
where username equals please and passer
is equal to subscribe access denied
so we weren't able to log in with that
obviously but you can see we're just
concatenated in those things they're not
being sanitized so what's to stop us
from using double quotes in one of these
like in order these these fields that
we're supplying because in the source
code it's using double quotes to denote
this is where I'm going to put the
username or put the password that'll be
the placeholder for it you can see it in
the query here so if I put an extra
double quote in there will things break
will it run out of well it will it mess
up that that placement of quotes let's
try this here looks like it did we see
executing query select all from users
where username equals please with two
quotation marks and we get a PHP error
or a warning here bicycle number rows
expects parameter number one of your
resources boolean given and blah blah
blah so something went wrong we can put
please anything what now Lowell and just
completely break it see if we'll get
more errors see if we'll get weird
things to happen that's all the way
included and we're still getting that
same error for that warning that PHP
warning so let's make this go crazy
let's get try and get some valid sequel
back into this we can use a comment for
in my sequel just a pound symbol or a
hashtag to comment out the rest of the
line or the query here so now we'll get
back to access denied like the command
was sex successfully executed there
wasn't a warning or any PHP my sequel
notifications there but we put a hash
tag or a pound symbol that commented out
this test for the password so now we're
not testing where username and password
is equal is something now we're only
testing where username equals to
something we're username equals please
and obviously okay there aren't any
usernames that's set to please but now
we've proven to ourselves there is there
is some sequel injection vulnerability
here so we can do other tests we can
inject other sequel statements like
trying to return something that always
returns successfully like selecting all
from users where username equals please
isn't going to return anything it's not
going to return true because there
aren't any users that are have a
username set to please but if we were to
add another condition one here like or 1
equals one because one is always one
right that'll always return true and
that's in an or statement so that
condition will light up green that will
work so that's the kind of most simple
easiest example of sequel injection
where you can leak or dump the entire
database because it will select all or
return everything where bla bla bla one
condition that doesn't normally work or
one equals one that condition always
works
select all where everything returns true
or one equals one
suite so that should return something
have results more than zero and we'll
get success successful login the
password for nanos 15 is this guy so you
can see this query here and with the
debug information select all from users
where username equals please again we're
terminating that original string because
we've been injected our own double quote
and we're doing another condition in
here or one equals one always return
true it gives me everything and then we
have a comment my sequel comment that
pound symbol or hash tag that we'll just
throw out the whole rest of the query
that and subscribe that and password
equals test that goes away because we've
commented it out so just like that we do
some cool sequel injection and now we've
got the password for the next level so
awesome thank you guys for sticking with
me hope you enjoyed this sequel
injection is super duper cool in my
opinion it's one of my
I love that aspect of web security
sequel injection in databases so I think
I just saved and overrode that my bad
let's go ahead and create a new script
for natus level 15 but hope you guys are
enjoying these thanks for watching I
hope to see you in a later video and
will do a lot more cool sequel injection
and web application security stuff
thanks again
yeah hey if you like this video please
do like the video and believe me a
comment maybe subscribe share this see
you soon