what's up everybody John Hammond here
back at the natus war game from over the
wire just finished off on level 10 now
was looks to be pretty similar to level
9 I went ahead and ran the script so we
can check out the URL what's in the page
right here and let's actually view it it
says for security reasons we now filter
on certain characters and let's add
another fine words containing a
needle-in-a-haystack same functionality
we had seen in the previous level but we
can take a look at the source code and
see what they're doing since they say
they were filtering on certain
characters so let's add that to our URL
just do to get requests on that and as
usual this is pretty gross but we can
run tidy HTML on it we can run the HTML
d entities entities and this BR or HTML
break tag it's kind of annoying we can
control H to find replace those BR and
let's replace them with nothing
Nate ctrl Alt + Enter here so they all
go away
cool so we've got the PHP code noted
here and we can search for a key that's
determined whether or not we have
actually submitted a request or posted
to this webpage and it's testing that
determining whether or not this key
exists if needle if that forum input was
provided and if it doesn't equal an
empty string if it were actually
provided from this previous conditional
it'll test if Craig match looks like
braces of square braces containing a
semicolon pipe symbol ampersand all
inside the key so preg match is regular
expressions and it's testing is there a
match for anything in this regular
expression set you can tell it's regular
expressions by the forward slash
beginning and ending and in regular
expression is the square brace means
anything within this character set so
anything like a semicolon pipe symbol or
ampersand in this case will return a
match and it's testing on the key that's
provided so whatever we actually input
and otherwise it will return out it'll
display input contains an illegal
character otherwise it will go ahead and
the command like it had in the previous
level actually run grep we can view this
in the webpage if we wanted to let me
fire that up here
steal the URL open up Firefox and we are
in natus 10 so let me just copy and
paste this password here ok great so if
we had anything with a semicolon at the
end it'll say oh this input contains an
illegal character so we can't use those
but that's okay because in the last
video for natus 9 we didn't end up using
any of those characters the exploit
quote unquote or the technique we ended
up using was posting to this page and
doing some command injection to say I
want to grep for anything with the
period because of regular expressions in
the file the like natus password file in
this case we will want natus 11 now
because we're on level 10 we want to
advance to the next level and then we
use a pound symbol or a hash tag to
comment out the rest of the line so it
didn't actually check out dictionary dot
txt it would just only run grep and
process through the password file for
the next level so since the hash tag or
that pound symbol is not in this illegal
character list it's not in this regular
expression set we can run this exact
same thing and we should still be able
to you know get the next password so
let's run that post command run that
function and let's see what's returned
to us go ahead and print the content out
I just changed URL to make sure it's
actually interacting with the page keep
in mind you may have to do that if you
forgot to but output here is the
password for the next level right that
okay we're done awesome because all we
did was just that little technique grep
for anything the period here specify the
file that we want it set run Addis web
past minus 11 and then comment at the
rest because since
there wasn't any sanitization or any
filtering done to really what's being
input into that grep command or into
that like system call that shell command
we were able to just inject just like
that same as the last level pretty easy
pretty simple really just reusing that
same exploit and now we're ready to move
on let's go to natus 11 create a script
for that I'm gonna have to replace it
because I already had some stuff that I
was just experimenting with and now we
can check out what this level is this is
going to be a pretty big one
pretty long video for natus 11 so that's
all I want to offset with a pretty short
view here for NAT is 10 because it's
really the same attack as the natus
level 9 thanks for watching guys hope
you're enjoying these I hope you're
enjoying this video if you do please
like the video comment tell me what you
think
what more videos you want to see if
you're willing to subscribe and thanks
for watching guys
hope you're enjoying these see you later