what's up everybody John Hammond here
continuing on the natus videos from the
over the wire war games so we just got
the password for and that is level 2 and
we have been storing these in these
Python scripts that we've been creating
and that way that each individual file
or script that we end up creating will
print out the flag or the password for
the level that we need to move into next
so we've got these four levels 0 level 1
etc and let's go ahead and actually run
these so make sure they're doing what
they want what we want them to do so
python natus 0 pi it prints that out
same with nightís 1 pi and we've got the
path and everything just moving swell
for us we can make all these executable
so we don't have to use that Python
preference etc and that looks good for
us okay cool so let's move into actually
natus 2 right now because I think that
is only just getting yeah the the web
page content here for us let's actually
go view that in the web browser so we
can see what we're looking with I've got
it pulled up right here again if you
needed to get to the page you can
authenticate by pasting in the password
that our scripts are now getting for us
and it says here there's nothing on the
page there is nothing on the page it's
exactly right in that regard no
interesting HTML source code or HTML
comments that we've seen like in the
previous levels but if you look closely
we do notice a image file image source
file pixel dot PNG if we examine that
just in our browser it's one by one
pixel that doesn't seem to really do
anything for us but take note that this
is currently located in a files folder
here you can see that kind of relative
path in the HTML link here or the href
the path that it's trying to reach from
the image source I'm gonna use a sublime
text to set the syntax to HTML right
here and let's go to see what we can see
in that directory can we can we reach
that and the web browser on the check
out files for slash files and we do
get to read the index of files here
interesting stuff there's pixel about
PNG and there's users txt which might be
peculiar let's go ahead and see if we
can reach this in our code let's get two
files one it was control B and we are
getting the same index of files here it
looks kind of messy in this so let's
make this better we can install a
package for sublime text I'm thinking of
HTML tidy and that will beautify tidy
and clean prettified the HTML code that
we're looking at in sublime text once
that is installed we should be able to
just ctrl shift P and run HTML tidy tidy
HTML and suddenly it will clean up all
of this for us so we can view this table
a little bit more cleanly and actually
read through this page in sublime text
so here again you'll see we've got the
pixel that's noted in here and we've got
the user's text file we can see the link
to it just relative to where we are
users text so let's check out that file
again just changing the link in our
script users dot text ctrl P to run this
and looks like we've got some
interesting stuff username and password
syntax or semantics here and we seen
that as three listening there and the
password clear as day so cool let's
great this out let's use looks like we
can just say natus : NAT it's 3 : and
then what we want to scrape out we can
we don't need to print the content
anymore we can just print out what we
scrape and there's the password for us
awesome so that is now a complete natus
to script let's put the password into a
natus 3 script change the username etc
print out the content so we can see
we're at run this again ok we're getting
a 404 not found because it thinks we're
still looking at files dot users dot X
let's make sure to change that location
and let's just keep looking in sublime
text what this
what this level looks like so HTML
source code again I'm looking at the web
page that we're on that is three content
is there's nothing on this page and
there is an HTML common here no more
information leaks not even Google will
find it this time ah okay so this is a
nod and a hint towards like Internet web
crawlers
so that's robots.txt files like google
has to index and crawl through the web
page to have all those search engine
results web robots or programs that
traverse the web automatically so search
engines such as Google used an index of
web content etc etc you may have seen me
refer to some of these and other
capture-the-flag challenges it's a
pretty common low-hanging fruit some of
you a rock you've got a check under if
you're doing some website reconnaissance
and stuff like that to see what might be
hidden from the robots.txt file so it's
just in the web root of the the website
that you're looking at so we can just
hack on robots.txt here and the website
if you learn a little bit more about
this is the syntax you'll typically see
and we'll see it just now once we run
this once we run this code cool so we
made a connection here's the response
we're getting user agent anything
disallowed the secret directory hmm if
you want to see this in your web browser
again make sure you're at natus three
that is three paste it in robots.txt and
this is just how it looks plain text
file completely nothing and that's what
we're going with so let's get check out
that secret in leet-speak directory pass
this in looks like we've got an index
page again
let's run HTML tidy so we can check out
what is in this directory listing that
we've got here a blank icon another
another icon oh hey another users dot
txt file relative to the secret path so
let's go ahead and download that user
texts run this file and we've gotten at
us for just like that all right cool
so let's put that in our regular
expression finder and we've got the
password for the next level save this as
our completed natus 3 script create it
as a new one for natus for pasting the
correct password and we are ready to
move on cool thank you guys for watching
that's all I want to cover in this video
I think the HTML tidy script or that
that plugin for sublime text is pretty
awesome
it's definitely come in handy for us as
we're doing some ninja stuff in sublime
text and just cruising through natus the
web security wargame from over the wire
will jump in the next one in the next
video but I hope you're pretty content
with what we've got so far of these
little weaponized scripts that from the
command line we can just straight-up run
hey Python NAT it's 3:00 get the
password same for Python that is 4 and
let's see we did 2 and the previous one
so 4 is what we got a complete but we're
just cruising along thank you guys for
watching hope you're enjoying these
please maybe leave a like comment
subscribe I don't know do your good
YouTube stuff see you in the next video