hey what's going on everybody this is
John Hammond and we're still looking at
the natus war game from over the wire so
we're on level 11 right now that's just
natus 11 9s that labs over the wire at
org in the URL and we looks like we have
an application you're kind of a web
application that will let us set the
color of the backgrounds for this web
page and that is pretty neat but we want
to see what's vulnerable what can we do
with it so the notice here is that
cookies are protected with xor
encryption so we can view the source
code here and this tells us okay here's
the HTML of the page and we can see some
PHP code here this is the interesting
stuff the PHP codes the server-side code
so that's what we want to know and see
what we can what we can mess with what
we can get around so looks like we have
a variable called default data you can
tell it's variable because it has a
dollar sign those are preceded variables
we received with dollar sign and PHP and
it's an array associative array of show
password assets in the string no
background colors by default set to hex
ffffff or RGB 255 255 255 and we have
functions X or encrypt and load data
save data etc and then we actually have
the level of the page the HTML of the
page and level it looks like there's a
note here it does a little condition if
the data array index had show pass over
to set to yes then it will give us the
pass over for NAT is 12 the next level
so it's censored out here but looks like
that's the functionality that we want we
need to somehow set data show password
to yes and checking out the code we can
see that data that variable is set from
the function load data and it uses by
default the default data so we saw the
default data up here but what is load
data do this is the function looks like
it reads out of the cookie PHP like
special variable it sets up the argument
that's passed in so default data
originally is def and goes through and
that's my data and it tests if the array
Q exists so if the cookie has
data set then it will looks like it
stores a variable temp data where it
tries to base64 decode an X or incur it
and then JSON decode whatever that data
cookie is set to and that's a lot of
stuff but looks like that all it really
does is extract out the those variables
it looks like it extracts out to a
password which we know by default is no
and the background color which is hex
ffffff in this case it looks like it
does that just by reading through it and
it does some preg match okay that the
regular expression is just a test
whether the background color is set to a
proper hexadecimal color cool and it
will do these things if the key exists
in that array so there must be a cookie
that's being set let's go ahead and take
a look at that I'm going to switch over
to a sublime text where I have Python
script that's letting us work with this
here is the page once we get it with the
request module in Python and we have the
content etc let's take a look at the
source code just like this again run
that and take a look make sure we
actually run it does it not doing that
for me classic okay now I've got it set
up and it looks pretty gross so we can
go ahead and do our tidy HTML and we can
go ahead and Deanna ties that and all
those BR or breaks in HTML we can remove
those because they're just in the way so
okay now we can see the PHP code in a
little bit of a better editor and this
is handy but let's just kind of take
note of this source PHP source 11 up
here or whatever you may have seen that
in my file explorer I had some stuff
already pre-prepared but that's because
I've tried to test the stuff and one of
they have it done before I started to
record
so let's keep moving here let's go ahead
and take a look at what that cookie
actually looks like so we're doing that
with the session variable we're making
this get request with a session variable
so we can print out session cookies
check this out and we don't have
anything oh because we're still viewing
the index source page let's go back to
the original page now we can check out
the cookie jar and we have data so let's
scrape him out just some array indexing
here and it looks like this which is
clearly in base64 with the % 3d and we
know that that is a URL encoded
character we can just remove that we can
decode that with URL URL Lib dot quote I
think I should bring it back nope
unquote is the one that we want because
that will remove okay they're cool nodal
properly interpret so now let's grab
base64 so we can decode that a 64 decode
and we want be 64 decode my bad so run
that and we have nonsense and garbage so
this must be the ex-ored version of this
version of the data that we're working
with because remember in the source code
that we were looking at they do run XOR
encrypt on it so it's probably going to
be a little bit difficult to really read
because it's x-ored
or exclusive or encrypted stuff like
that not really encrypted but you know I
guess maybe whatever however you want to
interpret it is XOR that operation is
ran through the data so we can take a
look at that XOR encrypt function here
and it happens with a key variable that
we don't know it's censored the input
that we pass to it so it looks like
that's just what was basic C 4 decoded
here and the out text or the very the
output variable that the result that
happens when we go through this
operation so it does this XOR in a for
loop that iterates through each
character by using I
as her iterator all the way through the
length of the text so we can index the
text and the key based off of the length
of the key modulus so it wraps around it
does a circle operation thing and it
uses the XOR operator here that that
carrot symbol so we're appending to our
output text or output text that variable
out text with the PHP concatenation
character with the dot dot equals and
then it finally gives us the out text so
okay let's try and get in the middle of
this because we can totally recreate
this function let's in fact do that I
want to see if this will copy correctly
because I see some weird characters in
this text it looks like there's no real
space or tab character in some of the
indentation for this code so let's go
ahead and did it may have done some
weird things with tidy HTML I'm gonna
copy this code from the web site from
the web page so I want X or encrypt and
I want the default data and now let's
create a PHP script where we can handle
this stuff
second natus 11 dot PHP that already
exists so let's go and replace it
because I was testing it earlier so
let's have PHP tags in here and let's
put where is our I did not totally just
color
all right or whatever whoops okay where
is PHP 7.0 you guys be bin 7.0 let's use
that as the interpreter here is our
shebang line okay now we have proper
things so if we were to try and run JSON
decode that stuff JSON decode is going
to happen when we have the encrypted
data but obviously it's going to just be
plain text of this they they loaded this
to begin with
with save data so that must have
happened with JSON encode here
let's go ahead and see what that looks
like JSON encode our default data and
let's echo that out to the screen so we
can see it and second that is 11 PHP we
will run it and okay it looks like just
a string that's all updated or it
interprets it however we need to cool so
if we wanted to use that and that's
what's passed in to our encrypt well
perfect let's try and see if we can
figure out the key for that data that we
already have because we know what the
original is that's this encoded version
and we know what the actual XOR result
was we can kind of figure out what the
key might be because XOR how it works
with specific properties we have a
ex-ored with B and that equals C right
so in that case plaintext XOR with the
key equals ciphertext but we can reverse
this operation because we can switch
these things around if we try an XOR the
plaintext with the cipher text will
return the key so let's try and do that
let's create another function where we
can pass in a key and and then key let's
just modify that actually we don't need
to create a whole new one now that
that's passed in and somehow
let's okay let's call this original data
that we're working with and let's go
ahead and get the yeah the XOR data is a
way we can pass it to this PHP code so
since we're working with it over here as
random garbage characters
actually go ahead and hexif I that
encode into hex so that is now the raw
version just in hex and then what we can
give it easily to the PHP code by
passing that in and decoding it so let's
actually because you saw in the source
code they were using functions called
bin to hex or hex to bin that may
actually they have been in another in
the previous level but that will you
know get the raw bytes out of some hacks
so if I echo hex to bin and pass in that
hex we should be able to see that yeah
okay cool so there's the raw stuff so
let's say this is the ciphertext and
this is the plaintext so now we can
figure out the key by running our XOR
encrypt by passing in the plaintext and
what we're gonna use as the ciphertext
for our key here because we're just
doing that operation a XOR B equals C so
a XOR C equals B now let's try and run
that echo X or encrypt with the
plaintext and the ciphertext check this
out and we get something that repeats we
get this Q w8j over and over and over
again so that must be the original key
just those four so now we can use that
as our key we can say key equals this
string and so now we can have the data
that we want to work with a data that we
actually want the good data where show
password is equal to is set to yes and
now we can run the like operation to get
the cookie value for that
we let's see that was first we have to
XOR it we need to run JSON encode on our
good data so now good plaintext and we
have the key so good ciphertext can
equal to X or encrypts pass in the good
plaintext now that we have and the key
that we want to give it cool so now
let's just echo that out and see what
our good ciphertext is it's good
probably gonna look like nonsense yep
because it's X word so what did they do
in their script to handle it
they base64 encoded it okay
so let's do that we have that function
in PHP as well so cookie can equal a 64
in code of the good ciphertext and now
let's set check out what the cookie is
this whatever this is so let's copy and
paste this into our Python script let's
set cookies data set to this and so now
we will get this page just as we had
before but we'll pass in cookies equals
cookies now we can print all this let's
move those up here so it looks normal
let's run this and see we've got on the
page now that we've given it the proper
cookie we got it set this index to HTML
and you can see here it ran with the
password for not as 12 is this guy cool
so that worked all we did was do a
little trick with XOR was figuring out
what the key was by XOR in both the
plaintext and the ciphertext because we
had those originally and that property
of XOR will allow us to determine the
key perfect so now now that we have the
password to the NAT is 12 let's go ahead
and create a new script and get us back
to where we were a fresh script that was
12 and when we run this now you can see
we are on NAT as level 12 okay awesome
sweet that was it that was our cool and
good way to get through natus level 11
just trying to take advantage of their
PHP code modifying the XOR function so
it can take a key in that we can pass to
it and then using the plaintext and the
ciphertext to our advantage so thank you
guys for watching hope you're enjoying
this and these videos if you are hey
please like the video maybe leave the
comments and what you think if you're
willing to subscribe and thank you again
I'll see you in the next video