in this video I'm gonna show you a
supercool attack that leverages local
file inclusion against a blacklist to
achieve remote code execution by abusing
PHP code injection in the HTTP user
agent header keep watching to learn how
to do this and more right now what's up
everybody my name is John Hammond we're
looking at natus level 25 and I think
this level is awesome because it ties
together a lot of cool techniques that
we've seen in previous levels and things
knowledge that we've built up so far and
it bundles them together into one really
cool attack so I'm showing you this in
the web browser first because for one
thing the source code looks better in
the web browser for these levels because
it has the PHP highlight file like
syntax highlighting and all that but in
this case I want to show you the
functionality of this Before we jump
into attacking it and writing our script
so it looks like it's just a static page
with blank text which is weird we
haven't seen that before in natus but we
do have a little bit of functionality up
at the top right it looks like it lets
us change the language that we're
viewing this text in looks like en for
English and de for German and that's
about all that we can do so thankfully
over the wire and at us these war games
let us see the source code as to what
the code is doing so let's take a look
at what that actually is here
HTML stuffs not important but the PHP
stuff that's highlighted is interesting
to us so a lot of functions being
defined at the very very bottom that
just gets the content of the web page
looks like there's a PHP function or set
of the PHP code running this list files
function that it defines up top and then
the main section of the content creates
a new session uses the set language
function that it defines up top and then
I think these variables that are being
displayed come from something earlier in
the code so let's actually floor what
those functions really are list files
language as F so a temporary variable
for okay just displaying the options for
what it's reading out it looks like list
files must be used to see the potential
like English or German or other
different languages that we want to
this message or this blog post in and
that looks like it's going to be used as
and include because we see for each list
files and lists files it gets read all
those things out just as file names and
that option that we give it looks to be
a form you can see just barely in the
HTML here it's not highlighted pretty
but on the form submit the option that
gets sent to it up at the very top you
can see a function set language that
determines okay if we have in the
request a language being set whether or
not we chose English or German it's
being passed to the safe include
function by default it will just return
English so this safe include function
looks like it takes an argument for the
file name and it tries to check for
directory traversal okay interesting if
string string filename okay
dot dot forward slash so trying to
determine if the notion of the parent
directory is present inside the string
then it runs this thing log request
that'll say okay directory traversal
attempt fixing request and it looks like
it just replaces and tries to remove
that up directory notion or that that
attempt to go into the parent directory
so what that's trying to prevent local
file inclusion which we've seen before
is a significant vulnerability it looks
like it does that log request which is
another function down here log request
gets the current date adds it to a
string that it keeps concatenating and
adding things on to it adds the HTTP
user agent so it would say like Firefox
or Chrome or Internet Explorer whatever
browser you are using and we've seen
that before also we may be able to
change its another HTTP header that we
can manipulate that's interesting thing
to note and it adds the message so that
must be the okay directory traversal
attempt fixing across the argument
that's passed in and it puts this in VAR
dub dub dub natus notice 25 logs session
ID okay and that session ID is that PHP
session ID that we've seen before and
are in our cookies
so we know that value when we're working
in our script because we can just get
that out from our cookies interesting
thing to keep in mind another
interesting thing that we saw in the
safe include function is it tests if the
natus web pasture ring is in the file
name it will log ok illegal file access
detected aborting it's not going to
allow us to simply type natus web pass
in whatever file we're trying to read
out of the language keyword or the
language variable that we're passing to
it and then it looks like it makes sure
the file exists sitting actually
included at the very very end so that
looks like it's how it's getting that
greeting message and footer variable
that's displayed on the page so okay
really the only thing we have to work
with is this language variable so let's
try and hit that local file inclusion
let's see if we can actually get it to
trigger this directory traversal attempt
and see if we can replace those dot dot
/a dot dot slash us to see that up
directory or the parent directory and
what we're looking for
ok it's it over to sublime text I've got
it printing out these page results right
here and there is a long quote blah blah
blah okay so let's try and post to this
something with the language parameter
being set post with data lang can equal
let's see de just by default that will
give it to us in German right because
that is okay yeah that's the file name
that it's getting so let's try and
change that to just four slash dot dot
slash dot dot slash dot dot slash go up
a couple many directories and let's try
and read etcetera password because we
know that file will be on the system so
if we were to get a result we would be
able to see it and it looks like we
don't have anything that that fires but
that makes sense because that log
request function is just writing to the
file as we know in the source code it's
not writing out to any output or
anything that we can particularly see
but we know that it is replacing those
forward slashes the dot sought for
slashes in the up directory because that
would at least be removed according to
that string replace function so let's
try and actually not give it a file here
and see what it does because I had an
interesting hiccup that I saw earlier we
see a lot of PHP warnings and notices if
we get it to fail without reading actual
file it says here fails to open stream
no such file directory in the current
location of that script index dot PHP
etc etc so an interesting thing because
it's not able to actually read these
variables it's not able to include
anything so we know we do have that
local file inclusion potential now we
have to actually get around that
blacklist or trying to replace these dot
forward slashes so it's an interesting
thing because it's simply doing a
replacement operation because what's to
stop us from trying to hide or kind of
camouflage or whatever you'd like to
think of it as or trying to sneak in
some more or like an actual parent
directory or up-up dot for the dot dot
forward slash notation inside another
one right because if we're running a
string to replace dot dot forward slash
with nothing so it'll go away why don't
we try and put a nother dot dot forward
slash inside what we have before so
it'll replace maybe the innermost one
this will go away but then once it's
left after it's completed that replace
operation you'll have just okay the
skeleton or the makings of an original
like up up like dot dot forward slash
you'll be able to actually transverse
that see because I was able to put in
just another one here that's all that it
tried to find and replace and then once
that is gone you're just simply left
with the same string that you wanted to
begin with so that's going to be an
interesting tactic let's see if we can
actually get some local file inclusion
by using that
I'm going to include that a couple times
many times because we don't exactly know
how far up the directory we're gonna
have going but let's try and include
etcetera password let's run the script
see if we get it and we do okay cool we
just leaked out etc password on the box
so now we need to figure out how we can
actually get the password for the next
user this is an interesting thing right
because the source code has this
explicit under blacklist operation if
natus web pass is in the original
filename that we supply it will log the
request and exit won't let us actually
have the functionality anymore so what
can we do instead this is a really cool
attack and I think this is an awesome
thing because it takes a little bit of
ingenuity thinking outside the box but
also keeping in mind the things that
we've learned in previous levels and
combining them for an awesome attack so
let's think what files do we have access
to right now literally everything on the
file system right literally everything
on the file system including the logs
that this application like saves and
reports for us so because we know the
location of this like this log we can
potentially get it to be displayed for
us so we know we are going to have one
entry in this log file because we're
using this directory transversal it'll
say ok directory traversal attempt
fixing a request now let's see if we can
actually read that file by trying to
locate this file in the file system so
we need to know the session ID but we
can do that right because we've got a
session that we can create let's write a
get request to begin with so we actually
get a session set up and then let's
determine what our cookies are when we
try print session cookies PHP session ID
let's not display the other things just
so we know we have a session here cool
yep that works just fine for us we can
index it just like that
so let's go ahead and try to in like
read that file we know in the source
code it's var dub notice that of 25 and
25 it said our session ID
dot log so changing the file that we're
trying to read now to not add cetra
password but that string
remember to concatenate on the dot log
extension and remember we do want to
have our session dot cookies PHP session
ID right there and that should be
concatenated on just fine and now we
should be able to read that remember to
print out the output I managed to drop
that cool now we're seeing that log
entry we're seeing the time and date
this has occurred we're seeing our user
agent which right now is python request
because we're doing this in the script
and we see that message directory
traversal attempt to fixing the request
so we know it's no replacing the dot dot
forward slash okay now here is the next
cool and awesome part because we can
control what this HTTP user agent is we
actually that that is input for us we
can modify that HTTP header so because
we're including this file and because
it's being spat out from the web server
that is looking at PHP code normally
right we've got notices and warnings and
all these other issues that are coming
through
what if we put PHP code as our user
agent let's try this that's gonna be
really cool right let's get a headers
dictionary here headers can equal user
tack agent so that's it up and then
let's use just the syntax to run a PHP
file command right here and now what do
we want to do oh how about determine the
contents of you know the natus password
that we want NAT is 26 so how can we do
that well it's PHP right we can just run
shell commands we've got system passed
through etcetera all those things so
let's just try system and let's use our
classic cat etc natus web pass natus 26
subtle display it on Center out for us
and we'll be able to read it because we
can specify we want our user agent to be
this string which will get injected into
that log entry which will be able to
read because of local file inclusion and
then it'll evaluate that PHP and give us
remote code execution with this super
super cool
try headers equals headers to make sure
we include that user agent let's run
this and what do we got here
excellent our user agent is now the
password for natus level 26 suite let's
go ahead and save this as a new script
NAT is 26 we can clear up the junk that
we have here go ahead and make just a
regular get request and let's see if we
are greeted with the next level make
sure that's the right password and it
certainly is we're on natus level 26 so
cool thank you guys so much for watching
I really do hope you enjoyed this I love
this this level honestly this is I think
one of the coolest levels that NAT has
has so far and that you're combining all
the other tactics and techniques that
we've seen so far and making a really
interesting attack take an advantage of
that HTTP user agent injecting that PHP
code so you get remote code execution
through the local file inclusion that
you already went through like some
little like blacklist evasion and I
thought that's awesome so hey thank you
guys for watching I want to give a shout
out to my supporters here this list is
getting pretty lengthy and long so I'm
super duper grateful thank you guys so
much for all of your support I love that
you are willing to go on this adventure
and journey with me so hey if you did
like this video please do press that
like button maybe leave me a comment let
me know what you think what you'd like
what you'd like to see what we could
have done better how you solve this etc
if you're willing to subscribe and if
you really want to support me check me
out on patreon cool see you soon guys