hey what's up YouTube this is John
Hammond and in this video we're looking
at natus level 15 from over the wire so
this level we just got the password for
not as level 15 so we can use the same
Python script when using to get the web
page see what we're actually working
with here and when we're looking at the
web page source HTML here we have a form
that goes to index dot PHP it's on the
post request with the username we can
fill out that looks like the only field
here and the button submit goes to check
existence so maybe it's just trying to
determine whether or not a user exists
we can go ahead and take a look at the
source code here by going to that view
source or index source page we'll go
ahead and DN to tie some of these and
let's remove all these break statements
here because we're getting in the way so
now I've got the page source here and we
can see the PHP code looks like it gives
us a schema a little bit of the database
like okay we have a user's table with a
username and password just in there and
we're determining if the array key
exists user name in the request so okay
if we actually post of the form and that
user name is is present we conduct the
database with the sensor password select
a database and the query that we're
running is select all from users where
username again concatenate it in so
pretty obvious sequel injection there
and we get the debug query again if we
want to take a look at it and we get the
query results and if we have a result
one or another it tells us this user
exists or this user doesn't exist or
where there's an error in the query okay
so we don't actually get to know any
information we don't actually log in or
anything really just determining a
binary kind of a yes or no does this
unit exist does this user not exist so
let's go ahead and play with this let's
go ahead and change this to a post
request and let's go to the original web
page not the source anymore
let's actually take the source though
and just put it in a new pane in case we
want it later on
and let's go ahead and post with the
data keyword arguments having user name
and what
say like John just to test that stuff
out I'm going to assume user doesn't
exist okay then I miss my opportunity to
use like username subscribe or something
dang it alright
but natus 16 so the next level here
looks like that we can assume that user
probably will exist okay that user does
exist so we want from the database here
we want to be able to find the user
where the username is equal to Natta 16
and we want to somehow leak out their
password but we can't do sequel
injection like we've done before because
we're not logging into anything
we don't have explicit sequel injections
so we can't see some of the results we
can only determine whether or not a yes
or a No well user exists or the user
doesn't exist so now we can get into a
tactic called blind sequel injection so
blind sequel injection means we're
probably gonna have to leak out data
like byte by byte or character by
character because we can't explicitly
see a result but we can figure out some
data by testing other characters over
and over again until we get one that
matches so we can determine through that
yes or no determination whether a user
exists or does not exist if we're on the
correct character or not and because we
have our sequel injection we know we can
have a valid query if we really wanted
to so let's change this user name to be
able to use the double quote here and we
can comment this out and we'll still get
a user exists' right if we had and one
equals two we can get this to be an
invalid statement that user doesn't
exist because one does not equal to an
and statement ruins that but that and
condition because we're using our sequel
injection lets us do more here we can
test and the password is equal to
something right we don't know what the
password actually is so we can't use
equal two but we can try and figure out
what the password is like and with that
we can start to iterate through possible
characters like
maybe any any possible thing a letter
not a uppercase letter a lowercase
letter or a number like the typical
style we've seen in all the other naty's
passwords we can figure out if the
password is containing those characters
and
we can leak out like character by
character what that password is so we
can do that with the sequel like
statement and we can determine if it's
like anything right
the anything character or the wild-card
character and a sequel like statement
eyes a % so we can say and password like
anything with the wild-card that will
return true right the user exists
because that wildcard will match
anything but if we had the password like
the word anything or who knows right we
don't know the password and that user
doesn't exist because that like isn't
going to work for us because there is no
that wildcard isn't affecting it and
it's not matching anything it's matching
only who knows and the password
obviously isn't that so we can actually
take advantage of this though we can
start to loop through all the possible
characters or what could be part of the
password so let's go ahead and grab
those things from string import all so
we can say characters that we want to
look through can equal lowercase that
we've got from the string module appear
and uppercase that we've got from the
string module above and digits so all of
these variables exist in that string
module but if we're seeing them seeing
the characters that we've put together
now we've got a list or a string really
how this 15 yeah okay all of these
things that we can work with so now we
can post this request make the sequel
injection happen and determine what the
password is like what we've built so far
of the password and trying to test each
character by character if we wanted to
test if the passages like a and anything
that follows with our wildcard here or B
and anything that follows with the wild
or either C etc de F and the list goes
on and on until you get like Oh F maybe
that's the correct letter it's or until
we find ELLs correct letter and then B
or a etc and we can leak out the
password by using this wildcard and by
using this technique this will happen
over a period of time right we're gonna
have to loop here so let's start a while
loop Wow
true do this over and over and over
again we can do for CH in characters so
every single character that we're
working with let's just print that out
for now
and you can see that loop goes over and
over and over and with the characters
let's keep track of what we've seen of
the password so seeing password that
will be a list and I was gonna declare
it empty like this so it'll be really
easy for us to append on to it or join
it together as a string so we can try
and print out trying character with
password and then join of what we've
seen of the password so when we join
that scene password together that just
makes it a string that's some Python
syntactic sugar to join every element in
the list or element in the array to
gether with an empty string so it puts
them all together as one string nice so
now we can get the response but we're
gonna have to change our post request to
make that like statement add in what
we've seen so far of the password as a
string right so I'm terminating my
original string with the single quote
but I'm still inside the like query here
with the double quotes that the note
this is part of the like sequel string
adding in what we've seen of the
password and then the character that
we're looking at currently and if we
wanted to actually check out what the
DES bug query is you can see that this
is going to be iterating through what
we've seen including our scene password
so we can actually do change this to
trying with password + CH and you'll see
it move just like that
great
trying with password ABCD efg etc etc
etc but right now we're not actually
seeing what the response is coming back
to us with let's actually get the
response and then let's just print it
out in our loop this is gonna look
pretty messy and pretty crazy but as
you'll see this user doesn't exist for
just about everything but eventually we
will trigger oh this user does exist for
one of these maybe it'll happen too
quickly
oh actually I forgot the % remember we
need our wild card because doing that
like is only going to be doing ok it'll
match this if it's like this query but
the % with the wild card will allow us
to fill out the rest of this now when I
go back and run the script we should be
able to see this user doesn't exist but
for one of these
it'll gimmick just like that you just
saw it and the user does exist for where
it is like trying with password W this
user does exist ok cool so now we know
we've just leaked out W is the first
character of this password so we don't
know whether or not it's gonna be case
sensitive or not though because by
default sequel is case insensitive so
that password may be using maybe
starting with the W but we don't know
there abouts lowercase or uppercase we
can change that by our query saying and
binary password putting binary right
before that in the Select statement
we'll make that field case sensitive so
now we can test if user exists is in the
content and if that's the case we can
say scene password dot append the
current character we've got our CH and
then we can break out of this for loop
and keep moving on cool so now let's try
and work through this we're not printing
out the entire content anymore but
lowercase W didn't catch but we'll
capital W catch it does ok cool and now
we're leaking out more W a that looked
like it went through that's a true
etcetera
cool we're getting more of them and this
will happen slowly but surely we will
get the flag just like this so I'm gonna
wait a second I'm going to pause the
video here and let this run and we'll
see if we can leak out the whole
password I think we're getting close to
the end here I sure hope so so this is
taking a little bit of time right that
goes without saying this is obviously a
real attack right blind sequel injection
is a real real thing you can take
advantage of with databases so it's
gonna take a little bit of time because
we're doing a real take advantage of a
real vulnerability and they're real
technique so we're almost at the end
here I sure hope so
how long are these passwords usually 32
characters Oh sublime text just had some
of those things that it acted funny with
sorry how much are we at right now 27
okay so we're getting real close it
looks like this one has been going for a
while so I don't think there's any way
we can particularly test this other than
just looking at the length okay so that
is 32 characters right now and I guess
we didn't make our program smart enough
to determine that that was the end but
we aren't actually getting any other
results back yet so that must be the
whole password so let's break this for
now and that should be what we were able
to move on with if for some reason I
just want to tell you this for your own
knowledge here if you only got like half
of this password or something and you
needed it you want to keep moving where
you were like were you left off that's
okay you can easily do that without
wasting all that time that you spent
waiting by putting that in as you're
seeing password like initialize it as a
string inside of the list object here
and that way you would start off right
where you had everything to begin with
and you can still keep moving along with
your sequel injection your blind sequel
injection loop with what you have so far
well you've built so far of the password
so that's a good way to keep that in
mind let's go
create a new script and just kind of
save this as natus 16 because now we've
got the password and let's see if we can
go ahead and read that page let's make
sure we actually did get the correct
password let's print out response dot
text should just make that content and
then print that out just like all of our
other scripts and awesome we are on
natus level 16 awesome looks like we
just did that looks like we just got a
blind sequel injection attack and leaked
out a password from a database so I hope
you guys really liked that technique
it's really just looping through all of
the like common characters or printable
characters that you're used to and
adding them onto a list or what you've
already seen so far I'm using that like
technique with the % is really great
there are other techniques where you can
say not only is the password because I
showed you where the password is equal
to but I said you can have the password
greater than because obviously when you
get down to it the numbers or all the
letters or all these ASCII characters
that you're trying are just decimal
numbers they're all 0 to 255 in the
ASCII table so if you went in ASCII
order you could terminal them out the
password is greater than something like
that and binary of course will make it
case sensitive so that's a pretty handy
trick too but I like the like character
because or the sorry the like term
because that way you can keep the
current character you're on rather than
seeing that threshold trigger because if
you're using the greater than symbol
you'll get results like the user does
exist that user does exist the user does
exist and then once the user does not
exist you know that ok the previous
character that I was just on with that
technique with the greater than symbol
was the correct one so you have to get a
backtrack for your character testing if
you're using that style but I like the
like statements equal here that's I
think that's a cool technique with the
wild-card so thank you guys for watching
again I really hope you're enjoying this
I think this is some really cool web
application security and exploits and
attacks so I'll see you in the next
video when we tackle natus level 16 hey
if you like this video please do like
the video or comment tell me let me know
what you think let me know what I can do
better subscribe and if you thanks so
much guys see you in another video