what's going on guys John Hammond here
coming back at you with some more natus
videos from the over the wire war game
so we just got up to level six here we
just got the paska for it in the
previous videos and again we're still
working with Python scripts that will go
ahead and return the actual password for
us they're kind of a flag to get it to
the next level
so that's been working pretty well for
us we're working in Python scripts and
now we're on to level 6 so let's go
ahead and check out what we're working
with here we're still using a request
object session and when we run this
script control B we're not getting an
output let's find out why okay looks
like we're good now sweet let's let's
see what this this page is here in the
content of the natus 6 level there's a
post method form okay it says input
secret and checking the secret that
that's that's all we submit that's all
we're submitting okay it's just going to
be posted so what is the issue there
let's try and make a post to it let's
change our command here to post to URL
and we'll pass in some data we need
right we need the secret to I guess
equal anything we'll keep our auth like
credentials move it in so name equals
secret and make sure submit is it should
be going through on its own submit so
now if we run this what was the response
seemingly nothing okay what is going on
oh oh there is a view source code okay
totally missed that out there is a view
source out HTML script here that's
linked so let's see what we've got
maybe it's doing something
humor with this with this input secret
that we're doing let's change the URL
that we want to just add the what was it
he was index - source dot HTML after we
get that page oh goodness gracious this
looks pretty bad
let's encode special characters will
that work for us no well what about tidy
HTML HTML tag will that come to save the
day kind of maybe we can install a
package to HTML escape or decode encode
mmm dang how do we HTML escape this
because we've got all the using coded
ones see if there's an easy way to do
that head on over to our friend Google
sublime text HTML T code dan - ties
looks like there's a package here has
commands to convert HTML entities to a
character let's try that install package
it was called string in code installed
cool HTML D into ties ok that did some
stuff will dance it ties again sweet
cool we just got the source code just
like that alright
if array key exists submit posts if the
secret so this is PHP code right you can
tell here too noting
well at least the question marks and
braces make it say that this is PHP code
so if you haven't heard of PHP it is the
backend language on most servers that
will do processing of code and
server-side code before a page is
returned to you so it looks like it is
including something from a separate file
maybe we can access that and it looks
like it gets a variable secret out of
that we can only assume that's how that
dollar sign is referred to PHP variables
are denoted by a preceding dollar sign
in PHP code and it's testing if the
submit okay so if it is submitted if the
post request has been made it tests if
the secret that we posted to it what we
actually submit to the form is equal to
that secret and if it is it will give us
the password ok so let's check out see
if we can access that included file
let's just tack that on to our request
change that instead of the it is ok cool
and we get the secret here this guy I
don't think that our browser I don't
know if because normally this clearly
this is PHP code you can tell by the
beginning and ending question mark and
greater-than less-than symbol Wacka
Wacka what everyone I call them PHP code
here would normally not be rendered out
to the web browser you not be able to
receive that I think there's an issue in
that the designer didn't name that file
with a dot PHP extension you can tell
Apache or web server to evaluate things
that you can tell a browser to do some
of those things with like evaluate PHP
code on things that don't have a PHP
extension but it's probably a good idea
to use the same extension if you like if
you want to and you can so all did that
didn't go through but we got the secret
for it did I put it in my clipboard I
did ok cool so let's go ahead and paste
that or post that in this case with
using
as the data that we give that we submit
and now let's see what the response is
nothing why did that happen I don't
think maybe we're not giving the submit
key and that's necessary because we
aren't giving it we let's say submit can
equal submit now that should evaluate
okay great that PHP code ran and it said
great the password for Nana seven is
here let's steal this glad that was able
to be echoed out for us paste that in
here if we run it will we get it great
we've got it let's go ahead and save
that so if we had submitted that just
how we were in a web browser let's get
let's get to that page and show you how
it looks just even in your web browser
all that's happening is let's go to now
six that that form that input secret
formed here we're submitting this like
all we're doing is literally typing that
in and pressing the clicker button you
can see through like your developer
tools if you're checking that out in
Firefox or your web browser you can see
that you're making a post request when
you do that so if I loaded this page
here all the get requests that are
happening to that URL and if we input a
secret here we submit the query you can
see that it was posted here and you can
check out the headers of stuff that we
sent it like you've seen before in the
previous video here's the server the
content that we're working with and
refer we had in here just like a
previous video and we actually ascended
the parameters the data that we're
working with secret that we encoded or
secret that we sent and sent as a form
data put into dictionary data type with
the Python could work with
and then we got the response here's your
webpage back here's everything they gave
you and since the PHP back-end server
code was able to process it we are
granted with the Natta 7 password neat
all right cool
really that's all for this video I think
we're dragging on for a little bit of
time here so thank you guys for watching
I hope you enjoyed this and we'll move
into native 7 in the next video see you
soon