PHP object injection through the
serialized and uncivilized PHP functions
can be super dangerous especially if
there's complete user control over what
data is being serialized keep watching
to see how we can take advantage of this
to get remote code execution on a
vulnerable web app right now what's up
everybody my name is jon hamm and we're
looking at natus level 26
so we're prompted with this draw a line
functionality and it looks like it will
let us just enter coordinates for maybe
a line that we want to draw and it looks
like the application once we submit this
we'll go ahead and create an image that
is displayed for us with that line or
whatever created so let's take a look at
the source code let's see what's wrong
with it let's see what we can do because
this is another really cool
vulnerability in PHP objects well let's
take a look at the source code HTTP had
HTML stuff here not HTTP are just HTML
whatever long acronym a bunch of H words
or series of words an acronym so the PHP
code here is using a little bit of
object-oriented programming you can see
we have a class here called class logger
and this has some variables set up
private that it uses only inside that
class or inside that object and they're
denoted by the this keyword PHP uses the
arrow notation to denote the use of its
own private variables inside of an
object or inside of a class so it
creates a file looks like that's going
to use to log based off of temporary
directory and temporary file that we
create here and it keeps track of the
session supposedly it has a function log
that will display stuff there and
destruct will okay save it to the file
and write it all up
that's fine so construct is a
constructor destruct is the destructor
constructor happens first when the
object is first created destructor
happens once the object is destroyed or
once it's done once it's not in use
anymore
these underscore underscore functions
are PHP magic object functions so they
are like necessary and built-in for PHP
keep that in mind because that's crucial
to this attack that we're going to be
looking at with our object serialization
and deserialization
there are codes to show an image it
looks like it just includes that HTML
image elements draw image it looks like
PHP functions to use a color and create
a new PNG image etc etc and draw from
user data it looks like another custom
function here it takes advantage of
these x coordinates and Y coordinates
that we pass along looks like it's
passing it through that to the get
method and it goes to head and draws a
line just like that and it looks like it
actually does this with a drawing cookie
we can see it's testing if this cookie
drawing it exists in the in the cookie
array then it uncie realises this data
its basic C Ford encoded to begin with
so that's why they have to decode it
here and that's important to note
because uncie realizing data that we
have complete control over is a huge
vulnerability because that can lead to
some unsafe stuff happening that can
lead to some PHP remote code execution
and will take advantage of it in a
really really cool way as we get into it
but other than that it just creates this
image in line store data again taking
advantage of these x1 y1 coordinates
storing them as an object and creating
that as a drawing cookie that we have in
base64 so you can see this store data
function does that with an empty bit or
a little bit of nothing to begin with or
creates an empty array but it will
create a serialized form of that object
in base64 encoded the page itself will
create a session and it looks like it's
using our session ID as the actual
location that it's loading the image
file from so let's play around with the
code let's see how we can take advantage
of this and let's see how we can
manipulate it let's get over to our
script hit ctrl B to run it set the
syntax to PHP here cool so let's see how
this looks
if we pass along some of those arguments
here
let's create another request we're going
to change the URL to include x1 can
equal 0 + y1 can equal 0 x2 can equal
like 500 just like we've used before and
y2 can equal 500 now let's go ahead and
print that see how this looks you can
see it's using our image source here
that's using from that PHP function and
it's using that session ID supposedly
let's actually go ahead and take a look
at that session cookies PHP session ID
and okay you can see that q1 c9 a is the
same thing that it's using right there
but take note that we can control this
we can actually inject something into
this like that session ID is just a
cookie so let's change it to something
like try some local file inclusion let's
go up the parent directory a ton see if
we can read out it's a tree password I
don't know what this even would do
because it can't create a PNG from that
but we get a bunch of warnings and PHP
errors session to start the session ID
is too long contains little characters
looks like the only valid characters are
alphanumeric and hyphens and commas so
obviously it can't create that stream
and it's not a PNG so it can't use this
image PNG function so that doesn't
really work out very well for us but we
can get into something else with that
object this logger class because that
looks like something that's being
considered serialized and actually like
loaded into PHP and we have complete
control over it we can take advantage of
that because it's just a cookie right we
can see our original get request here
let's see the cookies that we have
before we supposedly submit the form the
request cookie jar has a session ID
after that but if we take a look at this
session cookies following our request
let's try and run this
request cookie jar there's a cookie for
PHP session ID when we have another one
drawing that looks like base64 encoded
data so let's go ahead and take a look
at what that really is let's get drawing
out of here and let's go ahead and
import base64 so we can decode it and
take a look at what that code is basics
t4b 64 decode run this incorrect padding
let's see what that actually looks like
maybe it's not including the equal sign
of the very end or 2rl encoding there it
is
so let's decode that with URL Lib you
are a Lib dot quote and maybe unquote I
believe I do that constantly it is
unquote okay now we have our equal sign
perfect let's base64 decode that sweet
so we have strings and objects and
things all created supposedly in an
array but this is PHP serialized data so
let's take advantage of it with our
logger method if we can steal that code
this class logger we can actually change
what these variables are and what they
do and if we give that to the cookie
that drawing cookie and the PHP
application will like uncie realize that
data for us it'll load up this logger
and we'll try and write that message and
we may be able to take advantage of what
we actually write to a file and we can
actually essentially get some code on
the server and maybe run our own PHP
code because we are writing to a file
with this
so let's steal this logger class I'm
going to put this in another file I'll
call it 26 under school
tool dot PHP and set the syntax to PHP
by adding this PHP tags and stuff above
it so let's indent get proper whitespace
here
so let's create a new object for that
let's say new logger can be just object
object can equal new logger and then
let's go ahead and echo out the base64
version actually let's not let's not
encode it yet let's make sure we can see
that serialize data let's just run
serialize on our object cool so in the
shell over here let's run our 26 tool
might just run PHP 7.0 26 tool and I'm
getting a couple PHP warnings in there
so let's actually just redirect Center
error to elsewhere okay so we see we
have a logger object and it's creating
keeping track of these files here so
let's go ahead and it changed some of
these variables because we can take
advantage of them and have them do
interesting things like write to a
different file and write new things like
PHP code so let's do some PHP code
injection like that
let's put this in a relative path that
we know we can access something like
image right because it's trying to load
out of that image directory yep image
files are from image forward slash natus
in the session ID so let's put something
at like image winner dot PHP and we can
have some PHP code that's being written
in the initialization or exit message
let's use that regular PHP syntax and
let's run our system command cat
etcetera and that is web pass for the
next level cool that should get us some
commands running in this image pointer
dot PHP file so now that that's been
updated let's take a look at what the
output of the script is okay logger
we got the object putting it at that
file and looked like it's just running
PHP code perfect now let's go ahead and
base64 encode this
okay a lot of stuff here but we can copy
this and we can set this to our drawing
variable in our session cookie session
dot cookies
equal I'm sorry drawing right because
that's the cookie that we're working
with set that equal to that base64
string check out the response here and
let's go ahead and run this in the build
output do I have an error anywhere I do
see what we got
oh I may not have included my semicolons
here yet the pH in that PHP code so now
we can go back and get actual proper
base64 code here perfect let's go ahead
and change that now when we run this
script we have a new fatal error cannot
use object of type logger as an array
okay and that makes sense because
they're just trying to read that file as
a array right in the code it looks like
it tries to read that out as an array
but we know that that means that our
code successfully executed we know that
we got that object to unsee realized so
now we should have a new file supposedly
at image winner dot PHP so if we get
that and check out the response we've
got the next password heck yeah so I
actually had use this for a little bit
of testing earlier some Nada's 26
passengers up here but that is the
naddis 27 password 5/5 TB etc etc looks
like we had it a couple more times from
whatever reason but that means that hey
we won there was our attack we did some
PHP object manipulation with
deserializing objects and take an
advantage of some of those cool PHP
magic functions so if you want to learn
more about this attack it is PHP objects
D serialization I want to make sure I
can actually type this PHP object D
serialization and you'll see a ton of
write-ups on this you'll see a lot of
Oh wasp articles etc etc and they all
have that same methodology where there
is a class or a little bit of
object-oriented programming set up and
they're using a PHP magic method like
underscore underscore construct or
destructor to string etcetra etcetra so
totally check those out because you'll
see them a lot in CTF that is a common
attack if you see the uncivilized
function in PHP you should automatically
know something is wrong especially if
you can control the data that's inside
because that is going to be your attack
vector so SuperDuper cool thank you guys
for watching I want to give a shout out
to my supporters real quick
thank you to all of these people Spencer
Clark Gayle Horowitz ok Attila
or Gaddafi and ruler unruly destroyer of
worlds madam chair Jen Rob Timothy
County and Jacob H etc if I butchered
name I'm sorry but hey you are awesome
thank you so much for supporting me
thank you for being willing to go on
this journey with me $1 for patreon a
month will give you the shout-out just
like this at the end of every video $5
and more will give you early access to
things that I'm trying to push out in
the YouTube before they go live if in
case I record anything in advance and
YouTube is scheduling so thank you thank
you thank you hey if you did like this
video please do press that like button
maybe leave me a comment let me know
what you think what else you'd like to
see what we could have done better how
you solve this at cetera if you're
willing to subscribe and if you really
want to support me check me out on
patreon thanks again guys
see you later video