what's up guys John Hammond here coming
back at you with another video for the
natus war game from over the wire so we
just got the password for level 9 and
we've got a script that will get the
webpage content for us so we don't have
to use a web browser and this one looks
like it's saying alright natus 9 here's
a form you can find words containing and
inputs just regular text variable looks
like with the variable name needle and
it looks like it'll search for us the
output is displayed in pre formatted
text and we could probably see that in
the web browser if we really wanted to
let's do that just so you get an idea of
what this level looks like natus 9 and
thatis 9 and you can see there is
another option here to view source code
so we can check that out
index source HTML that was the name of
the file and we can do that in our
sublime text stuff if we really wanted
to we could decode that if we wanted to
or we can just view it in the web
browser so it'll handle that a little
bit nicely ok so looks like PHP code the
notes here with variables with a dollar
sign and all key is apparently set to
whatever we post to whatever is
requested once we communicate with the
server and if key is not an empty string
it will pass through hmm what is that
looks like a function pass through I'll
check that out and it's oh it looks like
it might be running a command here grep
so like we've kind of done in the
command line with the bash shell grep
whatever we pass to it nice key in
dictionary text dictionary text must be
a word that's trying to are dictionary
that it's looking through what is the
PHP pass-through function is it
literally just gonna run a command for
us
yes it will totally just execute
commands and display output okay so we
could potentially have remote code
execution here and we can totally get in
the way of it because we're just passing
in raw arguments to this thing so if we
wanted to find words that say like ten
words containing a p-- okay all of these
things in dictionary dot txt Apple
obviously right
what's etc so we can put more in here
like how about a period so grep will use
the regular expressions here and that
will return a period from period will
match everything just like regular
expressions will match any character so
it returned the entire dictionary text
file but since we're supplying this as
an argument that you can see went
through without any like quotes or
surrounding it to specify that that as a
single argument we could bleed into
other arguments here and specify other
files that we want to read or change up
how this command works let's take a look
and let's do that in our shell here or
are our sublime text script needle can
be app to see if we get responses let's
run this we don't want to go to index
source anymore we want to be posting it
to the actual page and we're getting all
of this output so can we return anything
with the period huh okay I must be
getting some strange characters out so
let's go a let's just app huh
maybe some maybe some strange characters
are in this dictionary that Python does
not want to render for us we can change
the encoding here coding equals utf-8
that's the magic magic Python syntax to
suddenly be okay with Unicode characters
will that work for us no okay
man that's super annoying let's do this
with the verb browser then I suppose at
least let's figure out our attack let's
say we can actually return anything and
if we get a space in between this we can
actually ask for another file that we
want to look through I think right let's
go to natus pass and we want natus 10
right search looks like it returns from
the file that things matched in but the
naty's password file should get a result
it should have matched at some point
let's check out what's control f4 natus
9 that is 10 no luck huh
was it in etc is it just gonna display
anything for us that's not dictionary
dot txt it doesn't look like there's any
other notion of natus no so maybe that
didn't work okay well we still have
command execution right can we do period
or like anything from nowhere yep
nothing nothing from nowhere and use a
comment to end the and what we're in and
the rest of the line here so it doesn't
put in that dictionary dot txt for us
but we use the semicolons to note a new
command right ok cool so we've got
command injection just like that so now
we should just be able to cat natus pass
natus 10
is that not the is that not the right
location a little wire what the heck
over the wire log over the wild org what
am i doing
maddis etc natus web pass oh I'm a fool
so the old attack probably would have
worked just fine
Matis web paths natus 10 yeah oh jeez it
totally would have worked just fine
except I'm an idiot
I'm sorry I didn't even realize that
path guys I thought it was the same
syntax as the other war games well hey
okay that's done for us right there's
the attack we can return anything and
let's just get something that we know is
in here actually no we can just say
anything and then we can still use a
comment to not include the not include
the dictionary text file natus web Pass
natus 10 and use the hash tag here so we
won't return the rest of the responses
from the dictionary text file we
commented out the rest of that command
here so now we've got our password
loaded or displayed out to us and let's
use our regular expressions here to
carve it out just like that we get our
password and we are good to go so natus
9 is done we can put this in the script
for natus 10 and just like that we are
ready to move on so I hope you guys hope
that made sense a little bit of command
injection because that that code was
just being passed through two real
command like a bath shell and executing
it and we can just kind of wrap around
the arguments or and do some unique
things with it and we can load content
from other files because that's the way
grep works and we can use other bash
syntax stuff like comments or other
commands with the semicolon to do other
interesting things so cool hack cool
vulnerability there and that's the real
thing command injection
is for sure a real problem in web
security stuff so okay now they filter
on certain certain characters huh let's
get start on that in the next video guys
thank you guys for watching hope you're
enjoying these