right hello everybody welcome back in
the YouTube video my name is John
Hammond and we are back looking at over
the wire the online wargames
and now we're moving into the word game
natus which it's all about web
applications stuff like web security so
I like this honestly this is kind of my
favorite category this is what I'm
really interested in web applications
security because I think that's more
applicable to like real-world bug
bounties and cool things like that so I
really like a lot of these challenges
and they start off pretty pretty not too
bad and then they kind of ramped up to
real cool stuff like blind sequel
injection and cookie stealing etc etc so
I want to show you how to roll through
some of these and I'm gonna do in a
little bit of a different way where I
actually create some get flag scripts or
really just small containerized just
individual standalone files or Python
code that will be able to solve a level
for us or at least retrieve the password
for the next level so let's go ahead and
get started you'll notice here that
passwords are stored in a file inside
the file structure as we're used to in
Leviathan and bandit we just go by the
level name so natus and the level number
that we're on 0 etc and by default it
starts with NAT as zero as the password
just like all the other all the other
war games that we've played so we can
copy and paste this URL in here and
we'll use natus 0 and Ngata 0 to
authenticate and we can view the kind of
file that we're going to be presented
with or the webpage that's returned to
us in our browser right here it says you
can find the pastor for the next level
on this page obviously there's nothing
really in the text here I can use ctrl a
to select everything but there's nothing
there so ctrl you to view the source or
if you really wanted to you can
right-click probably with your web
browser and select a view page source
it'll do the same thing control you is
just a hotkey that I typically use and
see for it and when you see this HTML
comment right here that says the pastor
defer natus one is this string okay so
super easy level 0 was not hard at all
but let's get set up with actually
through this in Python and through a
script so I've got my command line ready
for us again I had this directory over
the wire that has some of the folders
for the other wargames we've been doing
between manda and Leviathan vanilla to
make one dedicated to natus and let's
use sublime text and I'll call this
natus as you wrote I so I'm using
sublime text sublime text - and I'm
using that because I wanted to use the
build View plugin that's gonna let me
split the screen and actually view the
output of my command the output of my
script on a side by side not a vertical
build like sublime normally does so
let's create a shebang line here it's
create a spread for us I'm also using
the dark neon theme if you guys haven't
heard of that you can install it with
the install package command from the
command palette and sublime text control
shift P to bring that up if you don't
have that installed or set up you can
just build up that package with the
package controller if you google that
sublime text package control you have a
package manager you can get to and it
shows you installation and stuff that
you can just easily enter into the
console and either sublime text 3 or
sublime text 2 again I'm using sublime
text 2 here so I can use the package
build view which will build the output
of my script in a separate tab so that
way I can split the window with can
shift alt and to the number of windows
on one hero just too so now I have side
by side the windows and my code and the
build output that I can move back and
forth with and actually do stuff with in
sublime text so that's pretty handy so
I'm gonna go ahead and interact with
these webpages with the requests module
in Python which I don't have a tutorial
series on but I very very much intend to
because it's a better URL Lib and can do
really awesome stuff if you don't have
that installed you should be able to
just do a sudo pip install requests and
if you don't have pip installed you can
we do a sudo apt-get install Python
attack pip and we'll need your pass and
everything just like any sudo command
would so let's import requests let's
import re I'm going to use the regular
expressions module so I can quickly just
grab out the password for the next level
here and let's create a variable for a
username natus is zero in this case the
password is going to be the same since
this is just a unique case but we want
the URL to equal let's get this build
view out of here handy that I can just
kind of slide this to the side whoa
clicking everything all right we can go
ahead and copy and paste the URL here
and let's actually replace the username
in here so now we can use requests dot
get URL and that will return at HTTP GET
that will actually do an HTTP or get
request to access the URL and we'll
store it in a response variable so if we
wanted to see that we can print it out
and we are getting a 401 which if we
view the text of that to see that actual
response here
that's because oh we didn't authenticate
with it we're getting that 401 here
because we didn't supply the username
and password we can do that in the code
here with auth equals and then username
and password off being the function
keyword arguments to the get request and
just using a tuple for our username and
password now when we run this you can
see we've returned the source code of
the web page so what I'm going to do up
here now is just set the syntax to HTML
again I hit ctrl shift P to tell sublime
text that's what I wanted to do and now
we've got the like website source code
just that web page code all the HTML
just like we viewed in our browser a
moment ago but now within sublime text
so we can copy and paste this out if we
want to or we can go ahead and just get
our regular expressions module to parse
through it so I'm going to call this
variable content and then I'm going to
print
content or re dot find all sorry find
all being the regular expression that I
will function that I want to use and I'm
just gonna copy this HTML string here so
I can use kind of a cheap hack to scrape
out only that password part using
regular expressions here using the
parentheses to say I want this item this
element and I'm going to use a period
and to denote any character and I'm
using asterisk to know multiple of these
multiple of these any characters and
little passing content here
I don't want caps lock on cool so now
when I run this let's move our build
output to the side here you can see it
returns an array of everything that it
found and let's use the zero index here
to just scrape that out nice and easy
cool so that's the password for level 1
so we can save this as natus zero but
now we can just go ahead and save
another script call this natus one dot
pi change the user name that we're
working with because we can move over to
the next level here and let's paste in
the password that we have so now our
script will automatically jump to where
we were previously let's print out the
content what's the response we're
getting here and if we see here again
HTML source code the web page source
code and we just pretty much got past
the next level because how do we gone
through this on our own over on the web
browser natus one and Attis 1 paste in
the password here it says you can find
the pass through for the next level on
this page but right clicking has been
blocked it seems okay in my web browser
again maybe maybe it is not in yours
again control you will get you to the
source code and you can see it here but
doing this through Python doing this
through code is still going to get us
the same same result we're just getting
the response of the web page so now we
can just change our our code here have
regular expressions parse out that HTML
comments again change it for natus too
and we can not print the content and we
can just print out what we find
we are getting the flag or the passenger
for the next level right here so now we
can save this as natus to change the
user name to the correct natus to and
comment out this one print the content
that we're seeing again and now we're
into level 3 cool all right so we're set
up we're rollin we've got some Python
code that something has moved through
the natus levels that we would normally
be able to interact with through the web
browser but we can still do that if we
really wanted to but we're getting a
little bit more in the weeds including
some automated tools and scripts that
will do the really cool stuff for us and
learning a little bit of Python and
stuff like that and doing some cool
magic in sublime text
so we'll keep rolling with this in the
next couple videos I hope you guys are
enjoying these hope you guys like the
quality video whatever it is and really
the personality that you got with this
series so thanks again for watching I'll
see you in the next video hopefully tune
in next time