so natus 19 from the over the wire war
game starts out in the prompt and page
telling us that this page uses most of
the same code as the previous level
level 18 but such an IDs are no longer
sequential it gives us the prompt to
please log in with your admin account to
retrieve credentials for the next level
not as 20 and we see this form with the
HTTP POST method to index dot PHP but
there is no link to view the source code
in this level so we're just gonna have
to operate under the assumption that
again this page uses most of the same
code as a previous level so in our
Python code let's actually take a look
at what we have here after we make this
request we can see what our session
cookies are because we're using a
session to request this page we should
be able to determine what the actual
cookies are following this so we can
print out session cookies and let's go
ahead and check out the output right now
it should be nothing because we haven't
actually posted to the form
let's go ahead and do that create a new
response here but instead of running a
get command for HTTP we'll run a post
and the data there had a username and
password field so that will have to be a
Python dictionary or we say username can
be please and password string can be
subscribed okay so let's actually
display the text with it but let's have
the session cookies come with as well
we'll just have a divider there so as I
run this you can see over and over again
if I keep pressing ctrl B to make this
request interesting things are happening
because we can see a cookie that PHP
session ID again previous level level
level 18 not us 18 we were working with
brute-forcing the PHP session ID so in
this case it looks like we have kind of
a random number but not like we used to
it looks like the first couple numbers
are changing three three three etcetera
three two three one etcetera over and
over and over again but the last bit
does not change
so I was curious why that is and it
looked like it was almost dependent on
the username because after some testing
I changed this to like John and we have
a different result for that PHP session
just at the very very end but if we keep
looking at the three leading at the
beginning of the string or these numbers
here those tend to be the same pattern
so I tried to check this out a little
bit more
I changed the username to actually
nothing and still logged in with a
password supposedly but the numbers that
we're seeing I'll shrink this text a
little bit so that won't scroll for us
three five three four three one etc 3 2
3 7 3 0 etc but that 2d at the very very
end tends to stay there the whole time
and I was curious what that really is
cuz this doesn't look like a hash and
since its variable on the username that
couldn't be the case because they're not
gonna have a length of 32 or whatever
hash length maybe a parent there so I
try to check out what are these numbers
and other representations and that 2d
looked odd to me
so I actually determined what some of
these things might be in hex because we
have a D here and the numbers that we've
seen earlier we had a 6 e etc etc it
didn't look like we went to any letter
as higher than F and I thought ok maybe
this is hex so I tried to check that out
and I'll show it here an idol let's
decode that string from hex and we get
five six five and a hyphen here so that
2d must be the hyphen and then the
numbers must be changing let's actually
print out session cookies and let's get
that PHP session ID just like that and
let's decode that from hex
cool great now I wonder if I can do this
a couple more times just to showcase
this so it looks like we're getting a
random number and a hyphen and whatever
we pass for our username is that right
yeah looks like that username is also
hex encoded and the numbers that we seen
before
look to be bounded probably the same way
that were in level 18 they were from 0
to 640 okay
so that kind of fills in the color of
this picture and now we can put together
an attack to try and find what admin
credential or what admin PHP a session
ID there might be the same way we brute
forced it last time we're forcing it
again but now we'll just have to hex
encode that cookie that we know the
original of and try and find the correct
number so let's try that now let's say
for I in range 641 again we've got a
session and we want to see what is the
cookie that we can give it probably just
a get request now because we're gonna
pass in a cookie already prepared with
the PHP session ID already set to our
number
I'll just stringify that with the - it
should be % D for a decimal over digit I
guess and then admin because we want
admin to be the password here and we
want to encode that with hex and don't
forget that we need to actually % in
here inject that I or whatever iterating
on
so let's print this out just to see what
we've got let's print out this whole
thing
and then let's print out what the
response text is let's do this for only
a couple requests so we can see it in
action there's that session ID session
ID again etc etc etc and it says your
login is a regularly a regular user I
was gonna say regular loser again so now
let's try and determine if it says you
are an admin I want to make sure that's
the correct string that we had the same
way it was in the last level it says
yeah you are an admin if you are an
admin is in the response and then we've
got the correct session ID if you are an
admin in response to text we can print
got it with the integer that we're
trying and let's break this and we'll
print response dot text otherwise we
will keep moving some of those we don't
really need one so I'm gonna go do this
in the terminal I just killed my sublime
text but we can Python natus 19 and
we'll start to run through it okay
something strange happened oh no we
actually just forgot to increase that
loop counter so now we want to go to 641
and go all the way to where we could I
should have I should background those
now we'll keep moving and I will pause
the recording right here as this
increments if we wanted to we probably
could have just put the number to
display rather than the PHP session ID
but it looks like we're doing some weed
hack in here so I'll pause recording and
I'll get back to you once we've got the
credentials okay so the script finished
it says got it at 89
let's get sublime text open
I'll background at this time and oh I
put the break before it whatever let's
try and just make this get request with
the 89 as the correct ID number now
let's print response text if I run this
you can see it over on the side here
sessions not defined because I commented
that out now let's keep moving how do we
do
excellent you are an admin the
credentials for the next level are and
that is 20 and the password here so
that's the attack or a quote-unquote
attack but just a little bit of
experimentation and poking around and
trying to figure out what really was
that original PHP session ID but again
very very similar to the previous level
level 18 so let's go ahead and save this
as in that is 20 and we'll start to
examine what's next for us in that level
so thank you guys for watching I hope
you're enjoying this series I hope
you're enjoying these videos if you do
like the video please do leave a like
press that like button maybe leave me a
comment let me know what you think what
else you'd like to see later in a future
tutorial or video if you're willing to
subscribe and if you would like to help
me out support me please head over to my
patreon account and would do whatever
you're comfortable doing so
on that note I want to give a special
shout out to Spencer Clark an individual
that just recently wanted to support me
for patreon I have a reward that I'll
give you a shout-out in every single
video that I do like literally ever so
props to you Spencer thanks for your
help and thanks for your support really
hope to keep making quality content for
you guys