what's up YouTube this is John Hammond
looking again at the natus war game from
over the wire now we're on level 16 so
in the last video we did a little blind
sequel attack and that required a little
bit of a Python loop that we were
working with so I'm going to clean up
some of that code and now we've got just
a basic script where we can get the page
of this level here so so the syntax to
HTML or PHP either one really ok cool so
now we've got that color here we can
read this page for security reasons we
now filter even more on certain
characters and this has the form with
fine words containing and the needle
that we're searching for okay so this
and the output here with the pre
formatted text this looks like the same
kind of grepping through a dictionary
file level that we've seen in in kind of
previous foreign editions here so let's
see what they've done to actually make
this a little bit different let's view
that source code d anta ties this and
looks like the line breaks aren't coming
through so we'll just take all those
HTML break tags and replace them with
newline characters okay so now we've got
the PHP code visible in between these
pre tags here you can see the question
mark and greater than less than symbols
to denote the PHP code so we've got a
key variable originally set to nothing
but we test if we actually send a
request where needle comes through we
use that as the form and we're
determining okay if key isn't set to
nothing if it's actually if it actually
has value we'll do regular expressions
match against it anything in this set it
looks like until the set because of the
opening close of square braces so black
listing the characters of a semicolon
pipe symbol ampersand backtick a single
quote and double quote and if any of
those characters do exist in there all
it does is print input contains legal
character if it passes that check it'll
go ahead and run the command it'll run
the system shell command grep attack I
the key argument against the dictionary
text but this time the levels a little
bit different because the key argument
is passed in double quotes so it is
isolated as its own argument we can't
get around that like we had in some of
the previous levels but it's still
running a shell command
it's a learning system command so let's
see if we can find some technique
that'll let us take advantage of this
vulnerability here I'm noticing we can't
get around it with double quotes or the
single quotes the backticks kind of ruin
our luck for command substitution but
not entirely some of you that may have
seen some of my other videos from the
leviathan videos and over the wire
I've tried originally trying to do some
command substitution with backticks and
then I was informed that hey that's a
deprecated and stupid way to do it oh I
posted that to the source code let's
that go back to the original page and
okay with the backticks obviously we do
not pass that black list so we got to
figure out something else we can do
command substitution with the different
style syntax with the dollar sign and
the parentheses now we can run commands
like LS or who am i or view the password
etc the issue is since this is command
substitution we don't actually get any
output well I guess we get output but
it's going to be replaced in line of
that command that grep command so it's
trying to grep for the result of Who am
I here not a 16 in the dictionary dot
txt file obviously there aren't any
lines that match natus 16 so we're not
getting out any output that's curious
right because we don't get the output of
the command but we can determine whether
or not something is visible or present
in a dictionary a text file doesn't help
us like kind of at the surface level but
thinking off the heels of that last
video where we did a blind sequel
injection we figured out the existence
of the user or whether or not a user
doesn't exist to leak out a password to
leak out data so in this level we can
figure out whether or not something
exists in the dictionary dot text file
or if it doesn't and we have the
potential to get the password in our
query
because we could just you know cat etc
like natus web past not a 17 and if we
were run this obviously we're not going
to get any output from the dictionary
text file because it can't find that
string in the dictionary text file so
what if we would only get a part of the
password out what if we were to just
grep for like the letter A in the
password well whether or not that got a
result we don't know okay we got
something here let's do this in the
console so we can get the results okay
it looked like it didn't return any
string because we greps an empty string
and everything returned for us so let's
try something like B does B exist in the
password okay so because B does exist in
the password that grep command that we
saw in the PHP code is filled in with
the actual password now 217 password as
an argument and it obviously can't find
that in dictionary text so we don't see
any output here now let's do something
clever because let's put in something
some data like default data that we
would expect to get a return get a
response from dictionary tech like the
word anything right looks like we get
anything and any things let's change our
script to any things so we have easy one
result if if it matches so any things is
in there but now we can run a test just
like we've been doing before with our
command substitution grep for a and it's
that and that is a web pass not at 17
that we saw earlier that it doesn't have
the letter A in the natus 17 password so
any things will remain the only argument
we passed to it but if we grip for B
where B is present in now 217 now we're
going to be searching for any things and
then blah blah blah blah blah whatever
the password may be and that's not
present in dictionary text obviously so
now we've got that trigger a yes or no
kind of dichotomy that'll help us figure
out is this character in the password or
not but we need to leak out everything
in the past or me to leak out character
by character so how are we gonna do that
well we can still use that grep magic to
our advantage
cuz let's say grips using regular
expressions so if we use a special
regular expression character like the
caret that means the start of the string
or the very very first character
following this so if B is the first
character we will not get any results
from our output but because we do get
results anything's come through okay B
is not the first character that's what
we can decipher from that but we know B
was in there so we know our commands are
going through now we just have to figure
out which of these is the first
character now we have to loop through
all those characters just like we've
been doing in the previous video so
let's get set up with all of those
printable characters we had characters
equal to lowercase and uppercase and
digits because we know that that is what
makes up the password here for over the
wire levels let's set up a while loop
and now we know the condition that we
can use because this password that we're
using is going to be 32 characters and
length so let's get a scene password
variable and we'll use as a list and
while the length of scene password is
less than 32 we can keep looping and
we'll do for each character and all the
possible characters let's try and figure
out what the response might be and let's
add in what we've seen of the password
join together because it's a list so we
want that to be a string and the current
character we're looking at great so now
let's test what is actually being
returned to us let's try our e dot find
all get the pre tags there's a new line
following it and don't start anything a
new line end pre
let's see now
well let's we want content here so let's
print out that and let's see if we get
results
anything's anything's anything's
anything anything anything etc etc etc
but one of these should return nothing
for us at some point right
I should have noted the character that
we're on oh okay we see the trigger we
see the hit right there
so whatever that was well it's not a
thing so we can tech we can check if
returned can check let's say a variable
name return
so if returned so if that list actually
has content then print this is not the
first character and we'll just print out
the character from that and if it didn't
get anything returned then we know this
this is the first character sure and
then let's just try that to see how it
looks
looping through every single character
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah this is going
to take a little bit of time obviously
because we're brute-forcing but that's
the methodology we're gonna go for blind
leaking and we get a hit at eight okay
so now we can use the same functionality
we had before if not returned when we
get a success what we can do is we can
add that character to the scene password
so it will become part of what we're
looping through and then let's break out
of this original for loop so we start
again going to the alphabet and if we do
get it let's print out join of scene
password so now very very slowly let's
print out what we're trying yeah that's
actually just print out what we send it
and we don't need this one down here now
we can see it trying to leak this out
and because we're using that grep
regular expressions the carrot to denote
the start of the password will be able
to say okay that number eight is the
first character and we'll loop through
more and more and more until we get the
next character in the password and then
the next character because it's still
adding on to that list that we're seeing
and combining it as a string so this is
gonna take a little bit of time but at
the very end we're gonna have the natus
level 17 password just leaked out using
that nifty trick of the command
substitution with grep regular
expression caret and determining whether
or not we actually get a result out of
the dictionary text file let's let this
run all right looks like the script
finished looks like we have a password
and now let's try it for natus level 17
response text save this as not a 17 out
of 17 paste see if we get a result and
we do we are out that is level 17
awesome okay that's it that's all the
technique we needed to do thank you guys
so much for watching hope you're
enjoying these if you do like the video
please do that like the video maybe
leave me a comment I mean let me know
what you think what I can do better what
else would like to see if you're willing
to subscribe and if you thanks again
guys
I'll see you in the later video