hello everyone my name is John Hammond
and welcome back to some more natus over
the wire web application security some
Python scripting and programming to hack
some websites free cool stuff I've been
away from this for a while because this
challenge level 28 is a little difficult
and kind of hard so this is going to be
a long video please do bear with me I
hope it's pretty cool though I hope you
learn a few things so let's dive right
in I have the web page visible right
here because I want to showcase the
functionality of this application before
I start to look at it in code so we have
this computer joke database where we
could search for a query and it will
supposedly return information back out
to us normally we were able to view the
source code of some of these
applications just so we can learn and
understand a little bit more going
through the wargames here but
unfortunately this level does not
provide the source code so if I don't
enter anything into the search it will
go ahead and return some results for us
in fact it gives us just a couple here
no shortcuts in life let's right click
on find one blah blah blah it gives us
like computer jokes if we were to put in
stuff like anything or please sub it
would return queries that have that
string in it and unfortunately nothing
has please sub in it that's weird if I
tried to search for the letter A
obviously it'll get a couple more
results if we wanted to just go for
sequel injection we particularly could
but obviously that's not going to return
anything because that text is not in
that query or whatever it's trying to
run in the database however if I just
went for like a single quote or a double
quote or just a quote it will be able to
return things that have this in here so
that lets me interpret that okay it's
probably escaping these single quotes
and double quotes it's not just gotta
make the database crap out on us so what
I'm sure you're noticing is when we
actually look at some of these returns
all these things that actually return
out to us that give us some information
we are getting a interesting change in
the URL it throws us to search PHP it
gives us this query variable that that
is the HTTP variable that we're working
with and it looks like a bunch of
garbage a lot of encoded data a lot of
this URL encoding it is likely for
trying to hide some special characters
and that looks like it may turn out to
be base64 when we actually take a look
at it so let's go ahead and do that
let's get to our Python script where we
have the code over on the left here and
then the output of the the return and
what the webpage gives us on the
right-hand side so I just made a simple
get request to do that let's actually
set this to and set this to HTML for
syntax highlighting that looks neat okay
good and let's go ahead and try and make
a request now where we actually submit a
query so we're gonna end up posting to
that URL with data going through here
I'll put this on a new line so it looks
a little bit nicer let's say query can
equal just the letter A and then that
should be everything we need right I'm
hoping well we get anything yep okay
cool we get some responses and now we
want to be able to look at the URL so we
can do this we can't actually just check
out response dot URL and at the very
very top here you see okay it gives us
the entire URL and this front part the
whole actual web address and the search
dot PHP query that's all going to be a
static length so if I wanted to scrape
out the very very end here we can
probably just take how long how many
characters is this you can see at the
bottom left 60 60 character selected so
let's go sixty characters from the end
and we'll just get okay that portion
that is the encoded information oh I put
that on text not the URL okay cool
so now let's go ahead and encode this we
probably won't need you a relative
I'll do this through the requests I just
actually learned this the requests
actually has a utils like sub module
that allows you to quote or unquote I
think it's unquote
let me check I'm hoping fingers frost
yeah okay cool
now that is certainly base64 and if we
wanted to with that base 64 module
included we could base 64 dot be 64
decode and we'll get some
raw bytes out of this that sublime text
won't be able to show for us so let's
actually check out the representation or
our EPR to display those raw bytes and
okay looks like we're getting a lot of
interesting things there
so as I'm exploring this actually before
I go ahead and show the representation I
want to look at some experiments when we
test with the okay we'll just pay 6040
code let's again not do that just yet I
want to save these lines though because
we will probably keep track of them
pretty soon I would just want to see
that base64 string for a few of these
and I want to gather these I want to be
able to see are there any interesting
changes when I change my query so just a
less random inputs I'll steal a few more
of these and put them down here so I can
examine them say just what and get a few
more okay so if you check out this text
here you should notice that the first
portion of this encrypted or encoded or
whatever this data is is actually
staying the same for the first part
right here it looks like it'll get up to
42 characters in and the base64 encoded
values to give us constant and the same
values however everything that follows
looks like it will change so that leads
me to think of the conclusion that we
are having some static text or some non
changing just regular text or data
that's being a pro pendant or put at the
very very start of our input or what
goes through and then that's being
encrypted and then eventually encoded
and it seems that that's it's it's not
particularly changing the segments that
are being displayed here are being
encrypted kind of piece by piece or
chunk by chunk or block by block and
that's telling us that okay they're
being encrypted the exact same way that
points me in direction the direction did
I say and I say in other words I may
have said in other words okay I didn't
want the England cricket team that's not
what I wanted I wanted ECB encryption
this is
block cipher that is electronic codebook
[Music]
electronic codebook ECB it is a form of
encryption where the message is divided
into blocks and each block is encrypted
separately but going through the exact
same operation kind of using the same
key it's it's not chaining these blocks
or these chunks together so you'll be
able to see a residual you'll be able to
determine portions of the encryption
scheme as you tinker with and as you
play with it you'll see some examples so
you're on this Wikipedia page the image
of tux to Linux mascot when it's
encrypted use an ECB you're still able
to kind of make out what that image
actually is so we can probably do
something interesting here but let's
keep in mind that it is using this ECB
electronic codebook block cipher to
encrypt our input so the next kind of
point of attack is to determine the
block size or how big or what are the
what what's the dimensions of these
chunks or these blocks that our message
is being cut up into so let's take a
look let's see how we can figure that
out what I want to do first is actually
determine let's see here what query will
we have oh I just deleted those things
that I told myself I wanted classic
let's try and see what the length of the
actually decoded or like if the raw data
is after we send it different and
varying lengths of information so let's
do for I in range and let's go about a
like how many characters that we want to
go for well how about how long is this
to begin with how long is our decoded
one to begin with before we actually
check out the I put an extra string
there okay it is 80 characters long so
what could we potentially be working
with here let's go for I in range 30
maybe 30 characters long
180 I don't know let's try it let's just
go response equals all this let's
determine the length we don't have to
view it out let's just view the length I
or query length and then response length
will be just like that
so let's now change this query to like
the letter A multiplied by I so let's
try and run this see how long it takes
for us I forgot a comma here okay so
query length 0 response to length 80
this will keep returning and returning
and returning for us until okay we see
something change here we've got a
difference in the response length being
80 and the response length now going to
96 so that's changing the encryption
that it's actually outputting here for
us it looks like we're getting more of
these changes as we change our query
length just as we would expect
we're gonna hit 100 pretty soon let's
admit on this a little bit and okay okay
we went to 80 sweet so this starts at 80
and goes until a ends here and that
takes about or is it 13 lines yep but we
got 96 over here this length of the
response is only 96 for 16 lines and
then as we check out 112 we have 112
again 16 times you can see it at the
very bottom I've selected 16 lines same
thing for 128 if we check that out we
have 16 lines so what we can assume and
understand here is that this very very
first block that we're looking at is
obviously taken up by some of the
original data or the original string or
text that is being prepend Adhan or
putting in at the very start of our
input so that can't be that trustworthy
but maybe these other 16 length blocks
we certain
I can trust so that's how we can
determine the block size okay so now
let's try and figure out where our data
actually is or kind of how much room or
what buffer do we have to work with
within these blocks so let's check out
let's say our block size can equal 16
now that we've kind of figured that out
now we can determine what blocks we want
to actually check out let's do another
for loop for each of these let's do a
print just to get a nice visualizer
let's get about 50 characters of a line
there and let's do for block in range
how many blocks we want to check out
well the original thing was 80 and we
want to go to we don't want to go to MIT
we don't want to make any requests
anymore we saw that change happen about
with character length of 16 a query
length of 16 so let's change that to
against 16 or 15 or whatever you want
I'm not I'm not choosing 16 because it's
a block size I'm choosing it because
that's where we saw a change in the
response length and it gives us a couple
in and out so we can explore some of
those now
let's check out the actual blocks of the
data that we're seeing in the response
let's check out about how about 5 or
let's say 80 the original length was 80
and then we divide that by the block
size so let's check out the response
that we're getting just like we've seen
before except now we don't want the
length we want the original thing
decoded from locks the current block
that we're looking at times block size
so this will originally start at 0 and
then up until block plus 1 times block
size so that'll go 16 bytes at a time 16
first block and then 16 to 32 the second
block and then 32 to 48 the third block
etc so if we wanted to check that out
let's wrap her to get the raw
representation again and let's print out
block block data just like that
and we still want to have our query
length visible up at the top here so now
let's check out what this does response
what's not what's going wrong here oh I
would actually need that after thee
after I go ahead and query the site
okay so query length 0 response length
80 and this is happening over and over
again until we get to about 16 requests
15 requests just fine so you can see
again I'm looking at the raw
representation of the bytes your
elaborate representation of the data so
it's not basic ste 4 encoded just
separate into different chunks those
different blocks so the first block or I
guess block 0 and we can actually change
this to block +1 so it makes a little
bit more sense or has a hat as to how we
are reading it okay check this out so
blocks 1 & 2 seem to be the same for
every query length that we send it so
that tells us that that must be the
amount that is filled up by the original
prepended text that's at the very very
that's the static text that we don't
have control over it's just being added
in at the very start of our input and
that's what's it's encrypting you can
see that that doesn't change blocks 1 &
2 don't change
however block 3 is changing with our
input so where do we find a threshold
where we fill up one block we fill up
block 3 and then we start to move into
what would be blocked for because
apparently there's data being added
after our input so we could potentially
figure out what that is
because it's ECB because it's a lot
electronic codebook cipher so I see in
query length 10 in query length 11 block
3 actually stays the same value so it
looks like that same way onward from 12
13 etcetera etcetera so that means the
threshold for filling all
of block three that where that location
in the message where we are where our
input is going we have filled the block
between ten and nine so nine means that
there is just one more character that
wood has eventually fill the block
because once it has it hits ten and
eleven it's gonna stay the same over and
over and that means we fill the block
with our RA letters so if we have one
last character available in the block if
we send it a query of length nine we
could potentially figure out what that
data is following our input because it's
being encrypted if we actually figured
out okay what is this block what does
that block look like if we fill it with
one more character and we could keep
iterating through that character to try
and determine what character is it in
the real data that they're appending
that we don't know yet we could probably
leak it out so that may seem weird that
may sound weird let's let's do it let me
show you how we how we can make this
happen let's go ahead and say the
correct string is just this
representation again we'll put that in
repper
so that is what they would is we would
assume from that and we could import
string have all of the potential
characters here there's principal
characters for C in string dot printable
then we'll make a request where we say a
nine times because we know that that is
we're gonna have one last character to
fill this block and we'll put in the
character that we're looking at so then
we can go ahead and get what block we're
looking at block three in this case
we'll take that original line that we
had and just set block to two because it
is zero based when we know we're looking
at block three but since it counts 0 1 2
that will be the third block our answer
will be this again with the third block
that we're looking at
so we can test if answer is equal to the
correct string then we know we found the
character that would be following that
that that input that we supply so let's
include that see right there we can
print trying see and let's run this
trying 0 1 2 3 4 etc etc and this will
loop through the characters here I hope
this makes sense I'm gonna try and
visualize it here with some block stuff
I'll try and make these blocks just like
this so if we were filling up our blocks
up until the last segment here so 1st
and 2nd blocks are filled and then the
third block we know we just okay cool it
found it % here hopefully that will
close in we are filling up until we just
leak into whatever the 4th mole 4th
block may end up being so 1 2 3 we fill
the third block up until the character
that would eventually be starting the
next block starting the fourth block so
since the original data is at the very
very end here following our input we can
supply everything up to that last block
and since it will be encrypted one way
or the other we can keep checking to see
what is that character going to be is it
going to equal what it would have been
had it been actually encrypted following
that that's very very hard to discuss
and I'm sorry if I suck at explaining
that hopefully you see it visually ok so
since we are since we found the
character % we have an interesting hunch
here now because knowing the application
and knowing the functionality of what
this program does it's probably running
a query something like select text from
jokes where the text is
like and this is sequel right here where
it's using that % as a wild-card where
text is like our input with the %
following because that's the wild-card
it'll match anything that has that
notion in it so this is doing an
interesting thing because normally using
this technique now that we found that
character we could potentially shrink
our test block and just add the
character that we found at the very very
end so it will encrypt and decrypt the
same way we would expect it because now
that we figured out what character was
next we can try that attack again
shrinking down our padding or our space
that we're filling in and so we can leak
out more of the message that follows or
the text that follows our input but this
is kind of an issue in this case right
here because we actually are probably
wrapped inside of a string we at least
in the sequel code that's probably
running in the back we wouldn't be able
to actually test this because our input
is again as we saw from our testing in
the beginning being escaped like we we
tried to enter a quote or a single quote
but we know that that's probably not
being processed as real sequel commands
so they're gonna be escaped with a
backslash so unfortunately since that
will take up more than one character and
that's going to leak over into the
fourth block and we won't be able to
test it we won't be able to track it
down since we are testing in just the
very very edge of the third block okay
but now we have a hunch now we know that
maybe this is running a sequel injection
maybe this has some opportunity for
sequel injection except we can't use
those single quotes or double quotes
just as I was saying because they're
going to be escaped we can't just do
that sequel like Union selects whatever
we want blah blah blah password from
users we can't do that just in the
search query because it will be escaped
out of it so now we have to take
advantage of what we know with this
electronic code book with this
encryption scheme we could potentially
try and figure out what what what could
we enter what encrypted information
could we get that would actually look
like we had entered that information
since we can encrypt the same way but if
we handle that escape sequence properly
because we know that we're gonna end up
having it eventually following let's
actually keep that that query here if we
got this single quote to be included in
the third block and not no longer really
necessary for the fourth block that way
we could be home free where we could do
our own injection following it so now we
just have to figure out how we can
encrypt and get the data forward that
input this probably sounds weird again
I'm gonna show it to you let's write
this code here let's say our injection
is a space character or the letter A
whatever padding we want to use times
nine so we fill up the third block
because that's that's our buffer here
and I'm only going to use nine
characters so just as we saw that select
text from jokes where thing like blah
blah blah that single quote at the very
very end will actually go ahead and be
interpreted just fine we won't have an
escape going through we'll actually just
have that single quote at the very very
end rather than the % so nine will be
that threshold if I use that injection
and then I add on our single quote Union
select let's just do password from users
because that's kind of what we've seen
in the previous levels and we'll just do
a comment here to note the very end of
the sequel injection for the sequel
query now we have that string that we
want to figure out how we can encrypt
how we could actually get that to be
something that the backend application
will handle so let's do that let's
determine first of all how many blocks
is this going to take the way that we
can do that is we can just say locks
equals lengths of injection and we got a
minus the ten here because we have
is padding the A's or the spaces that
we're filling it up with and the single
quote let's do minus ten and then let's
divide that by the block size now that
will get only up until we have a
remainder so we have to say if we have a
remainder we're gonna need another block
the way that we can do that is we can
just test if length of injection minus
ten modulus block size is not equal zero
so if it's not a it's not a straight
factor if we do have a remainder then we
can just say blocks plus equals one so
we add a an extra block in there let's
see how much how much this is going to
take up it's gonna take up three blocks
okay that's fine now what we can do is
we'll go ahead and encrypt this the way
we can do that is by checking this
response and getting the URL just as
we've done before and said rather the
query we're working with will say our
injection and then let's check out the
block that's returned for us the full
thing we don't need the representation
we just want the raw bytes and we don't
need it cut at any specific block we
don't want the full thing do I have a
number of parentheses there okay cool
we're good so let's just say raw inject
and if you wanted to see this you could
if we want to check out the
representation you could that's just
fine so that is going to be the
encrypted scheme that has our injection
in now how are we going to be able to
properly put this into a request without
actually making the request and having
the program encrypt it we have to
encrypt it for the program let's trick
it let's try and give it original good
data like the spaces that we use to earn
the a characters that we use to fill the
third block then let's get the very very
end like after we have actually filled
the third block just so we know the very
data at the at the very end of the
original query and then fake it with
that first part of the the safe good
string
and then let's put our injection in
between it so that probably sounds
strange but again I'll show you in code
so let's get a response with just the a
character or our padding ten times to
fill the third block let's get that like
good base and let's actually say that
our query will be or the URL that we're
end up going to the query that we're
gonna be using is good base up tool the
third block size so the third block
block size times three so we know that
that's the third block that we want now
that we filled it we can go ahead and
add our injection in there
so injection will get the third block
size filled and let's take block size
plus three plus blocks because that is
the amount of blocks that are necessary
for our injection times the block size
so that's a full value here now we
should be able to add on the very very
end that we had from our good base again
taking from three blocks in to the very
end so it's it's faking the query it
essentially just puts our injection in
it encrypts it the way that it would
have expected it again making sure the
blocks are all in a line I've set up
blocks I've said that a lot throughout
this whole thing so let's check out our
query right now probably something that
we can't see that's fine
let's go ahead and basic c4n code it
hmm oh I'm sorry I made a mistake here
let's go from zero to the third block at
the start and then other way around so
from 48 in or the third block in that's
my bad now we have a proper looking
injection string okay now we want to go
ahead and quote this so it is properly
URL encoded and this was a sticking
point for me it looks like that function
does not actually URL encode forward
slashes and that made all the difference
when I actually tried this challenge so
we're gonna have to go ahead and replace
those let's change those forward slashes
should be % 2f in hex so that does make
all the difference in this challenge we
will need to make sure those four
slashes are URL encoded this has to be
fully URL encoded for it to work ok so
this can be our query now and let's keep
in mind that when we actually retrieve
this data it was in the form of the URL
with search dot PHP at the end it
brought us to search PHP as a page and
then it had query as the actual HTTP
variable that we're working with so now
that we've constructed that variable on
our own let's go ahead and add that in
so we don't post a request we just get a
request with argument query now if I run
this display out the text we're getting
from that response nothing so something
is wrong
let's explore I think I see the first
problem and that I was using just the
string injection as the blocks that I
was trying to reach out rather than just
raw inject so now let's try and run this
okay all right that was it
sweet so that is the password that's the
flag that we're looking for
but I hope this made sense I hope this I
know this is a crazy long video but I
hope you were able to visualize
everything that I was doing because
electronic codebook cipher is very very
strange and the way that it encrypts
block by block and each block is just a
segment of the original message but we
can detect it we can determine what it
actually is so let's get re and scrape
out this flag here
I think it's re dot find all your raw
string from Li something in there
anything to endo I with our response dot
txt zero and we don't need a number of
blocks to be displayed anymore that's
just fine okay there is the flag just
like that so that is natus level 28 I
hope that you guys enjoyed it kind of a
long process doing some peculiar
interesting things I hope it was easy to
see the code was easy easy to understand
we're doing some interesting things but
I was honestly just very amazed and
impressed and pleased with this I
thought it was very cool and honestly a
really big learning experience for me I
will have to jot down this process is
like the the procedure that I went
through here to actually okay determine
the block size and then determining
where the block actually has our input
going in and then determining how we
could take advantage of the fact that
that escape sequence or that that string
delimiter the double quote or single
quote would actually be handy for us
when we're trying to do our sequel
injection so very very cool very very
interesting hope you guys enjoy this hey
shout out to the people that support me
on patreon thank you guys so much you're
fantastic I love you I don't know why no
pixel has an O in front of the same
you're the best man
$1 a month on patreon I'll give you a
special shout I just like this have a
never video five dollars or more in
patreon will give you early access to
everything there at least on YouTube
before it goes live if you want the
content where I want to Todd wrote it's
work ready that's the best way to do
that please do join our discord server
link in the description is an awesome
community flow
CTF players programmers and hackers you
can hang out with me and other cool
people we'll be tackling I CTF Knox CTF
and other competitions that are coming
up this week hey I have a link the
description for a Humble Bundle book
package that will really help me out its
affiliate link full disclaimer I'm a
sellout I'm sorry I suck but it helps me
put food on the table and you guys and
your support really just enables that
for me so thank you thank you
would love to see you on patreon please
do like this video comment this video
subscribe if you're into that stuff I
don't know I love to see you on patreon
love to see in the next video
get out of here man