natus level 22 starts out with
practically nothing on the webpage so
the first thing to do is just go ahead
and take a look at the source code see
if they actually are trying to hide
anything here so I'll paste that URL
into our Python script and we'll go
ahead and download the page gonna need
the anti ties this all again that's okay
remove any break statements or anything
else that we have in there that's
getting in the way but it looks like at
the very start of the webpage there's
some PHP code here it starts with the
new session and then determines if Narae
key exists if there's a get parameter
reveal EO reveille oh I don't know I
would assume this is reveal EO since
they're trying to reveal the password
and the comment here is only admins can
reveal the password so this is
interesting because it's testing if the
session admin key exists and if it's set
to one but only if it's not set to one
it'll do something it will redirect you
or it'll set a header location like an
HTTP header to move you back to another
page like the root directory or the the
root page of the website here so that's
peculiar because it only does it if you
are not admin but the only PHP code in
the page here is testing whether or not
you're passing the review the reveal EO
tag in they HTTP GET variable it doesn't
worry about the session admin here so is
there a way we can ignore being moved or
following a redirect if we just supply
this get parameter but we don't know
this admin session or we because it
doesn't look like there's any way to
actually set this there's no
vulnerability to kind of get in the way
or inject this admin credential in our
in our session so let's try just trying
to run with this reveal EO HTTP GET
variable and it looks like it will just
bring us to the page yeah so no no admin
credentials there because it redirected
us right because we weren't such an
admin so it kicked us back is there a
way we can ignore that header absolutely
so you can totally do this in burp if
you wanted to because burp will see the
original request return the output to
you and then move you along with the
redirect if you want it to but since
we're doing this in Python with request
that module is gonna follow to redirect
but by default you can turn that off
allow redirects that's another keyword
argument for get requests you can just
say false and that will load only that
page the one that you requested so now
if I go check this out hey you're an
admin even though we haven't modified
that session admin variable that PHP
global in session we are still able to
get through it because of the code of
the website we're not being redirected
just telling us
no I browser I don't want you to do that
stay where you are create up so for the
next level we've got the password and we
can move on so create a new script here
I'll call this nat is 23 paste a
password in and we will keep moving we
don't need to do this a lot of redirects
anymore but that's something good to
know maybe you do want to use that allow
redirects keyword argument more often
some your Python scripts if you're doing
some of this web hack and CTF style
stuff so thank you guys for watching
hope you're enjoying these if you are
please do like the video maybe leave me
a comment let me know what you think
what else you'd like to see well how you
solve this and what I can do better if
you're willing to subscribe and if you
really want to support me please check
me out on patreon a shout out to the
people that already support me on
patreon Spencer Clark thank you so much
for your support you're helping this
channel grow and develop and helping me
out for sure I do know to reward if you
support me whatsoever through patreon
I'll give you a shout out and include
this stuff at the end of the video and
if if $5 or more I'll let you see some
YouTube videos in advance before I get
them uploaded or scheduled so thanks for
watching see you soon