what's up everybody welcome back to the
YouTube video my name is John Hammond
and this video we're looking at level 17
of the natus war game from over the wire
so on the tails of level 16 we just got
the password for level 17 so let's run
the script to check out what this
webpage is and what we're actually
working with here here we have the form
that we've seen before
just for logging in it looks like we're
given a user name input field and the
button will check existence so kind of
the same sequel injection attack we've
seen before but maybe there's something
different so let's actually take a look
at the source code and let's see what
they're doing here just copy that link
to the index source and again we'll have
to Deanna ties this and we can remove
all those brake tags because we don't
need those alright so we have the same
schema as we've seen before just a
user's table with user name and password
have the same test if we are actually
posted to the page in the PHP code and
we run the same query looks like we have
the same sequel injection attack vector
because they're just concatenating in
the user name but it's commented out the
output as to whether or not it got a
result so no longer can we determine
okay yes or no
binary dichotomy thing does this user
exist as this user not exists so we
can't use that for our typical blind
sequel attack we won't be able to
determine via that yes or no 1 or 0 do
we have the correct character and what
we're trying to leak out so we have to
go for a different attack and this will
be pretty neat this is one I think one
of the coolest things you can do with
what sequel but let's go ahead and start
to post to this web page and see what we
can do we want to change our method to
post same URL data will be username
that's the variable that we've got to
work with in HTTP and we'll say
subscribe post run this no outputs just
like it told us but we know we have our
sequel injection so if I were to change
these two single quotes and the original
quote the double quote they're using in
that sequel statement we can or one
equals one and throw a comment in there
run this and looks like we're getting no
real output but we can do some other
interesting things we can actually
because we have that sequel injection we
can run sequel commands and sequel
functions and do sequel things let's
actually try and sleep for a certain
amount of time so this function will do
exactly as it says it will wait or sleep
a certain amount of seconds that we pass
in here as a number and it will actually
operate because we're using that and
function so if something returns and we
get this sleep function which will
return one what if it succeeds or it'll
it'll return successful but the and will
mean it will execute if the user that
we're checking for according to the
application code exists so let's try
this if I hit control B to run it it
returns immediately because obviously
the user subscribed does not exist but
if I change this to you and add at 7:18
notice 18 is the next password that we
want if I hit the Go button here the
build output there's no response for at
least five seconds because we've ended
that sleep function so this gives us the
building blocks for a timing attack for
time-based sequel injection cuz we can
actually leak out the password right we
can say where password we actually don't
want to use the where Clause because
it's already being used for that where
user name so we can just say an password
is like and use the same methodology
that we've been using before so add in
what we've seen of a scene password join
of scene password because we'll keep
track of that in a list and a character
that we iterate through don't forget our
% here so we get the wild-card and well
let's change the sleep to two
so let's get that character pool we want
to work with so let's say characters can
equal let's get everything from the
string module so we can use lowercase
uppercase and digits as we've seen
before
sorry for this duplicate code here guys
but now we'll do a while loop or
actually we'll do a scene password again
to determine the length length of scene
password is less than 32 because we know
that was the length or it will say for
character and characters try and get
this response here and let's actually
just print trying and let's get what
we're looking for we don't need the plus
there we don't have to print that out
but I'm gonna do this in the command
line let's change that preference so it
looks let's run that Python not a 17
script and I forgot my colon my bad okay
so now we're gonna start to iterate
trying all these characters but X we
hang a little bit and we got a test if
we actually got a hit if it slept for
two seconds or if there is a real
difference in the time between one
execution and the next then we know
we've got the correct character because
that and a password like successfully
executed and then sleep will
successfully execute so let's change
this and let's start to get a time to
determine how long this code takes to
run let's import time now let's actually
do from time import all so we can just
use the time function real easy so for
every character we're looking at well
we're gonna try and send it and then
we'll determine what the time currently
is start time we can just do that for
debugging purposes
and then we can say and time can be a
new time after we've already made that
request and let's say the difference can
equal n time - start time so we can get
an idea of how long that took difference
now we can print these things out and
while we're watching it difference is
maybe twenty tenth of a second but I'll
scroll up here once we got to X we could
tell the difference took more than a
second because we slept for that second
there you might have different values on
this depending on how your internet
connection is because we're literally
timing how long this request takes and
that sleep function whatever integer
amount of seconds you pass into the
sleep function in sequel obviously that
will vary so if I were to run this with
two you'll see a different difference
because now you're sleeping for two
seconds but it seems you're gonna
automate this and weaponize it to
actually leak out the password you want
to do something that will give you
relatively quick speed but still let you
be able to determine what is the
threshold for this actually being a
successful hit so we can say if the
difference is greater than one then we
know we actually have a successful hit
that's the correct character that we've
seen in that position of the password so
let's add that to our seen password and
break out of this for loop so we can
keep moving seeing password dot append
character we're looking at in a loop and
then let's break cool we don't need this
start time notice anymore now let's
start to loop what did I do wrong
I think that was happening because
nothing was buffering this output here
now let's try this if we actually have
that print statement will tell us the
trying and it will determine that X is
the correct password okay cool so now we
have an attack
looks like we're leaking out the
password but we forgot the binary notion
in the past we're here so we may be
missing capital letters let's make sure
we include and binary password like so
we get case sensitivity when we leak out
that field in the database now we can
let the script run and by the end of it
we'll have the password for natus 18 all
right I'll let this run and I'll see you
in a little bit so it looks like the
script did finish and we have a
potential password let's head back to
the original script and save it as a new
one natus 18 paste the password in here
change the username and let's see if we
can just get that page see if we got the
correct password and we're ready to move
on let's control B run this and here we
are
NAT is level 18 sweet so we did it that
was the successful loop and pretty much
a good Python attack for actually
implementing a timing based sequel
injection exploit if you want to call it
that and I think that's super cool
sequel map does some stuff with that if
you haven't seen that tool totally check
it out but I like to consider that
methodology pretty good for a timing
attack and you'll see those in a lot of
capture-the-flag competitions and when
you don't have explicit sequel injection
and you can't get a results easily to
determine your blind sequel injection
you can still leak out pieces of the
database just by taking a little bit of
time using a loop like this and you can
just run with a while true if you don't
have this criteria about what you're
leaking out about its length or whatever
you can just run forever and
once your loop starts to act weird and
gives you like random bites you know
okay I pretty much reached the end so
that's it that's how we can do a timing
attack and time-based sequel injection
and Python and some web hacking thank
you guys so much for watching if you do
like the video please click that like
button please let me know what else
you're thinking of what else you'd like
to see what else I could do better with
in a comment if you're willing to
subscribe any thank you so much see you
another video