that is level 24 showcases another
example of basic PHP type juggling and
this is probably the most common one
that I've seen Bradley ever in the
capture-the-flag scene so this is and
again this function itself is what
you're gonna see is an immediate
telltale as to how you can get around
this so the PHP code that's testing the
source code and lattice noble 24 there's
the same password form entry and in text
input as we've seen the previous level
and they're testing okay again if you've
submitted this form if the array key
exists in the request what it does is it
tests does the password match something
or whatever that whatever it may be and
this is going to be whoever knows the
the flag or the password and again in
this case the way it's censored because
we'll know we don't want to know where
the game doesn't want us to know what
the password is
but that's our objective to find out so
string compare is an interesting PHP
function because it returns a zero if
it's an identical string it returns
whether or not they are identical in the
way that it does that it's determining
whether or not there are differences so
returns less than 0 if string 1 is less
than string 2 greater than string 1 if
it's greater than and 0 if they are
equal so the way that some people test
ok these things are are identical is by
nodding or using the exclamation point
here to say if these things not return 0
as in this condition evaluates to true
then these passwords are the same this
input is the same as maybe the flag or
whatever you're trying to get out here
so this is an interesting example of the
password type juggling though or the pH
P type juggling because because we have
control over this as a request variable
as something that we pass through HTTP
what's to say we don't make this a
string anymore
what's to say we make that an array so
let's go over to the code and I'll show
you how this is done if I go ahead and
request this page simply with the get
request we have okay there's the view
source now let's go ahead and make a
post request let's just post this data
can be the pass
word and we'll set it to anything here
because we don't know what it's supposed
to be we'll call it like please sub and
that will return wrong in this case I
forgot the comma okay I do this way too
often sorry guys we will know okay
that's going to be interpreted as a
string it we don't know what it actually
need to equal so it's going to return
wrong but because we're passing this in
as an HTTP POST variable and we're
passing it in raw we're able to modify
it and let's say the password variable
is no longer a string we can denote it
to be an array by adding these square
braces kind of at the very end of the
variable name now if I run this the
response that we'll get back is a PHP
warning it'll spit up on us it'll say
hey string compare expect perimeter one
to be a string but we gave it an array
and this will fall out all the sudden
the string compare will return zero
because I guess that's just what it
knows to do on that point you can see
that in the documentation and it says
the credentials for the next level are
and that is 25 and we've got the
password so just like that interesting
gimmick in PHP type juggling that strcmp
the string compare function is notorious
for having that and you'll see it time
and time again in some kind of low-level
you know capture-the-flag web exploit
stuff so let's save this as NAT is 25
and let's keep moving so thank you guys
for watching I hope you are enjoying
these videos if you are please do leave
a like maybe comment let me know what
you think what you'd like to see what I
suck at what how you're solving this
stuff etc etc if you're willing to
subscribe and if you really want to help
me out please support me on patreon I
want to showcase some of the supporters
I have currently so shout out to Spencer
Clark and gal Horowitz please forgive me
if I butcher your name one dollar or
more and I can give you a shout out in
the video and five dollars or more and
I'll give you early access to as much as
I can whenever I upload things to
youtube I normally do them in advance
I'll schedule them for a gradual release
schedule but if you don't want to wait I
can get you them as soon as I'm done
recording and as soon as the contents
ready so thank you guys again I'll see
you in a later video