so that is 21 of the over the wire war
game starts us off with the same kind of
notification as earlier your login is a
regular user login as admin to retrieve
credentials for the next level they give
us a note here though they say the
website is co-located with another URL
and that is 21 experimenter and that's
peculiar we'll have to note that and
we'll check out what the source code is
before I do that I want to snag that
experimenter that just that URL doesn't
look like it needs a username in there
at all but let's actually check out the
source code for this original page
before we move on let's go ahead and
Deanna ties that and remove all the
break tags just like usual so we can
pretty much see the source code and
let's put it in a new page so it's easy
to see here so it doesn't look like
there's anything interesting in this
page other than it just gives us okay
here's the function source code for the
print credential thing determines
whether or not we're a user and would
give us the flag or the password for the
next level and that's all it does so
looks like that experimenter link is
where we have to go next to be able to
move on so let's head over there I'm
gonna just copy this and let's change
the get URL to experimenter check out
that webpage in source code so now does
21 CSS style experimenter this website
is co-located with okay the original
page that's fine example background
color yellow looks like you can change
the colors of the page here supposedly
in the in this form that's the
functionality this webpage whatever we
care about the vulnerabilities so let's
go ahead and take a look at the index
source code here and see if we can read
how how that may have a vulnerability
index source out HTML just add it to the
link here
let's also D anta ties this kill all the
breaks and store this in another pane in
case we need it again so okay PHP code
here a little bit more active than the
previous page we have a session that
we're working with if Update was
submitted store it so if a reiki exists
submit
request so essentially if they submit to
the page every single key in the
requests Oh is actually stored in
session that's awesome
that is probably how we're gonna be able
to become admin it looks like that's
that that's pretty much a vulnerability
whatever we request to it will just
store in a session and if we're using
session to determine whether or not
we're gonna get the password then that's
it looks like that a bug messages go
through if we include that this code
looks like it it's trying to filter keys
down here there's a loop that determines
whether or not it is inside the valid
keys but and then it will add it to the
session key but it looks like it that
already happens like this exact line is
already being ran up here okay whatever
looks like we can still take advantage
of that so let's see if we can get the
session admin variable updated it looked
like we could run with debug source to
bug true being set we can go ahead and
run the get statement here and we see
that above notifications okay session
contents array they're not set to
anything but since they're testing
through the request we don't have the
request associative array or that that
that notes that global in PHP that's
either PHP post or get so we could just
try submit equals one and see what
happens here right yep okay it looks
like it's gonna read the get variables
just as well as it would have read the
post variable so we don't have to change
the the Python function that we're
trying to run with requests now let's go
ahead and set admin equal to one because
we can do that just as easily and now we
have a session variable for our admin
being one perfect so I'm going to assume
if these websites are co-located looks
like the session variables are probably
just going to be there they're gonna
stay intact so let's check out what our
session cookie is
in this website in the experimenter and
then let's try and use that as the
string for our PHP session in the
original page and see if we can actually
log in as as admin in that let's try
this I'm just gonna note that there but
let's change this back to URL so we go
to the original page and let's try with
a cookie PHP session ID set to that same
string and let's check out what we get
Oh looks like I put that to the source
let's go to the original page and this
website is co-located blah blah blah
you're logged in as a regular user okay
so no dice on that one login as admin to
retrieve credentials for natus 22 hmm do
we need the same session already
occurring let's comment that out and
make sure that all happens I would think
maybe you need the session already
occurring no let's let's set a post
request and make sure that actually
happens I guess let's post to
experimenter and let's let's do this
with post variables if we need to
whatever weighs a little double them up
there's nothing wrong with that so data
will equal that and submit can you cool
whatever admin can equal one let's try
that let's try old session being set
here because that's not gonna let us in
is it no okay let's grab that text then
or whatever it did I print it out in
here I did so whatever that PHP session
ID might be we can pass that along to
the original page old session
and let's see if it runs there we go
cool so the way that I did that was I
got the original session set up maybe we
may not even need this post since we
were doing with get earlier let's try
that nope looks like we don't need to do
it in post because again that requests
global and PHP will work just fine it'll
take either get or post variables it
includes them all so after I've got that
session already set up I'm able to just
steal the cookie from the original page
the experimenter bring that over to the
real level page pass that along with the
cookies and it will say okay great
you're authenticated you're logged in
with that admin credential your admin
the credentials for the next level are
now tis 22 and we'll keep moving save
this as natus 22 let's get the password
in here we don't need the experimenter
variable anymore probably just use that
and don't need the others but that is
that that is not as level 21 an
interesting trick with an external page
hmm don't know what this is doing
looks like we'll check out now 222 in
the next video but hey if you did like
this video please do press that like
button maybe leave me a comment let me
know what you think what else you'd like
to see what else I could do better with
how you solve this if you're willing to
subscribe and if you really want to
support me please just check me out on
patreon
on that note a special shout out to
those that support me already Spencer
Clark thank you so so much for
everything that you're send along you
really help and support me in the
channel I offer a reward if you some
support anything if you send in anything
in patreon I'll give you a shout-out for
every video and $5 or more and I'll give
you early access to whatever I can for
what I upload to YouTube so thanks for
watching guys see you in the next video