what's up guys this is John Hammond
continuing on the natus war game from
over the wire I just got the password
for natus level 4 so we've got that
going in our script let's actually print
out the content of the webpage as we
connect to it make sure we update the
path or the file that we're actually
retrieving and we want to just go ahead
and get the page let's set the syntax to
HTML so we get that nice color coding in
sublime text and the content of this web
page says access disallowed you're
visiting from empty string well
authorized users should only come from
HTTP natus 5 at nat Assad Labs okay so
well what do we what do we need to do
here I am curious how its determining
where we are visiting from and I think
it has something to do with HTTP headers
so HTTP headers are carried with every
single request that you end up passing
the server and typically they can come
with a get or a post or any other HTTP
verb or what you're trying to do so come
on some of the common ones are like
x-forwarded-for or except the kind of
file that you're looking for even though
it'll carry the cookies with you etcetra
etcetra and you can continue through
these etc and examine some of them but
they are like a dictionary value and key
pair of things that you're giving to the
web server so headers can have specific
values and one of the most common ones
that we'll see at least when we're
making a request with a get request or
get verb that we're doing at least in
Python and through our web browser is
with the referrer or HTTP header and
that's I think what they're examining to
see where we are coming from this from 1
up here typically contains internet
email address host says the domain name
of the server that's actually really
crucial for virtual hosting and virtual
host routing you'll see that a ton in a
lot of hack the box
vulnerable machines and other practice
you may do with that hack the box
training platform but refer is well I
think what we're gonna be checking out
right now user agents is all about your
browser and maybe we'll get into some of
that in a later level and natus and
maybe a later video let's check out
refer though so we can add HTTP headers
like kind of how we're doing a keyword
argument here in our get request in
using the request module in Python and
we can do that with a dictionary data
type so I'm going to call this headers
and in Python we'll just have a string
for the key that we're trying to use
refer and we'll give it a value that we
want so let's say just to test it out
will be like a subscribe lols shameless
plug there and let's pass that in to our
well I've been calling this variable
reponse for all of these videos holy cow
why didn't you guys tell me that's so
funny I got a rough fix gotta fix all
those other scripts all right let's pass
in this this argument law as a keyword
keyword variable and keyword argument
headers equals headers here
that's probably confusing because I'm
just using this variable named headers
to refer to this keyword argument but I
promise it's doing what we want it to do
even though it sounds pretty silly and
repetitive now let's run this script and
see what happens
checking out the response it says access
to salade you're visiting from subscribe
lolz okay so that clearly did work while
authorized users should only come from
this string that is v then that is v URL
so let's use that as the value for our
referer header paste that right here and
now we can run this script check out the
response
it says awesome access granted the
password for NAT is v is this lets
totally steal that and use that for our
regular expressions scraper
do we get the password that we want we
do perfect alright let's go ahead and
save this this is the correct natus for
script now let's create a new one for
natus five changing the changing the
username and the password
we probably don't need these headers
anymore so let's just go ahead and
create a new line where we aren't
passing those in and we don't need to
see the password we just want to see the
content because we are making a new
request to jump into this next level on
the script it says access disallowed you
are not logged in hmm okay that might be
working with cookies right typically if
you want to log in to a website or a web
application they store your login in in
a cookie or say that you over
authenticated with a cookie so let's
check out what we can see with our
cookies since we're making a standalone
request with requests dot get we
probably won't keep track of cookies in
an easy way all we're doing is a single
or question it's not keeping our our
session or our cookies alive in a
repeated connections so let's actually
move to a new object a session and that
can be recreated with just a request
module requests session and that will
return an object for us that we can work
with and create other create other
requests with that keep their state or
they keep the session that they're
working with you can see it actually
turned out here okay it is a session
object I printed it twice I'm a fool so
okay now we can make requests with that
not using just the request module as the
scope we can say response equals we're
session dot get or the name of our
object what we've created here
so now we can still get the same content
and everything back but now we're using
the request object or the session object
for us cool so the same response we'd
seen before but now that we have a
session object we can check out what our
session cookies are after we've viewed
this web page because this web page
probably set a cookie for us let's print
out session and the variable that we
want to check out to see what cookies
have been set for us is just cookies and
again if you don't know any of this
stuff or you aren't familiar with the
syntax you can just go and check out the
documentation on the requests online
website it kind of goes through in the
QuickStart how you can move into some
cookies here I just control out four
cookies and it will go through an
example here oh I guess it does set it
does it does to our cookies in this
response object cool good to know I
guess for moving on we can keep the
session variable session object let's
try it I guess when we run the script we
can check out what cookies we have here
sessions is not a thing we do want
session okay cool so now we have a new
object a request cookie jar and we can
see this cookie logged in is set to zero
so we can index this kind of just like a
dictionary here we can say logged in
just like that and you can see it's set
to zero if we set that to one that will
I don't know get a better get us logged
in maybe they get us that that'll get us
the password so since cookies also work
like headers in that they use a
dictionary data type in Python we can
say a new dictionary object a new
dictionary variable cookies equals the
syntax for a dictionary with the key
being logged in and we'll set the
password we'll set the value to two one
I'm using that as a string here because
all of that stuff that when it makes
connection to a website has to
the a-string so now we can use the same
get function we've been using before but
we can pass in cookies equals cookies
kind of just like we did earlier with
headers equals headers and that will
pass that dictionary along to our get
request so now we can totally check out
what the content is
and we're it easy as that access granted
the password for natto 6 is this stuff
so I want to just drive this point home
here if we were to check out again
session dot cookies you can see okay now
the request cookie jar has the cookie
logged in set to one because we've set
that with our request and the webserver
just must be testing what the value of
that cookie is and it's letting us move
so in the content we're getting as our
response we can give this string to our
we'll take the div with it to give that
to our regular expression hunter
and let's see what went along or
anything nothing cool we got the
password so let's go ahead and save this
script this will remain as our natus 5
script but we want to create a new natus
6 script with updating the user name and
giving it the the new password here we
don't need to pass in the cookies
anymore at least we don't think we do so
we can take that out of the get request
and we should be ready to move on for
the next level once we get moving in
I'll actually end this video now because
I think it's going on for long enough
but I hope you guys are enjoying these
again hopefully the style isn't too bad
and you're showcasing some some cool
things to do in sublime text and Python
and running through these natus levels
so thanks again guys see you in a later
video