what's up YouTube this is John Hammond
again showing you some more of natus
from over the wire this time level 13
so level 13 it works a lot very very
it's very very similar than that as 12
if you run the same script we've been
working with before just a Python script
to be able to get the contents at the
web page we can view the page here and
it says for security reasons we now only
accept image files in the uploader that
that file upload functionality you've
been working with in the previous level
so it looks like it has the exact same
functionality it's just that it says we
only accept image files so let's verify
that let's take a look at that index
source HTML page and see what it is they
really do in the code to verify that
it's a it's an image file that we're
uploading not not a PHP script so once
that's downloaded let's go ahead and
clean up that all of the the code here
looks like we still have that gen random
string make random path and make random
path from file named functions looks
like the only thing that has really
changed here is this big test if the key
exists the filename we're posting so if
we actually upload a file here tests for
the file size again tests oh here it is
here if not X if image type files
uploaded file type name so if that
doesn't return true it explains that the
file is not an image okay
let's I guess we'll just see what
uploading our original function will do
if we want I suppose let's save this and
put it in a separate pane so we can look
at the source code in a second but I
want to run this just to see what
happens and in it it says file is not an
image okay so whatever it is our PHP
script here is not passing that test so
take a look back at the source code the
function that we're looking at is X if
image type so what I thought this did
just kind of looking at it off the top
of my head was I
it was viewing the content type of the
file that we upload because normally
it'll pass along like in in the HTTP
POST requests or whatever it is that you
do it'll say like Oh image JPEG or image
PNG or image gif or whatever and that is
carried along like with the upload you
can actually get in the middle of this
in the request module if you wanted to
just like with this functionality here
and we're looking at in the
documentation and you can do that you
can make the change in burp suite or
whatever you wanted to just change that
raw HTTP like communication if you
wanted to but when I looked at this
function more in depth it turns out it
wasn't doing that I went ahead and
research what is this exif image type
really do and it says it reads the first
bytes of an image and checks its
signature so okay that means that we
must have to use something special with
our the PHP script or the file that
we're trying to upload to actually get
it to get onto the box so if we were to
run file on what our thing is right now
what the script is or the the file that
we want to upload it'll tell us okay
reading the first couple bites of this
you can tell it's a PHP script but if we
want it to if we will if we wanted the
server or the website to read the first
couple bites of an image and check the
signature we can't have it determined
that it's a PHP script we have to make
it think that it's something like I
don't know a Jif image or JPEG image or
a PNG etc etc etc so you we and any
other intelligent or people trying to
get around these things can make it
change to this file that isn't going to
be too detrimental it'll still operate
the same way we would expect it to if we
want it to be running PHP code but we
can include something like a special
magic header or the magic bytes of a PNG
image or a JPEG image or probably the
most easiest use case is a jiff
because a Geist magic header is just the
word jiff and then 89 lowercase a and
then if we go back to our command line
we can think that file Rev shell PHP is
actually a Jif image version 89 a and it
totally gets the dimensions wrong which
is really really funny but that's the
gimmick that's the that's the the kind
of hack we can do here and just like
that we can trick the web server to
thinking that we're uploading a real
image now if I post this it says okay
cool the file uploaded this guy has been
successfully uploaded so just like that
just making that quick change in that in
that remote code execution PHP script
just adding that jiff 89 at the very
very top the first couple bites where
should be in let's go ahead and change
that function call to get with the
uploaded file and let's run Who am I or
something make sure we've got it
run this command or jiff 89 alpha is up
there but we also get NAT is 13 so we
get code execution so let's cat out the
password for the next level with our
code execution capability run this and
just like that we get the password sweet
not a huge change from this level but a
really good thing to note just easy
gif89a 489 lowercase a I don't know why
I'm saying alpha I'm not a cool Coast
Guard kid that will that will work for
us so let's go ahead and create a new
script for NAT is 14 easy
we're cruising right along thank you
guys for watching these hope you're
enjoying them if you are please like the
video maybe leave me a comment on what
you think what else you'd like to see
share this video tell your friends and
co-workers and if you're willing to
subscribe guys see you in the later
video