what's up guys John Hammond here coming
back at you with another natus video
from the over the wire wargames we just
got the password for level 8 I paste it
into a new script with the correct
username at all
I do need to clean up the URL so that we
go to the right place and we don't need
to view our regular expression intact
anymore or a search we just want to see
their raw response to the webpage so
let's see we got here we can check this
out check out the response looks like
this is asking for another input secret
and that gives us the source code of the
website so let's go ahead and see if we
can get this source code here if I can
move over the connection
okay now that that is requested we can
go ahead and run that dn2 ties plug-in
code that we hit before and let's go
ahead and actually tidy up this HTML so
we can read it too and again we'll do
the same HTML DeAnza ties because some
of them were still stuck in here ok so
we've got some more PHP code we can tell
because of these guys here it looks like
I'll bud break breaks just managed to
stick in here the newline character is
just become breaks that's stupid I'm
sorry
we can view this in the web browser if
we really wanted to in fact let's do
that just to kind of make it a little
bit easier and remind you that you can
do that I know that it's kind of
different for me doing this stuff all in
Python but what the heck just wanted to
remind you that you can do this stuff in
the web browser obviously that's the
real point of the the wargame but doing
some really neat stuff with python is
cool too okay so we've got an encoded
secret and it looks like hex right it
looks like there's a function called
encode secret for secret there's an
argument that we pass into it
again PHP variables the dollar sign
looks like it will return bin to hex
string reverse basics for encode secret
Wow okay we're checking if the rake he
exists submit okay so if the form is
submitted
if we actually post to it it will run
encode secret but also it'll run this
function on what we submitted what we
pass to it and if it's equal to this
encoded secret it will give us the
password for natus 9 ok so we just have
to kind of reverse what this is doing
hmm
okay well what is happening here first
day base 64 encode this and then they
reverse it and then they turn it to hex
so hmm if we're trying to do the
opposite of this right if we're trying
to bring this backwards let's see what
this is and bin or binary I think I
don't know if you have PHP installed but
I think I do
PHP 7.0 if we echo just this oh we might
need to make a scrip for it which PHP
7.0 okay it's a thing let's go ahead and
create a second natus 8.5 just just oh
no I've done it now to say dot PHP this
is going to be a PHP script we're gonna
work with the code if you haven't done
this if you haven't had installed PHP or
four you should be able to sudo apt
install like PHP 7.0 Tex CLI or
something you can check the repositories
with sudo apt cache search if you need
to but when we ran which PHP 7.0 that
was user bin let's go to our shebang
line user bin PHP 7.0
set the syntax here to PHP for us okay I
guess our shebang line is just kind of
gonna look like that let's let go do I
have anything in this PHP I don't have
any syntax highlighting in this thing
okay whatever I code that out can I run
this can will PHP work here seemingly
not looks like I broke my build commit
okay whatever oh I probably need a
semicolon here PHP 7.0 second taught PHP
great mmm oh we need to actually put
that in PHP stuff duh now let's set
syntax for PHP we need to actually have
the question mark braces around it so
when I run this is it any better
nope I don't we make that executable
some of the old Python script one not
having it hmm
are you kidding me okay so you have to
denote it with the question mark PHP I'm
sorry guys that was probably pretty
torturous didn't mean to didn't mean if
you have to watch all that okay the new
line will stick in there if we run it
just like that okay so now we can run
the opposite of these PHP functions so
bin to hex is a thing in PHP and there
is certainly a hex to bin function I
would think yep noted in the see also
section here decodes a hexadecimal
encoded binary string so let's run that
hex to bin on this thing now this looks
like base64 except it's backwards so
they had ran STR rev on this right if we
run this okay now it is base64 encoded
and we can do what was the function
called base64 encode we can do basic C
for decode neat and this should be the
secret we want okay let's go ahead and
put this back in our natus eight thing
here let's go to make a request here a
post request now and let's say the data
again gonna be a dictionary so curly
braces secret was this string that we
just discovered and we do want to
include that submit variable as well so
the program actually so it actually
knows that we are submitting so let's
run this see what we get here oh we are
still requesting to index source
let's go back to the original root page
and access Granite password for natus 9
is this thing so I didn't do a whole lot
here to really reverse this other than
explore PHP code within PHP code and I
literally just kind of worked backwards
from what they had because the final
function that we saw them run was bin to
hex and obviously this looks like hex
right so I kind of worked from the
outside in in a weird way and just work
backwards hex to bin reverse the string
decode the base64 and keep displaying it
on the screen so I can work with it and
that's it
you can do command line scripts with PHP
you don't have to all be in a web server
and that's a really cool thing to note
it's actually really powerful if you
tend to like PHP for the programming
syntax and the semantics because you can
still use it at the command line just
like we just did except for a little bit
of troubleshooting my bad but hope still
hope you guys have learned something so
if you guys are enjoying this series we
will get the password out of here and
we'll call it quits for this video I
should be able to just paste this here
steal the password out of this and save
this as not it's 9 dot pi and we're
ready to rock for uh the next level
let's keep moving all right see you guys
in the next video