what's up guys John Hammond here coming
back at you with some more videos on
natus the over the wire war game for web
application security just got the pass
before level seven
we can probably clean up some of these
comments here they've been around for
too long and I'm sure you're probably
getting sick of looking at them actually
we do want to keep printing the content
in case we're ready to move on to the
next level
and we won't need to submit anything
because we're not posting just yet let's
just get the page for a natus level
seven and see what we're working with
here I'll run this control B and here is
our prompts here is the file and the web
page that we returned with now to seven
great in the content div we've got links
here to page home and page about and
there's a HTML comment here or hint
password for the web user natus a tisn't
etcetera and that is what passed NAT is
8 so hmm I'm sure you're probably
wondering why are we passing variables
to the index dot PHP page to refer to
the page that we actually want to view
like home and about are those actual as
is home like a thing we can read or is
about a thing we can access even in this
current directory or something if I just
reach that yes okay so that in itself is
being included in the index page so does
it kind of zoom out here so you can see
this a little bit better let's say we
gave it this URL let's say we tried to
read index dot PHP with a page variable
being sent with with the get variable
saying that we want to go to about okay
it gives us this is the about page so
this text that we were able to see when
we went to just straight about that must
be the raw text of that file and about
is its own file so we must be reading a
file that is being included in index dot
PHP so index dot PHP must be able to
read other
with that page variable so when we went
to home it gave us the links here this
is the front page and about this is the
about page so if we can just access RAW
files maybe the vulnerability here or
the issue the gimmick we can take
advantage of is called local file
inclusion so local file inclusion lfi
and you can probably see here in the a
wasp security update and somewhere here
here's an example when you have a page
or on a website that is using a
parameter or an argument typically it
looks most commonly in like a get
request as to load another page we can
then and take advantage of that and kind
of abuse it make a request to a
different file located elsewhere on the
server like reading its entry password
if we back step through the file system
a little bit because we don't know where
in the file system we might be or the
root directory of the file server might
be like we could be in VAR www HTML
stuff if it's like an Apache server or
etcetera so we'll use the parent
directory the two periods to keep moving
up up up the file system and eventually
get to the root directory we can read
other other files out of let's try that
I will use that as the attack here
multiple multiple parent directory
symbols period period and then let's see
if we can view it set for password we
can okay because that page is just
straight up leaking it for us it's
including that file so we can get some
local file inclusion and explore things
in this in this website and this web
server this is actually pretty dangerous
especially if we get to like the current
process if we can get the process ID
I think it's proc self right
command-line maybe that will yeah we can
see like okay how is this command
started what memory Maps does that have
open the proc self check this out in
a command line proc self file system
that directory will let you see really
interesting things for how the program
is being run so since I patchy is
serving this webpage we're seeing how
Apache was started with that but
whatever we want to get to the password
we want to get to what we're really
looking forward to move on in natus so
let's try this let's use that attack
local file inclusion with it set run at
us web past eight and at its eight and
we've got it right here
cool we leaked out the password so how
can we steal this with a regular
expression content
let's go probably a new line character
between a break newline character
newline character and then the hint sort
of the hint comments let's see if that
will actually return for us will that
get it it will awesome so the newline
character is just representing the
breaks in the text there and retrieve
everything and use HTML comments note to
say that we this is the very end of or
trying to reach great so that's how we
stole the password using some local file
inclusions and legitimate vulnerability
in a lot of web servers on what web
applications doesn't have a whole lot of
security or mitigation techniques to
prevent it because most commonly you'll
see websites that will try and filter
out these period periods or do kind of
peculiar things and how we can load some
of the files or try and protect those
things but obviously local file
inclusion is a really bad vulnerability
to begin with but it's pretty cool so
alright thanks for watching this guy wow
I don't even know what I just said
thanks for watching this video guys same
gonna send a lot of words hope you guys
are enjoying the series hope it's pretty
cool hope you're doing some neat hacker
things and cyber skills and sublime text
and Python but I'll see you in later
video