what's up YouTube this is John Hammond
and we're looking again at the natus war
game from over the wire so now we're on
level 18 and let's go ahead and run our
script to see what it is that we are
actually working with here
looks like the page returns please log
in with your admin account to retrieve
credentials for natus 19 okay
so this doesn't look like the sequel
injection or the command execution that
we had seen in some of the other levels
maybe this is something new we have a
username and password input fields here
but let's take a look at the source code
and try analyze what we can paste that
into for our get request and now we can
Diann to ties what that returns for us
and remove all the break tags with some
Find and Replace magic so the PHP code
starts out telling us we have a max ID
variable set to 640 in the comment here
6-4 you should be enough for everyone
don't entirely know what that means just
yet so we'll keep reading here's one
function is valid admin login determines
if the request username is equal to
admin this method of authentication
appears being safe and has been disabled
for now okay so it just that function
returns zero it pretty much does nothing
just just return zero okay but that kind
of nerfs our ability to log in as admin
because if we were to pass a longest
request with the username field just
trying to log in as I'm and it wouldn't
work for us so okay whatever that's not
gonna do anything it just returns zero
so this function is valid ID just
returns whether or not it's a number the
argument that's passed to it the ID is a
number create ID user doesn't look like
users actually use in this function but
it does take advantage of this max ID
variable it's global scope right on the
outside and it creates a random number
from 1 to 640 that's what that rand
function does
okay so create ID is kind of random
debug messages we can use with a get
parameter that's pretty handy to know in
case it gives us any valuable
information but my session start looks
like it will determine whether or not a
session ID already exists in the cookie
a PHP session ID and if
a valid or not and if that is the case
it will go through with this code if not
it does nothing there is no else
statement with this it looks like so if
a session hasn't already started
looks like it will just say it fails or
turned false otherwise it will create a
new session determine if you're an admin
and a bug ok looks like it closes that
admin variable there such that session
admin equal to zero ok so that locks us
out again of being a band that still
won't work right there's haze valid
admin log and return zero such an admin
being sent to zero so it a session was
old admin flag set resets us so it looks
like it never really lets us be that
session admin yeah even this session
admin equals zero but later on in this
print credentials function it looks like
it's trying to determine if such an
admin is equal to one then it will say
you're an admin in credentials the next
level are here so we have to set session
admin to one but we can't in this code
place what we've read so far well
otherwise we're logged in as regular
loser a regular user sort log into admin
to retrieve credentials huh if the
session has started it will display that
otherwise it will read they read the
request for us session admin is going to
be 0 because that is valid admin login
is 0 and it will show the form if we
haven't if we haven't logged in ok so
let's just try it out let's go ahead and
make a get request here we'll pass in
the data make sure we actually post to
the real page not the source code no
changed URL up their username can equal
please and password can be subscribe
shameless self advertisement run this
so we get here your login to the regular
user log in as an admin to retrieve
credentials for natus 19 what the heck
okay I don't know why we aren't an admin
other than the fact that I tried to log
in as please subscribe so clearly we're
not gonna be an admin just like that
let's print out what cookies we have
because it looked like in the source
code it was showing us the PHP session
variable PHP session ID being set to 260
so that must be what that source code
gave us as the random number random
between 1 and 6 40 but there's no way we
could otherwise be an admin because it
wouldn't it wouldn't let us use any of
those like session admin variables so
maybe is is one of these session IDs
just just the admin ID I'm gonna do a
little bit of research here let's fire
up Firefox and I just wanted to show
this to you because PHP session ID is
something we should probably get to know
I know there is a PHP session ID PHP
calm like article on this thing there's
got to be a session ID PHP SS ID will
actually tell us what this thing is it
looks like it just gets in sets session
functions it won't tell us anything
about what that PHP session ID is
although then there is one and it looks
like it has to be stored stack overflow
PHP uses two methods of keeping track of
sessions cookies are enabled like in
your case it uses them okay so that must
be what we're working with so looks like
we have to change that cookie variable
PHP session ID to one of the numbers
between 1 and 640 because maybe one of
them will be an admin ID so let's try
that let's get the page with a session
ID set to something else so let's get
with cookies equals PHP session ID set
to one right it's got to be a string
here I don't need the cookies anymore so
I'm pretty trusting it will return says
you're logged in as regular a regular
loser and let's actually move move
forward from this here because we want
to see okay that one clearly wasn't the
admin user so what else can we get that
might be we want to determine in a loop
because we're getting the page over and
over and over again with a new session
ID if we are the admin so if you are an
admin was the string that was in it
right
let's see content response dot text can
just be the content variable that we're
working with content actually probably
want that down here print got it and
then print the content just print trying
ID or session ID and we will loop
through for session ID in range of 1 to
640 we can go up to 1 641 since that
will be inclusive here and let's run
string of our session ID
before we went to do this I should have
actually checked that or saved that
source code because I wanted to know
what that would be that string because
honestly honestly forget so let's just
check let's just do one more get request
to make sure that is the correct string
determining if we are not an admin let's
print response dot text DN to ties I
really should just save this code I'm
sorry I didn't you are an admin ok that
works just fine for us good let's put
this in a new pane in case we need it
again and let's start the attack session
ID get with the cookies PHP session ID
being set as a string here getting the
content determining if you are an admin
is in the content if it is it will get
it and then otherwise it will print
trying session ID and let's see how this
looks I'm gonna do this in the command
line so we can Python natus 18 pi try 1
2 3 etc etc etc so I'll let this run and
actually I should probably put a break
when we get it and then print the
session ID that we got now let's run
this and I'll pause the video so role
pauses recording so once it's done we
can see what the password is so I ran
through it and it didn't work so let's
take a look at the code and see what's
wrong
oh we were sending that to the source
code all along I'm a fool so that code
probably would have worked I'm gonna let
this positive video here pause the
recording so I can see ok so the script
returned now and I did get the correct
session ID at ID number or admin ID at
ID 138 so here we've got the password
you wanna admin the credentials for next
level are now to sign teen password this
guy and that's it so the session ID
we're passing in to our request but
since that's not part of the session
object it doesn't look like it's staying
in the session object itself it looks
like it's just going for that request
so that's peculiar note and I really
want to apologize about sending it to
the wrong page up there with the index
or still in the URL I'm sure you were
probably screaming at me the entire time
I need you to remember to change that
but thank you guys for watching hope you
enjoyed this let's go ahead and put this
new new password in a new script let's
put this in natus 19 and let's go and
set and see what this level is asking us
to do cool all right well hey thank you
guys for watching hope you're enjoying
these videos if you did like the video
please do hit that like button leave me
a comment let me know what you think
what you like what I can do better what
else you'd like to see please subscribe
and if you really really want to support
me floor head on over to my patreon
account so thanks again guys I'll see
you in a later video