hello everyone now let's talk about HTTP
basic authentication so HTTP
authentication is a way in order to
protect resources on a server so HTTP
protocol supports two authentication
HTTP basic HTTP digest authentication so
now let's see how HTTP basic
authentication works so here you can see
that here is our client and here is our
server so first of all the client will
send a request of a particular resource
to the server then if that resource is
protected then that server will request
client to add a username and password
then client gives the username and
password to the server and then after
receiving the username and password the
server gives the requested resource to
the client so this is how HTTP basic
authentication works but there is one
limitation or weakness in HTTP basic
authentication that is it never blocks
multiple retries which means if we don't
know the password then we can go on
adding wrong username and password and
it will never block us because it's the
weakness and the another weaknesses that
it transmits our username and password
in packets in the in the form of plain
text so the attacker takes advantage of
this limitation in order to do some kind
of attacks like brute-force attacks
dictionary attacks to find the username
and password now let's see how we can
crack this HTTP basic authentication now
let's see how we can crack basic
authentication so in order to test basic
authentication we will use the web for
pentester - ISO which we have used while
testing captures so here you can see
that my web for pen tested to ISO file
is up and running and its IP addresses
192.168.0.1 for one so we will also need
kali linux for it so here you can see my
Kali Linux so let's open web for pen
tester
and make sure that you have downloaded
and you are using web for pentester too
because the older version of effort
Pentastar not contains authentication
challenge it's it's only present in the
latest version of web for pentester so
here you can see my work for pentester
and here is an authentication category
so just for the time being let me click
on this example one so as I click on
this you will see that it asks us for
the username and the password
so here the thing to be notice that
there is no form through which we can
enter our credentials so this kind of
authentication this this box is actually
a basic authentication used for
protecting HTTP resources so if I just
enter here admin and password now let's
see what happens
it again asks us for the password
because we are entering a wrong one so
as I told you earlier that the main
weakness behind this basic
authentication is that it never blocks
multiple retries which means we can
retry multiple times by using wrong
credentials in order to find the right
one so let me click on cancel and you
will get a message here not authorized
so in order to crack basic
authentication there are different ways
there are different tools but in this
video I will cover a tool called as
Hydra which is present in Kali Linux so
with the help of this tool Hydra we can
crack the password of different devices
and like HTTP passwords ftv passwords
routers passwords everything so let us
go to the main page of Hydra here you
can see a very fast Network logon
cracker which support many different
services
so usage of Hydra is very simple so
before going further let's try to
analyze the HTTP basic request that how
the request looks like so let me start
Bob sweet
and let us also configure our browser
proxy settings
so my BOB suite is starting and let's
configure it to the manual proxy
configuration so it's a Bob suite IP
along with the port 8080 click on ok
let's go back and let's see that whether
a Bob sweater is running or not
so this kind of basic authentication
will not found in today's web
applications but this is just a demo
that how we can track the different
authentication types so let's go here to
the proxy and let's open this link so
here you can see the box will start
blinking and here is the request so I'll
forward this request and here you will
see a authentication required pop-up
so let me write here admin password and
click on OK now let's go back to our Bob
suite
and here you can see our HTTP basic
authentication request so it's a get
request you can see here and this is the
resource which is actually protected
this directory is protected by HTTP
basic authentication and in the last you
will find additional header fields of
authorization and it's some basic
authentication and here you will find a
base64 encoded value so what did value
contains it actually contains our
username and a password which we have
given admin password now in order to
verify that what we have given just
right click over here go here to convert
selection then basics t4 and click on
basic Steef or decode and here you will
find the user input which we have given
admin and password now let's just make
the intercept off and now let us try to
crack this as TDP basic authentication
using Hydra
so let me just type here Hydra so here
you will find a demo command which we
can use to use Hydra so we have to type
Hydra - L and the username which you
want to give like admin so that admin
name should be remain common and then we
will give additional parameter called as
- capital P and here will give the list
of our password file which contains
passwords and then we will give the IP
address of our web for pentester - along
with the protected resource now in last
videos I have showed you that in kali
linux there is one directory which
contains our word lists which we can use
for different attacks like dictionary
attacks brute-force attacks so here is
that directory which contains the word
list user share and word lists and here
is one file called as fast-track dot txt
now let's see what's inside this file
you will find a lot of passwords here
now let's try to use hi Hydra and we
will give the reference of this file
fast act dot txt so I have just written
here Hydra - L and the username should
be admin then - capital P and here we
will give the location of this file
first act dot txt which is inside user
share word let's and fast act dot txt so
now we have to write here the IP address
along with the protocol so we know that
the HTTP protocol we will use but here's
the thing so let me just first send this
request using HTTP
and the resource which is protected is
authentication / example1 so it's the
URL of that directory which is protected
by HTTP basic authentication now if I
just hit enter you will see that it asks
us that what kind of request we want to
send whether you want to send get
request or post request so while time of
analyzing this request in Bob suite we
have seen that this HTTP basic
authentication request is actually a get
request so what we have to do is we just
have to do a little modification in our
Hydra payload so all we have to do is we
just have to write HTTP - get then :
two slashes and the IP address of effort
web for pentester along with the
protected resource now if I just hit
enter here you will see that this tool
Hydra is successfully able to find the
correct username and a password so here
you will see Mac 16 tasks per one server
attacking service port 80 so the
hostname is this login is admin and the
password is admin and in the last you
can see at the statistics one of one
target successfully completed one valid
password found so now let's go here and
let's try to enter admin as a login name
and the password is also admin now let's
see whether it's true or false
okay so I forgot to remove my proxy
settings
so it's one for one so let's go to this
challenge again authentication example 1
and let's write here admin as a username
and a password should also be admin
click on ok and here you will see a
success message which means we are
successfully able to find the password
of HTTP basic authentication using Hydra
so if you are interested to protect your
SDP resource so you can apply or
implement HTTP digest authentication
that is secure
so in this video we have covered words
HTTP basic authentication and how to
crack that now thanks for watching this
video