hello everyone now let us talk about
curve so curly the small computer
utility which is used for transferring
data from various protocols so with the
help of curl we can send a request and
we can see its response it's just like a
command-line browser so inside the curl
there is one library called as lip
seeker which is responsible for
requesting a resource and retrieving the
data and with the help of curl we can
also do SSL certification verification
and the curl also supports cookies HTTP
HTTP protocol Gopher protocol and so on
so if you don't know what is go fur so
gopher is a protocol which is being used
before HTTP protocol for requesting a
resource but nowadays it's not used so
with the help of curl we can also send
HTTP request by using different HTTP
methods now let's see how current works
now let's see how we can use curl so in
order to start curl we have to start our
Kali Linux because curl is rebuilt
installed in Kali Linux so in order to
start curl we have to start our terminal
and here you can see that right now I am
inside my Kali Linux instance and just
right down here curl followed by the
website name of which um you want to
connect and transfer the data or you
want to fetch some data and if I hit
enter you can see here that it has
fetched all that tml content of this
website so by default if we make any
requests to any of the website the by
default HTTP method used by curtilage
you get now what if if we want to send a
particular request by using different
HTTP methods is there any way to do that
yes so how we can do that just right
down here curl - V so - V is for verbose
mode means for detailed information and
here we have to write down -
capital X and followed by the HTTP
method we want to use in this request so
let's request that modern Indian babies
dot-com by using head requests so - X
had had his HTTP methods which is used
to fetch the data but only the header
information and he fight and here you
can see the header information the head
request with HTTP 1.1 and user agent is
curl and here you can see the server
information along with the PHP version
number and SSL information okay now let
me give you one scenario just for
example we want to make a curl request
to a particular website but there is a
redirection on that domain just for
example if I just write here curl
google.com and hit enter you can see
here that it's same 3:02 moved and we
all know that 3 0 2 response code is
actually for the redirection now what if
if any of the website contains this kind
of a redirection that how we can
actually fetch some data by using curl
so just write down curl and write - L
capital L and any website name now what
will happen is if the curl will see that
there is a redirection then curl will
actually redirect to that redirection or
the curl will follow the redirection and
if I it enter now you can see the actual
content or the HTML data including some
JavaScript and some scrap data of the
google.com so now as a pen tester there
mind me some situation in which we want
to store all that ste ml content in a
particular file in a particular text
file for our future use and for our
future reference then in order to save
the
data in an any of the text file we can
specify - Oh method - no parameter here
you can see Cal - o - o is for the
output file space the file name like I
want to store the data inside curl dot
txt followed by the website name and if
I hit enter here you can see that it has
stored and received the data and now if
I do LS here you can see the file named
as curl dot txt has been created now
let's see that what's inside this file
and here you can see the entire HTML
content so this was the quick short
introduction of curl that how we can use
curl how we can send a different
different HTTP method request by using
curl so thanks for watching this video