hello everyone now let's see how we can
take our target or a website offline so
in order to take our target or a website
into our system we will use this
software st track so st track is the
website copier which is used to copy the
entire content of the website including
JavaScript pages CSS and HTML pages so
as a penetration tester sometimes we
faced our conditions where we have to
test the website but not on a production
server so as a penetration tester we
will use this tool in order to copy our
target or a website into our local
system so once we copy the website we
can host that files into our local host
server and we will test that website now
let's see that how we can use HT track
in our Kali Linux now let's see that how
we can use st track so as i told you
earlier that st track is available for
linux as well as windows so st track is
by default or a prebuilt
installed in kali linux so we have to
start it so here you can see that right
now I am inside my Kali Linux instance
so in order to start st track we have to
open the terminal so just click over
here and you can see the terminal now
just simply type here as T track and hit
enter so once we hit enter here you can
see that right now we are inside the st
track website copier so the first of all
it asks for the project name so let us
give the project name called as demo ok
now it asks for the directory in which
it will store the website so if you want
to give a particular directory in which
you want to save the copied website and
then you can otherwise you can just
leave empty and hit enter so if you just
leave this empty then by default it will
save all the website files in this
directory slash root slash web sites now
here we have to add the URL so let me
add a URL
and let's hit enter okay
so now it give us the Action List so the
first one is Mirror website then the
second one is mirror website with Vizard
then if you want to just fetch out all
the URLs and if you just want to fetch
out the test links but here we are
interested and mirroring the website so
I'll select the first one and let's hit
enter so if you want to give a proxy URL
and then you can otherwise leave it
empty leave it also empty hit enter
hit enter again okay so now ready to
launch the mirror now if you are ready
to launch the website copier then just
write down here why and hit enter so you
can just see here that you are running
this program as a root okay thanks for
using s3 tracks
so now st track has copied this website
modern indian babies names calm now
let's go to that directory slash root
slash website to check whether website
has been copied or not so let me just go
there first of all let's see that where
we are so we are inside root let's do LS
so here is that website directory
hit enter do LS so here is the project
name demo so let's go to demo directory
hit enter again LS so here you can see a
few details like cache a log log dot txt
and here is one directory called as
modern Indian babies named comm which
was our target so let's go there hit
enter and here you can see that it has
fetched and copied its index page so
let's open this page in Firefox and
let's see how it looks like okay so here
you can see that it has copied this page
along with the JavaScript and CSS files
so here you can see and you can also
check the part so this was all about a
steed rack so thanks for watching this
video