hello friends now let's talk about
cross-site scripting so cross-site
scripting vulnerability it's a
client-side attack and it's most
popularly called as XSS so cross-site
scripting vulnerability is often found
in lot of web application especially
where a user provides input to an input
receiving areas like search bars forms
and feedback forms so if the user
supplied input is actually being
executed by the web application which
means that web application is cross-site
scripting vulnerable so the user
provides JavaScript code instead of
providing a legitimate text and if the
JavaScript code is being executed by the
web application which means that web
application is processed scripting
burnable so cross-site scripting
vulnerability can also be used and in
order to steam user cookies session IDs
and even it can also lead to CSRF attack
so cross-site scripting is of two types
the first one is reflected cross-site
scripting and the second one is stored
crosser scripting now let's talk about
both of them in much more detail
so reflected cross-site scripting is
also called as non persistent cross-site
scripting because the here the user
input is not stored in database which
means if the user input is not stored in
database so that then the response of
the web application is only shown to the
user who is actually injecting the
JavaScript which means if we are
injecting something in in search bar and
our JavaScript is being executed by that
application which means the response of
that JavaScript can only be shown to us
not anyone else because our input is not
stored in database and the input is not
stored in database and often found in
search bar now let's talk about stored
cross-site scripting so store cross-site
scripting also called as stored XSS and
persistent XSS why because the user
input is stored in database and once the
user input is stored in database then
there are just for example there is one
comment section and we commented out a
JavaScript theory and in place of
comment we added a javascript curie and
we click on submit and our
Mendes submit and now if anyone visit
that page then the JavaScript also being
executed on that user which means the
impact of store cross-site scripting is
much more than non persistent cross-site
scripting and it can also lead to CSRF
attack now let's see how we can exploit
cross-site scripting vulnerability in OS
broken web application now let's try to
find cross-site scripting vulnerability
in mutilate a web application Somu
today's a web application maintained by
OS p-- and it's already present in OS
broken web application which we have
installed in the last video so here you
can see that man my OS broken web
application is up and running and here
is its IP address 192.168.1.1 this IP
address in my firefox okay so here you
can see this is a / s broken web
application and here is the link of OS
mutated a second so let's click on this
link and here you can see the OS muted a
web application and on the left hand
side you will see a different OS list
vulnerability list and let's go here OS
2013 so here you can see the different
vulnerable web application challenges
divided into different categories like
injection attacks broken authentication
cross-site scripting I do be cross-site
request forgery but for the time being
let's go here cross-site scripting and
now the cross-site scripting has two
types as I told you earlier the
reflected and the persistent and
reflected nothing is stored in database
it's a temporary and in persistent our
javascript is being stored in database
and it's affected and all the users
which will visit that page will just get
affected through a JavaScript so first
let's focus on this reflected cross-site
scripting so if you go here
select this this links set background
color okay now let me give you an
scenario like you have you arrested one
website so here is the same page or the
same functionality which the website is
offering to the user now let's try to
play with it what it's saying so please
enter the background color you would
like to see okay
so enter the color in hex format now
example red is this now let's try to add
this color code and let's see what
happens and if I click on set background
color you will see our background has
been changed now okay now as I told you
earlier that in crosshair scripting our
main motive is to execute JavaScript on
this web application now as a pen tester
what we can do is instead of adding a
simple text instead of adding legitimate
text can we add a JavaScript here so
before going further let me let me write
a simple HTML code which is responsible
for taking the user input for here so
just for example I am just writing here
an example code input type text' and
name equals color and value okay so just
for example this is the input tag which
is responsible for taking the user input
and whatever input is given by a user
like if I just give here so this input
is get is get stored in here and in this
place so if the user will add this input
it will just get store here now this
becomes like this okay now what is our
motive or what sir
what's our goal is to somehow execute
JavaScript in this pack now just for
example what if if user tries to add
this as an input now if this is given as
an input now let's see that how this
input tag looks like so let me remove
this and let me copy this out let me
paste it here and if I paste it here you
can see that now our web application may
get confused why because if we if we
just look at here it says our our web
application may think that this tag is
closing here at this point due to our
input so now what we can do is can we
add an another tag after this which we
just get execute here at this point so
just for example let's write here script
simple JavaScript code which will alert
XSS okay
now let's copy this input and let's
paste it here and let's see now how this
tag looks like okay so here you can see
that our input tag is closing here and
here our script tag will going to be
executed so this is how we can analyze
or we can find that how we can get rid
of the normal behavior of the web
application and how we can try to
execute our cross-site scripting or
JavaScript now let's try to add or
supply this input to the web application
and let's see how it looks like or how
it works let me just write down here
again normal text now on double quotes
for clothes this is for the closing the
input tag now let's try to add script
tag here and let's see how it looks like
okay now if I hit enter you will notice
that we are successful to executing a
JavaScript here our JavaScript injection
or crosshair scripting injection has
been successful here you can see so our
JavaScript has been executed if I now if
I click on OK you will see the same page
back see in the previous page why
because this is reflected XSS nothing is
stored in database so the response of
this JavaScript will only be shown to
the user who is actually adding the
JavaScript into the web application so
this was all about reflected XSS now
let's have a look at store XSS so in
order to exploit cross-site scripting
stored so just let's go here cross-site
scripting and now let's select this link
persistent second order and here is one
link here is one page add to your blog
let's click over here and one thing more
this Avast mutiny application comes in
different different security levels so
right now security level is 0 it's very
easy so in the upcoming video series
I'll make different different video
series of for different different
vulnerabilities with their security
level 5 but for the time but for this
video series I will cover all the
vulnerabilities with security level 0
okay so right now we are at this page
welcome to the blog so it looks say it
looks similar to any blogging website so
where we can add a blog so what that
same adblock for anonymous ok so first
of all let's try to add a normal text
first let's try to analyze the normal
behavior of this application let's add
here hello this is a sample text click
on save blog entry and let's see how web
application is treating our text if
scroll down here you can see that our
text is stored in comment section here
you can see hello this is a sample text
now what we can do now let's try to
inspect this le try to inspect element
let's go here inspect element let's over
here
okay so here is our text you can see
hello this is a sample text and this
text is being enclosed in PD tag now
what we can do let me open a notepad
file again so here is our text hello
this is a sample text being enclosed by
TD tag now what a pen tester can do pen
tester can give the input like this okay
so now this will be our input now this
web application will think that this is
now that this TD tag is closed here now
let me just remove this thing and let me
just copy this out and paste it between
these two tags and here you can see that
our TD tag is closed here at this point
and after this TD tag we can try to add
some JavaScript code
okay now if I just copy this out and me
remove this and paste it here now here
you can see that we are successfully
able to close the TD tag here and
executing our JavaScript now let's copy
this input and let's go back to our
challenge and let's paste it here input
and now click on save blog entry and
here you can see that we are
successfully able to execute JavaScript
on this page and here you can see our
session ID along with the cookie so if I
click on OK then if I scroll down and
let's try to inspect element again and
here you can see that our JavaScript in
is now the part of this page and if I
scroll down here you can see that now
our JavaScript is the part of this page
baganz it and it's stored in the
database now let's try to open any
another page and then we will come back
to this page to see that whether it's
stored in the database or not ok so here
you can see now let's let me try to
refresh this page and here you will see
that this javascript code is being
executed again and again because at now
this time it's stored in the database so
now in this video we have covered that
what is cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities it's different types
thanks for watching this video