hello everyone now let's talk about HTTP
protocol so HTTP stands for hypertext
Transfer Protocol
so it's a client-server model in which a
client requests a particular resource
from the server whereas the server
serves that resource to the client so
HTTP protocol is used for accessing a
resource on the internet and it is used
to request a resource from the server
and here you can see the HTTP working so
here is our client here is our server so
client requests a particular resource
and the server will serve that resource
to the client now let's talk about HTTP
versions so there are two HTTP versions
HTTP 1.0 and HTTP 1.1 so HTTP 1.0 is the
older one
whereas HTTP 1.1 is a newer one and used
nowadays so in HTTP 1.0 we can request
only one resource in a 1 connection
whereas by using HTTP 1.1 version we can
request multiple resource from the
server using a single connection now let
us talk about HTTP 1.0 and HTTP 1.1
working in much more detail so here you
can see the HTTP 1.0 working so the
first of all the client will send a
request to the server for making a
connection and once their connection is
established the client will send a
request for requesting a resource and
the server will serve that resource and
once the client got that resource here
you can see that their connection breaks
so this was an HTTP 1.0 whereas in HTTP
1.1 let's see what happens so by using
HTTP 1.1 version so the 4 steps are same
so make connection connection
established client will request a
resource server will serve that resource
and then here you can see that monster
client got that resource the client is
requesting another resource and it's so
on and their connection will still still
remains until client wants to disconnect
that connection so this was the key
advantage of HTTP 1.1 version in which
we can request multiple resources by
using a single connection now let's talk
about HTTP
test code so just for example so you you
might have seen that while opening any
website sometimes the website give us an
error like 3-0 to 404 500 error so what
these kind of errors are so these are
called as HTTP status codes so HTTP
status codes are nothing but just a
server responds towards our HTTP request
so here are different kind of HTTP
response codes you can see here like 200
400 3 300 500 so if we are successfully
able to access our resource then we got
this HTTP response code that is 200 so
HTTP 200 response code is 4 ok or a
success and the response code which are
responsible for the redirection is 3 0 1
& 3 0 2 and now just for example we are
try to access any resource and that
resource is not present on that server
then we got this HTTP status code that
is 404 not found and in the last there
are two access HTTP status code that is
505 0 3 so these are server-side HTTP
status code in which there might be an
server error and we got the these HTTP
status code 505 0 3 in that cases so in
order to send HTTP requests we also have
to specify that what kind of HTTP method
we want to use now let's talk about HTTP
methods so HTTP methods are types of
requests which we want to send means we
want to send an HTTP request and what we
have to do in HTTP requests can be
defined as HTTP methods and here you can
see the different HTTP methods like get
head put post patch so the get method is
used for accessing any resource or
fetching out any resource so head method
is used to see the server HTTP headers
but not the HTML data whereas the post
and put methods are used for sending an
input to the server and there is
interesting method called as options so
if the user wants to know that what kind
of HTTP methods are enabled on a remote
server then a user can send HTTP
requests by using options method and in
the response the user will see that what
kind of HTTP methods are actually
enabled on a remote server and in the
last there is one method called as
delete so delete method is one of the
dangerous methods because by using the
delete method and if the delete method
is enabled on any server then a user can
delete any particular resource on the
server by sending the HTTP request by
using delete method so this was all
about HTTP protocol now let's talk about
three-way handshake so what is 3-way
handshake a 3-way handshake is the first
process before requesting any resource
so a three-way handshake is used for
making a connection between a client and
server or between two networking device
so three-way handshake is a first
process and it's a three-step method
here you can see our client and here is
our server so the first of all the
client will send a send request to the
server so send means synchronize so just
for example the client will say hey I am
new here I want to connect with you now
let's see what server gives the response
so the server will send say none deck so
send means synchronize and
acknowledgment acknowledgment so then
the server sent okay let's connect and
in the last here you can see that the
client will again send act which means
thank you and here you can see their
connection is established so this is how
the three-way handshake works so in this
video we have discussed about what is
STB protocol it's different versions and
it's HTTP status course along with its
methods and what is 3-way handshake
thanks for watching this video