hello everyone now let's talk about
cookies so before going further let us
discuss about HTTP statelessness so HTTP
protocol is a stateless protocol which
means if you open any website again and
again you will be treated as a new user
so we have to give our information again
and again when we open any web page of
that website because we are treated as a
new user
that's why HTTP protocol is called as
stateless protocol because we have to
give our information every time we open
any web page so in order to get rid of
it we use two things cookies and
sessions so with the help of cooking and
sessions we not have to give our
information again and again when we open
a particular website now let us discuss
about cookies so cookies are a small
files which contains information so
cookies contain information in a text
file or it's a text
it's hardly of 4 KB in size so cookie is
not an executable file and it's stored
on a client site by a browser into our
system and sometimes the cookies are
also stored for storing the user
preference so cookies also contains some
login information authentication
information and even session IDs so now
let's discuss about that what kind of
fields are present inside the cookie and
how cookie stores our data so cookie
stores our data in the form of name and
value pair like there will be a name and
then there will be its value so now
let's discuss about cookies important
fields so here you can see that there
are 5 important fields in cookies so the
first field is domain so domain field
tells us that of which domain this
cookie is then the path field will tell
us that of which particular path this
cookie is set it up then secured so if
the cookie is being sent through a
secure medium by using HTTP protocol
then this field will be present inside
our cookie and then there is an expires
so expires field will tell us that when
this cookie will expire and in the last
there is one field called as HTTP only
so if the STP only field
present inside the cookie which means
that cookie cannot be stolen by using
javascript so this was all about cookies
now let's do one cookies example by
using Python flask now let's see
cookie insertion demo using flask so I
have written very simple script in
Python which will set a cookie in our
browser and then we will see that how
that cookie looks like so here is my
github link and here is that script
which you can just download it from here
from this link and if I just open this
up so you can see the code here set
cookie PI so I'm using flask in this
example so what's the flask is so flask
is a web application framework written
in Python so in the above two lines you
can see that I'm importing flask
libraries and here is the function which
is responsible for setting up the cookie
and this is the cookie key value pair so
the keene the name of the key is course
and its value is web pentesting so let
me open my Kali Linux instance so here
is my Kali Linux instance and here's my
firefox browser and let me download this
file
let me save this page on my desktop
setcookie dot pi okay so the file has
been saved on our last desktop here you
can see now let me open the callee
terminal so in order to run this file
make sure that python 2.7 and the flask
is installed in your system so Python
2.7 is already installed in the Kali
Linux here you can see and in order to
install flask you can install flask by
writing pip install flask and it's
already installed in my system so here
you can see requirement already
satisfied now let's go to our desktop
and here you can see that here is that
file setcookie dot py and in order to
run it we have to change it so in order
to run it we have to make it as an
executable so in order to make it
executable just write down chmod then +
X followed by the filename setcookie dot
py and if I do LS again here you can see
that now it's an executable file so in
order to run it just write down Python
and this file name and hit enter ok and
here we can see that this file is up and
running on our localhost server this IP
and the port is 5000 now let's go back
to our browser
and now let's go to this IP localhost IP
and the port is five thousand so before
going there let me show you that in
which place our browser stores cookie so
just go to settings preferences and then
privacy and here you will see the option
remove individual cookie so if you just
recall here here you can see the cookies
of the different websites like
github.com and if I expand this you can
see the cookie domain domain is
github.com and this path is just a root
folder and the name of cookie and the
expiration today so this is expiration
date now let's do one thing let's move
all the cookies and now let's open that
localhost IP and the port is 5000 and if
I hit enter here you can see in the
response cookie inserted now let's
verify click over here remove individual
cookies and here you can see our cookie
and scientist our localhost and if I
expand it so this is the cookie so in
the name of the cookies course as we
discussed and its value is WebP and
testing so you can see the host here and
path also
so in this video we have discussed that
how websites usually set the cookie in
the user browser so thanks for watching
this video