hello everyone in this video we will
talk about cross-site request forgery
so cross-site request forgery also
referred as CSRF or C Cerf so before
going further let me give you one
example that there is one user who is
logged in on a particular web site and
attacker sends a malicious link to that
user of a malicious website and if that
user clicks on that link and open that
malicious web site then that malicious
web site will make a request to that web
site on which the user is logged in on
the behalf of user so here you can see
that that malicious web site will make a
legitimate request to that legitimate
web site on which the user is
authenticated and the request is
triggered as soon as user click on that
malicious link so the session IDs
cookies tokens are all sent by users
browser to that legitimate website if
the malicious web site make a request
now let's see how CSRF attack works now
let's have a look at basic C's of attack
the first thing we have to do is we have
to start our OS broken web application
which we usually do all the times and
here you will see that my OS broken web
application is up and running so let me
open the OS broken replication of
Firefox
now this time we have to use this web
application over ass with app goat so if
I just click over here it asks us for
the username and the password
so the username is guest and the
password is guest click on OK
so here you will see the ovis web code
web application so let's click over here
start web good and on the left hand side
you will see lot of challenges let's go
here cross-site scripting and here you
will find one challenge called as
cross-site request forgery or cease off
let me open this challenge so what we
have to do is we just have to assume
that we are a normal user we are a
authenticated user and we are logged in
so now what we have to do is we actually
have to create HTML page or we have
actually have to create HTML page and
inside it we have to create an image tag
which will be hidden so that image tag
will actually points to this URL and in
that image tag we have to pass
additional parameter called as transfer
funds so if I if I if any user like me I
am authenticated user here as web God so
if an attacker will send me the link of
its web page so if I just open its web
page then a transfer of 4,000 rupees
will be done from my web goat account so
this is the challenge so here you can
see your goal is to send an email to a
newsgroup that contain edge that contain
an image whose URL is pointing to
malicious request so try to include 1x1
pixel image the URL should point to CSRF
lesson with an extra parameter called as
transfer funds and here you will see
that they have given us something to
store the value like if I just write
here
text hello this is sample text and now
if I click on submit you will see that
this text has been submitted and we can
just read it content now let's create
HTML file which will point to that CSRF
URL
so height should be one and it should be
one and the source let me just copy this
URL let me paste it over here and what
they want is they want an additional
parameter called as transfer funds
equals 4,000
so here you will see that our HTML
webpage is ready now one thing more so
there are different different tags in
the HTML which we can use to trigger the
CSRF attack so the one is image because
the image tag contain a source and we
can point the source to our CSRF web
application so we can also use iframe
tag because iframe tag also consists of
this attribute source then we can also
use script tag and few more so let me
just paste it we just create a file
called as attack dot HTML and let me
just close this so now as an assumption
so what we have to do is we have to
layout our victim as a pen tester we
have to lower our victim to open this
file so if we if our victim open this
file then the transfer of 4,000 rupees
will be done from his account so if I
just open this file ok now let's go here
and I'll refresh this page but before
refresh this page let's do one thing
let's go here to the developer and click
over here Network and I'll let now let's
see that what's the network traffic
comes in and goes out now if I just
reload the page you will see at top this
get request and if I just click over
here you will see our request and here
you will see a small green tick means
the transfer funds of 4000 has been
successfully done from the victim
account so you will see a green tick so
if you want to just restart this lesson
just click on restart this lesson so
this was the very very basic
attack of sea surf but in the advanced
courses we'll cover this topic in much
more detail so in this video we have
covered that what's a cease of attack
and how we can do cease of attack and
with good web application so thanks for
watching this video