hello everyone let's discuss about
another kind of injection attack that is
formal injections so formal injections
are also called as CSV Excel macro
injection so before going further let me
give you one scenario that there is one
web application on which we can add it
create and export Microsoft Excel
spreadsheets so as a penetration tester
or a hacker what we can do is we can try
to inject something malicious inside
that spreadsheets so once we inserted
something malicious then we will export
that web sheet so if that web
application is vulnerable to formula
injection then that web application will
not sanitize the user input and export
that web sheet which contains the
malicious code injected by an attacker
so if any other user will open that
Microsoft Excel spreadsheet will get
affected and which results in
client-side injections so here you can
see so these kinds of vulnerabilities
are often found on web applications
which having export spreadsheet
functionality and this spreadsheet is
being generated without sanitizing the
user input that results in code
execution at the client side now let's
see how formula injection works now
let's see how we can do CSV injection or
formula injection so before going
further let's understand that how
Microsoft Excel executes our formula so
let me start here Microsoft Excel and
here you will see a formula bar so if I
just write here equals to sum so I am
writing here very simple formula which
will do the sum of two numbers and if I
hit enter here you will see that our
formula has been executed and the sum is
20 now what happen is while pentesting
any web application sometimes the web
application has a feature of exporting
data in the form of CSV files now as a
penetration tester what you can do is
you can inject something malicious in
the CSV file and that malicious code
will execute it as formula
in the Microsoft Excel and some commands
will be executed on client side now
let's go here dynamic data exchange
protocol is responsible for inter
process communication and for sharing
data between the two applications in
Microsoft Windows so the format of this
protocol is like this equals two here
will be the server file and item and
here the server is the program which
will handle the user request and the
file is which we just execute and here
you can see the most commonly used
payload used to test the CSV injection
so here you can see the equals to sign
is for starting of the formula and here
is a CMD so it's a server which will
handle the user request and it's the
here is the file see ALC which will get
executed and we all know that CLC dot
exe is actually a calculator dot exe
file in Microsoft Windows now in order
to test this payload what we have to do
is we'll use extreme wearable web
application which contains this runnable
csv web page so let me go here so here
you can see that my extreme whenever the
application is up and running and i have
hosted this web application on kali
linux and if i scroll down on the left
hand side you will found a one challenge
or formula injection so let's open this
up
scroll down and here you will see some
list of items including the item code
item name category and price and here is
one option to export this file export
this data to csv file let me just click
over here and here you will see that
it's saying you want to save this file
or you want to open this file so let's
save this file and let me run this and
here you will see the list of the items
coffee items comes here now in order to
test that whether this web application
is vulnerable to CSU injection or not we
have to find a way so that we can
on input here which comes under this
category so there is one challenge here
called as unrestricted file upload so if
I go here here you will find that add a
new item to coffee list which means by
adding here by adding some data here we
will able to inject our malicious code
and that will comes under this page for
rule injection so now let's fill these
fields let's go here to the upload image
and select any random image so item name
will be demo in äj-- so description
should be anything so this is csv
injection test so now here in place of
category let's copy this payload and
paste it and the price should be
anything so let's click on submit and
here you will see that our item upload
successfully now let's go back to
formula injection page and if i scroll
down here you will see that our item has
been added into its list and here is our
payload now let's export this file save
this and run it so here you will see
that it's saying Microsoft officials
that it's a kind of a malware security
concern enable and here you can see that
Microsoft Excel is saying whether we
want to open a CMD dot exe or not and if
I just click on yes here you will see
that a calculator application is up and
running automatically so which means we
are successfully able to inject CSV code
and now we can execute any commands on
client side now in order to extend this
attack what an attacker can do so they
can execute a matter patter scripts
using invoke shell codes using reverse
handlers and so on now let's talk up
talk it about written but more advanced
so what happen is most of the web
application nowadays
and they just filter out this equals to
sign and the user input now what we can
do is in order to execute our CSV
injection again we can also use a
different characters that will also
signifies the beginning of a new formula
so we can use at the rate plus minus and
some few more characters so here you
will find advanced payload so it's an
advanced payload which we can use in
order to test CSF injection so if we
just look at this payload you will see
here that the add add the rate some one
plus one so it's a beginning of a new
function and here after the
multiplication we have written our same
payload so let's try to copy this
payload and let's try to execute this
payload directly inside the Microsoft
Excel and let's see whether it works or
not let go here let's paste here hit
enter and here you will see so it's
saying that whether we want to execute
this file if you just click on yes here
you will see that calculator comes in so
this is how we can inject CSV code and
we can do formula injection so in this
video we have covered that what is CS
means action what is CSV macro injection
and how we can do it now thanks for
watching this video