hello everyone now let's talk about
capita testing so if you don't know what
our captures so captures is a technique
in order to distinguish the users from
the human or bot which means it captures
are used on a web application in order
to distinguish whether the user that is
assessing that web application
is human or a bot so CAPTCHAs are also
used to secure the website from CSRF
attacks but if you use captures in order
to protect CSRF then it's not a
recommended measure because the captures
can be easily bypassed it's no matter
that how hard the captures has been
developed now let's see how we can test
some captures in order to bypass that
captures now let's do some capture
testing on web for pen tester too and
you can download the ISO file of web for
pen tester too by clicking over here and
here is that link so it's later it's the
latest version of web for pen tester so
I have already download this ISO file
and you can see on my desktop so let's
create a virtual machine in VirtualBox
for the web for pen tester 2 and here
you can see that I have the previous
version of web for pen tester but it's a
new one so let me create a new virtual
machine so web for pen tester to click
on next and click on create so click on
settings so depending upon your network
configuration you can change your
network settings so for me I want to
change and put it on the bridge adapter
click on OK
and let's start this machine so when the
first time this machine will start up it
will ask us for the location of the ISO
file so let me give the location of the
ISO file it's on my desktop
so here you can see that right now we
are inside the shell of reffered
pentester now let's check its IP address
so its IP address is 192.168.0.1 for one
so let's open this IP address
so here you can see that the web for
pentester 2 contains lot of additional
challenges like mass assign assignment
authorization MongoDB injection and here
you will find a list of challenges
inside the CAPTCHA section so let's open
the first example so here you will find
a CAPTCHA along with that field so the
main reason for implementing captures to
protect the website from sea surf but in
order to protect the seas of attack the
CAPTCHA is not recommended and nowadays
the CAPTCHA is used for to differentiate
between the bots and the human beings so
by doing CAPTCHA testing our main motive
is that whether we can bypass this
CAPTCHA otherwise we can fill it and
pass it now for the time being if I just
pass it any random string and applicants
submit Kure now let's see what happens
you will see nothing and the capture
value has been changed now if I go back
here to the it's paid source and if I
scroll down you will find that here is
the image capture image that's coming
from and here you will see the input tag
where we'll add our text and here is an
input button now let's analyze this
request through Bob sweet so in this
video I will cover two example of
CAPTCHA testing and let us configure the
browser proxy settings
okay and here you can see that my Bob
suite is up and running now let's add
any random Kure and click on submit and
here you will see our request under the
proxy tab so it's a get request and here
you can see CAPTCHA example 1 submit and
it's accepting is 2 parameter
the first one is capture and its value
which we have just passed here you can
see hello and then submit and here you
can see the host details along with the
user agents and cookie detail now if we
just click on forward and forward the
request we will see nothing now let's
try to bypass this CAPTCHA and let's see
what kind of response we got from the
server now I'm just leaving it as a
empty so let's just click over here
submit query and here you can see the
same request now what I'm going to do
here is I'm removing this additional
CAPTCHA parameter here you can see let
me move this and so now there is only
one parameter that submit and now the
point to be notice this that we haven't
given any kind of capture here ok and
here you can see that we are
successfully able to bypass the CAPTCHA
and here is a success message so due to
the poorly configured captures the
captures can be easily bypassed if there
is a no validation checks occur now
let's have a look at capture example 2
okay so here you can see the same
challenge the same capture challenge
let's try to fill any random Curie and
let's see what happens so this challenge
is very interesting so here you can see
the request of this challenge and
example - so now it's taking actually
three parameters
the first one is capture in which we
have given the our input that's hello
and another one that's answer here you
can see the answer now if I just click
on submit and let me forward this
request and we will see nothing so in
the most of the cases what happen is the
captures actually comes from the image
source now if we just look at its path
source of this challenge
we'll come to know that by implementing
this capture the web developer have
actually hard-coded the value of CAPTCHA
in the pace source so if we just look at
the page source and scroll down here you
will see the captcha image and here is
the hidden input field here you can see
input type is hidden and its value is
this which means the value of this
CAPTCHA is hard-coded already inside the
source code so if this is hard-coded
inside the source code or if it is
already present inside the source code
then what's the need of implementing the
CAPTCHA so it's another a wrong
application logic which might lead to
bypass this capture so it's again a
wrong application logic now we can also
do one thing let's now we came to know
that this value is actually present
inside a hidden input field now let's go
here and let's go to form and display
form details and if we display form
details so here you can see that the
hidden input field is displayed here in
front of us let's copy this input field
and
let's paste it here now click on submit
Curie and let's see what happens so our
request goes to the Bob sweet okay click
on forward let's just go back and let's
just remove this and here you can see we
are successfully able to crack this
challenge so there are different
different captures implementation and
their weaknesses which we will cover in
the separate video series so but for the
time being we have discussed that what's
a CAPTCHA testing versus the use of
CAPTCHA and how we can find the Misurata
configurations and capture thanks for
watching this video