hello everyone now let us talk about
HTML injection were nobility
so HTML injection is also called as a
rendering attack because instead of
injecting JavaScript into a web
application we try to inject HTML code
and if that web application is being
rendered according to our HTML code
which means that web application is HTML
injection burnable so similar to
cross-site scripting HTML injection is
also of two types stored in which the
user input is stored in database the
next one is reflected in which the user
input it will be not stored in the
database and the response of that HTML
injection can only be shown to the user
who is actually injecting that HTML code
now let's see how HTML injection works
now let's see how we can exploit HTML
injection vulnerability in you today so
in this video I am taking the previous
cross-site scripting challenges pages
which we have covered in the last video
but instead of adding a Java Script
in them we will try to inject HTML code
and we will see whether the utility web
application is being rendered
according to over HTML code here you can
see that right now I am on mutilate a
web application so let us go back to the
previous challenges of the cross-site
scripting
and here you can see that right now we
are this challenge at background color
so this challenge looks similar to the
crosshair scripting but now here instead
of adding a JavaScript we will try to
add HTML code okay let me close this tag
now let's add here h1 tag and let's see
whether this web application or this
page is being rendered according to this
HTML tag so let me just write down here
DML injection and let me close this h1
tag let's click over here set background
color and here you can see that we are
successfully able to execute HTML code
here and here you can see that this web
application this web page is rendered
according to our HTML code here you can
see our HTML h1 tag is executed so this
is the reflected at steam injection now
let's have a look at stored ATS tml
injection but before going let's reset
the database so that our previous Java
Script Curie which which was stored in
the database just get deleted now let's
go here cross-site scripting second
order and add to your block now in the
last video if you remember then we just
came to know that the PV tag is
responsible for enclosing our input now
let's give us now let's just write hello
and let's close the TD tag here and
let's try to add any JavaScript code so
I am adding a market tag here
and let me click on 'save blog entry and
let's see whether we are able to exploit
this page or whether we are able to
execute that steam injection here or not
okay so here you can see that our HTML
code market tag is being executed and
it's running here you can see and in
this video we have covered that what is
at steam injection there it's different
types and here we will see that how we
can exploit the HTML injection
vulnerabilities so I recommend you to
practice these all challenges in your OS
broken web application and thanks for
watching this video