hello everyone now in this video we will
talk about file inclusion vulnerability
so what is file inclusion a file
inclusion is a process in which one file
include another file in itself to view
its content or in order to share some
data now what happen is file inclusion
is an accessory feature of the highly
complex web application means it's the
necessary feature or it's a requirement
of every complex web application and
what happen is sometimes in a web
application one file tries to include
another file in its current context so
as a penetration tester or as an
attacker what we can do is we can try to
include some server file in it and if
our web application included the server
files and we are able to see the server
file content which means that web
application is file inclusion vulnerable
so if we just look at this URL here you
can see that here is one file called as
index dot PHP and this index dot PHP
actually takes one argument called as
page and here we are giving another file
name that is html5 storage dot PHP so
this index dot PHP file is including
this file in itself now what we can do
is we can try to remove this file and
here we can write down the internal
server files path and we'll see whether
this web application includes that
server file in itself and we are able to
see the content of server files or not
so this file inclusion vulnerability is
of two types local file inclusion and
remote file inclusion so in the next
video
we'll talk about both of them local file
inclusion and remote file inclusion in
much more detail so in this video we
have covered what is remote file
inclusion vulnerability and it's
different types thanks for watching this
video