hello everyone now let's talk about and
map
so nmf stands for network mapper and
it's one of the best open-source tool
used for scanning the network with the
help of an map we can scan open ports
and the services running on them
including their version number so the
and map is also used for searching the
operating system that is running on the
remote host and with the help of n map
we can perform various scans including
service can aggressive scan and with the
help of aggressive scan we can fetch a
much more detailed information including
our target operating system and the
metadata and some additional information
like internal files now let's see how we
can use M map in order to perform
various scans now let's see that how we
can find open ports and their version
number by using n map so in order to use
n map we have to start our Kali Linux
and here you can see that right now I am
inside my Kali Linux instance so in
order to start n map we first have to
open the terminal
let me open it up so in order to start a
n map we just have to write and map
followed by the website name or the IP
address so let me just write down here
ok so once you write the website name
you can also write a particular port and
let's scan all the ports which are
opened on this website along with their
services now let me hit enter and here
you can see that our nmap scan has been
started and it's my n map version 7.40
it's a it's a newer version because I'm
using Kali Linux 2 and it shows us the
detail of port its State and along with
its services so you can look at here
that on port 22 this
state is open the port 22 is open and
the service running on port 22 is SSH
so same you can see HTTP service carbo's
https and some my sequel service and few
other services so this was the basic
usage of nmap now what if if we want to
scan the version number or you want to
enumerate the version number of a
particular service so why in a meeting
the version number is important so as a
penetration tester your main goal is to
find the version number because once you
get the version number a penetration
tester can use some tools or can search
the particular exploit corresponds to
that version number so that's why
scanning the version number is must so
there is one scan in nmap called as
version scan so let's see how we can use
it so we have to write and map - s and
capital V so s is for steel and this V
is for version number followed by the
website name so you can even write the
IP address instead of writing the
website name hit enter so these kind of
scans take little bit time ok so let's
see the result
so it's here is a port then the next
column is of state then services and
here you can see additional column of
version so this output is same but here
is the thing so here is a service as a
chest and you can just read its version
OpenSSL 6.2 then HTTP version then my
sequel and a path applied so now it's
giving us an additional information that
this website is hosted on Mac here you
can see Mac OS
so this was all about the service scan
so the best practice of a system
administrator here is to hide the
version number of the running services
so now let's talk about aggressive scan
in nmap so aggressive scan is one of the
most powerful scan of an nmap because
aggressive scan contains all the
features of different different scan or
you can say that aggressive scan is a
combination of different scan so by
aggressive scan one can find the
services version number metadata
disallowed directories and even the
routing also DNS servers names also and
some additional stuff so now let's see
how we can use aggressive scan an nmap
so in order to use it we again have to
write and map - capital a followed by
the website name
so this can aggressive scan take a
little bit time so we have to be patient
okay
now scan has been completed now let's
analyze it result okay so here you can
see that first of all it has enumerated
the ssh public host keys then the PHP
version also of port 80 HTTP and here
you can see the additional information
like HTTP title the website title along
with the SSL server detail so if I
scroll down you can see lot of juicy
details along with the name server
domain name server and it has also find
that the operating system on which this
website is hosted
so it's hosted on apple OS X and if I
scroll down here you will see or find
the traceroute detail so here you can
see the traceroute
so this can can perform a best
information gathering for our target so
this was all about and map and the basic
usage of an map now thanks for watching
this video