hello everyone now let's talk about
login page SQL injection so in the last
video we have seen that how an attacker
can inject its own SQL queries in order
to dump the entire database so similarly
an attacker can also try to inject its
own special crafted SQL query on inside
the login pages in order to bypass the
login pages because what happen is some
time login pages are also vulnerable to
SQL injection so if the login page is
vulnerable to SQL injection then an
attacker can easily bypass that
authentication mechanism now let's see
how we can do login page SQL injections
now let's try to do sequel injection on
login pages so here you can see that
right now I am on brick's web
application so this is the application
which we have used while testing a
sequel injection so if I just go here so
you will see a login pages link so let
me open this so here you will find that
there are total 6 login pages which are
vulnerable to sequel injection so let's
open the first one because it's the
basics 1 so it's just like a login page
here you can see that we are not logged
in so let's try any random credentials
and let's see what whether it works or
not so here you can see it has prompted
wrong username or a password and at the
bottom we can see the Curie so let me
copy this query and paste it in a
notepad file so here you can see that
this is the Curie which is executing at
the back end select star from users
where name is admin and password is the
password which means it's doing and
comparison between the user supplied
input or between the data which is
present
in the database so now in order to
bypass this login page what we can do is
we can do a small trick in order to make
this brick server application confused
so what we can do is so what if if we
just right here in the place of username
so if I just write here admin single
quote or one equals one so now what it
means so it means we are closing this
field name by just here admin and I'm
adding an another condition that is one
equals one so as we all know that one is
equals one and it's a universal truth so
this will remain true and by adding the
or operator this will not matter that
whether this part should be true or not
if this is true our condition will
become true so in the place of password
if I just add here same thing admin or
one equals one and in the place of name
let me just add this har one equals one
now let's see this Curie so it becomes
select star from users where name is
admin okay or one equals one so if this
will not true then this will be true and
the password should be admin so this
will not true this part will always true
one equals one
so none now let's try to add this as our
input so admin single quote or one
equals one and let me copy this Kure
and let me paste it here and now let's
click on summit and let's see whether it
works or not okay and here you can see
that we are successfully able to logged
in and you can see the Curie which is
executed at the back end
so this was a small example that how we
can bypass login pages through sequel
injection so in this video we have
covered that what is login basical
injection and how we can bypass the
login pages using sequel injection
thanks for watching this video