hello everyone now let us talk about an
web scripting engine so nmf scripting
engine is actually a part of an nmap and
it's one of the most powerful feature of
the nmap so through animal scripting
engine we can write our own scripts
which we can use in performing different
networking tasks so we can also use
pre-written scripts of various security
researchers present already in animal
scripting engine so one of the most
powerful of feature of this tool is that
we can use this tool for standing our
target and once we scan the target we
can exploit our target so this tool is
also comes in the category of V apt tool
that is vulnerability assessment and
penetration testing tool so here you can
see the NSE script categories so in NSE
under scripting engine the scripts are
divided into different categories as
follows so the first one is auth so the
scripts which are present inside the
earth categories are actually used for
finding the authentication pages or for
authentication purposes then the scripts
which are present inside the Brut
categories is actually used for
brute-forcing the target like for
performing different good force attack
dictionary attacks to FTP logins astir
DP logins and so on so the script
present in discovery categories is
actually used for finding the target or
used for scanning the target then there
are other categories like dos exploit
further used for fuzzing the target and
malware so if you want to know more
about NSE scripts categories then you
can visit their official website here is
the link given below so now let's see
that how we can use animal scripting
engine in order to exploit our target
now let's see that how we can use and
map scripting engine so in the last
video I showed you that how we can use
and map and we all know that an maps
scripting engine is a part of an map so
NSE contains a different different
scripts divided into different
categories like script for
authentication script for host discovery
script for reckonings
and so on so forth so let's start and
map first so right now I'm inside my
Kali Linux instance
and here is the terminal cally terminal
you can see so in order to use any
script any of the nmap scripting engine
script inside our and map search what we
have to do is we first have to write an
map then we have to give an additional
parameter called a script - - script
followed by the script name so in this
first search I am using a simple script
called as banner so what this script
will do the script will make an
connection with an any open port on a
server if that open port sent anything
to our script or anything to our request
then that script will print out that
data here in the result so I'm using the
script and map - - script script name is
banner followed by the website name
okay so here you can see that it has
printed out the banner of port 22 and
banner detail is ssh version and same
like port 3306 it's printing its banner
and same for the port five nine double
zero so this was the simple script which
just print the banner and some any
random data sent by the particular port
now let's use some another scripts of NS
e so n map - - script now I'm using one
script called as HTTP headers so first
of all what is HTTP headers HTTP headers
are nothing but just our HTTP request
and response means how our request and
response looks like so there is one
script in an web scripting engine called
as HTTP headers so I am using this
script so nmap - - script HTTP headers
followed by the website name
okay now let's analyze the result so as
we all know that the port number for
HTTP is 80 and here you can see the list
of HTTP header so now what our HTTP
request contains or what's inside the
HTTP header so here is the list so it
also it contains date the server
information to whom it requesting or
receiving the request response then
access control X power then connection
close connection type text HTML now
let's scroll down and let's read the
HTTP header it's same and the request
type is head so this was all about HTTP
headers now let use one script which
will enumerate all the important
directories on a remote server owner or
on a remote website so their script name
is HTTP ennum so let me just write down
and map - - script followed by the
script name that is HTTP ennum and
followed by the website name
okay now let's analyze the result so at
port number 80 it has an M rated sum of
files and some of its directories here
you can see and same for the port 443
slash icon slash images slash help so
now if you remember our last video about
scanning the target in which I showed
you that how we can scan the different
different subdomains of a particular
website by using nach PI scan so there
is one script in nmap called as DNS
brute which will perform same tasks as
nope I do so now let's use that script
to enumerate the sub domain so the
script name is DNS root now let's check
the subdomains for google.com hit enter
okay so here you can see that it has
listed out all the subdomains of
google.com along with its IP address so
you can see a long list of detail of a
domain names of Qualcomm so this was a
quick short introduction about nmap
scripting engine so thanks for watching
this video