hello everyone now let's talk about
MongoDB injections so MongoDB is one of
the most popular non relational database
so it's a non relational database which
means it not store data in the form of
rows and columns but the interesting
fact is that MongoDB database can be
exploited similar to SQL injections and
XPath injections but in order to exploit
MongoDB database we have to do a little
modification and special characters now
let's see how we can do MongoDB
injections now let's see how we can
exploit MongoDB database so in order to
test MongoDB injections we have to use
the same web for pen tester to
vulnerable web application which we are
using from last few videos and here you
can see the web for pen tester is up and
running and here are two examples of
MongoDB injections so let's open the
first one example one and here you can
see that it asks us for the username and
the password
and if you look at this URL it's looks
same like the LDAP injections but as I
told you earlier that the MongoDB
database is a known relational database
and it not contains the tables rows and
columns now how we can bypass this
mechanism so if you remember then while
doing login page sequel injection we
have given our input which is logical
true so that input was admin or 1 equals
1 which means this admin and or 1 equals
1 so this previous query and this
statement will be compared and as we
know that one is equals to 1 it's a
universal truth
so this Curie will be executed and will
be successfully logged in but as this
MongoDB is a non
relational database so we have to do
some little modifications in our given
input so so we'll just give admin so
instead of writing or we will write the
or operator which is two pipe signs and
we'll give it one and instead of typing
this equals to sign we have to write two
equals to sign so that it can become the
equals to operator so if we just give
one equals to sign that will acts then
it acts like an assignment operator so
you have to give it two and one so now
let's just copy this input and let me
just paste it here and let's see whether
we are able to logged in or not and here
you can see that we are successfully
able to log in so this was a small demo
of MongoDB injections which can be
applied to any another non-relational
database so in this video we have
covered that what our non-relational
database and how we can exploit MongoDB
database thanks for watching this video