hello everyone now let's talk about path
traversal attacks so path diversity tags
are also called as directory traversal
attacks so in these kinds of attacks
the directory browsing is allowed on a
remote web server and if the directory
browsing is allowed on a server then
what the attacker can do the attacker
can try to access files from different
folders or from a different directories
so the main goal of the attacker can
tries to access the files which are
present outside the root directory or
outside the home directory of that web
servers so these files are server
internal files which are not accessible
by the users so by using these kind of
attacks path terror cell attacks the
attacker can access these files which
results in full compromise of system now
let's see how path traversal attack
works now let's see how path traversal
or directory browsing attack works so
here you can see that right now I'm
unmuted a web application so let's go
here OS twenty thirteen and here you
will find a category of security Miss
configuration and inside it there is one
challenge directory browsing let me just
open it up and here you will see what's
it saying so saying that some of the web
servers are actually misconfigured which
allows directory browsing which means
and most of the web application of the
servers are actually misconfigured which
actually allows users to access its
directories and to seize that what's
inside the directories and what are
their files so most of the web
application has disabled the directory
browsing whereas the most of the web
application has enabled the directory
browsing now let's see that whether this
mutilate a web application has enabled
the directory browsing or disabled the
directory browsing so as a pentester
what one can do there are different
different techniques in order to find
whether the directory browsing or the
path traversal attack is actually
enabled or not so the first technique is
to using a burp suite because in the
last video I showed you that
the Kali Linux contained a lot of word
list file which contains lot of decay
which contains a lot of words dictionary
words so a one can configure it's Bob
suite intruder module to attack the
server application and tries to finds
the important directories and then we
will see that whether that directories
are present or not the second thing is
that we can just commonly guess the
directory name and we will see that
whether that directory lists out all the
file for us or not and if that directory
is present and it's listing all the
files for us which means this web
application is a directory browsing
runnable so if I just erase this thing
so here you will see that here is one
directory mutated a and if I just hit
enter we'll just get prompted inside
this index dot PHP file now make a fake
guess that there must be an images
directory inside this mutilate a web
application from where these images
these icons are coming from so now let
me just write down here images and let's
see whether that directories are is
present or not images and if I just hit
enter here you will see that we are able
to access this images directory and here
you will see it's all the files so if I
just open any file here you will see
that file you can just go back so here
you can see that this mutative
application is actually whenever of
directory browsing so instead of images
let's just try to guess one more
directory called as includes and if I
just hit enter here you will see that
the files which are present inside the
includes directory some PHP files some
configuration files so what one can do
is one can configure its Bob suite to
attack this web application by using the
word list now let me going to show you
some word list in Kali Linux which one
can use so the word list is present
inside this directory
here you can see hey so here you can see
there are two directories dir and dir
buster it's a directory buster let me
just go here and here you will see there
are a lot of files now let me just add
it this big dot txt file and let's see
what kind of directories or the file
names that have here you will see lot of
file names or a directory names which
one can use so let me just search it
like admin here you will see the
directory name is install admin and so
on so forth
so this was all about path traversal or
directory browsing attack so as a
penetration tester or as a secure web
developer I recommend you to please
disable directory browsing in your web
application so in this video we have
covered that what is path traversal
attack and the Reg diction and directory
browsing issues so thanks for watching
this video