hello everyone in this video let's have
a look at testing environment setup so
in this video we will see that what are
the different things which are required
in order to setup our testing lab so we
need three things the first one is
VirtualBox that is a software in which
we will install our virtual machines
then we'll need Kali Linux which is one
of the famous penetration testing
distribution then we'll need Mehta
spirit of a Linux which is actually a
vulnerable Linux operating system which
contains lot of vulnerabilities in build
day so in this video we will cover this
small introduction and in the upcoming
video we'll talk about each of them in
detail so thanks for watching this video