hello everyone now let's talk about
Wireshark so Wireshark is most popularly
used a network protocol analyzer so with
the help of Wireshark we can capture the
internet packets which is going in and
going out from our system so it's the
most popularly used software used for
capturing the internet packets mainly
tcp/ip internet packets now let's see
how we can capture some packets by using
wireshark now let's see how Wireshark
works in order to start Wireshark we
have to sort our kali linux and even if
you want to use Wireshark in Windows you
can download Wireshark from their
official website but in the Kali Linux
it's already installed you know so in
order to run Wireshark open the terminal
and right down here Wireshark and hit
enter so every time he runs the
Wireshark this error will come so you
have to ignore this okay so well I told
you earlier that via shot can capture
the packet on a particular interface but
what's the interface what is the
interface so interface is nothing but
just your internet connection so if your
Kali Linux is installed in VirtualBox
then your interface should be eats 0 ETH
0 and if you are if you have connected
your Kali Linux through your Wi-Fi then
your interface should be WN 0 and if you
want to sniff the packets to the
localhost then you have to select this
interface loopback interface but right
now my Kali Linux is actually connected
with the each 0 interface so here you
can see the activity that the packets
are coming going in going out so you can
see a little bit activity here at each 0
now in order to sniff the packets or to
capture the packets on this interface
you have to select this you can just
click over here this icon otherwise you
can just double click on this interface
so as soon I'd double-click here you can
see the list of packets which is going
in and going out the result you can see
is actually divided into different
columns here you can see the number of
packets their time and destination that
way they are going and the protocol
which they are using and information
regarding a particular packet now in
just for example let's ping google.com
and we'll see the packets which is
coming in and out and these packets are
being captured by Wireshark and if I
scroll down you can see the packet Eco
ping ping request and ping reply so this
source you can see a source here this is
my car Linux IP address and this is the
destination IP so this is the IP of
google.com and the protocol is ICMP and
in order to find or to in order to read
a detailed information about each and
every packet just select that packet and
here are some packet header information
so it's frame Ethernet header Internet
Protocol so let's read this in the
Internet Protocol header you can just
check the source address and the
destination address and the destination
geo IP location also the location of
google.com or the location of this IP
United States and in the last there is a
header of ICMP also you can check the
ICMP protocol header so it's a type 8
header and here you can see a coping
request and if I scroll down you can
just also check the timestamp and also
data which is coming in and out and the
size also 48 bytes here you can see the
data and its length and at the bottom
here is some hex values you can see so
actually this data is present in the hex
values so the work of Wireshark is to
parse this data
and of hex data to parse the hex data
into this text one so even if you just
select any part of hex data you can see
that that part of text will
automatically select it if I just click
over here you can see so this is how you
can use Wireshark to capture the packets
which is coming in and going out from
your network thanks for watching this
video