hello everyone now let us talk about
remote file inclusion vulnerability so
remote file inclusion over nobility also
referred as RFI so in remote file
inclusion over nobility attacker or
penetration testers tries to include
remote files which are hosted on a
different web servers so these files are
specially web shells and if you don't
know what is the web shell so a web
shell is a small piece of code which is
written in different different
programming languages depending upon the
web application so through web shell one
can access the remote server so all we
have to do is we just have to include a
remote web shell inside the web
application which is remote file
inclusion burnable and once our web
shell is included and died web
application then we can access its
remote server now let's see how we can
exploit the mod file inclusion
vulnerability now let's have a look at
remote file inclusion vulnerability that
how it works so here you can see my
notepad files which we have created in
the last video while doing local file
inclusion vulnerability test here so
here are some URLs so let's analyze them
so here you will see that the page
parameter is actually accepting one file
which is included in index dot PHP so
the difference between local file
inclusion and RFI is that in remote file
inclusion what we can do is we can
include a file which is hosted on a
different server which means the file
which are not present on our actual
servers but it's hosted on some another
server
so now owatta pentester what a hacker
can do so they can try to include some
kind of web shells to the web
applications and if the web application
is able to include the web shell inside
it then what the pentester can do he can
gain a remote access of that web
application now in order to test remote
file inclusion vulnerability is the
first thing is we have to start our OS
touken web application where you can see
it's up and running the next thing is we
have to start our kali linux here you
can see my Kali Linux is up and running
now let's do one thing first of all
let's just open the muted a web
application
let me just open any page okay now in
Kali Linux there is one directory which
stores a web shells now let's go to that
directory it's inside us are then share
and web shells so here you can see that
here are different different web shells
available in different languages like
the web shells written in PHP is present
in PHP directory the web site written in
Perl is present in Perl directory but
for the time being we are interested in
PHP so let's go to PHP directory hit
tell us and you will find a lot of web
shells written and are available in PHP
so the most common one is simple
backdoor dot PHP it's a command-line
shell and PHP back dot dot PHP it's a
GUI shell now what I'm going to do here
is I am I will run a Python simple HTTP
server and the port will be 5,000 now
what it means actually in Python there
are pre-built servers or scripts so I'm
using this script Python
- 'm simple HTTP server and i'll run the
server on port 5,000 so what it will do
it will actually create a server on this
directory PHP and then I can access this
files and try to include in neutral a
web application but for that we also
have to know that what is the IP of Kali
Linux so IP is 192.168.0.1 35 now let's
do one thing let me just hit enter and
here you will see that my astir DP
server is up and running let's go back
here and at this after this page
parameter now let's try to include web
shell remotely by just entering the IP
address of Kali Linux
and the port is 5,000 and the shell name
is simple backdoor dot php' hit enter
and here you will see that our rep shell
is up and running so this web shell
simple backdoored PHP also takes one
parameter called a CMD
now let's pass this parameter in a URL
string but here the thing to be notices
that we have already given one parameter
that is page so now here we can't add
exclamation sign we have to add and then
parameter name because it's a second
parameter CMD equals LS and here you
will see that we are able to access the
remote server by using this rev-share
now we can execute any command like if
you want to check the present working
directory so here you can see go ASP
mutiny day so this was a difference
between local file inclusion and remote
file inclusion vulnerability that in
mode file inclusion we can remotely
include any web shell or any script
inside a web application so in this
video we have covered that what is RFI
vulnerability and how to exploit RFI
vulnerability thanks for watching this
video