hello everyone now let's talk about
security miss configuration issues so
the main cause of security miss
configuration issues are wrong
application logic so what happen is
while developing one web application the
web developer implements some wrong
application logic which results in
security miss configurations so one of
the common example is a user hide secret
pages by unknown URL example a web
developer wants to hide some secret
pages from the users so it actually
changed the name of that URL so that the
users can't be figure out that what's
the name of that URL so this is how the
web application or the secret pages
remain hidden but what's the threat here
so the threat is that someone can brute
force or first that web application urls
in order to find some interesting urls
and if they are able to find that urls
which are hidden that resultant so some
of the msconfig security miss
configuration issues also results in
path disclosures or even directory
traversal attacks now let's have a look
at one example of security miss
configuration issues now let's have a
look at security Miss configuration
issues so here you can see that my OS
broken or application is up and running
so in order to access the security miss
configuration challenge let's go here
here you can see security Miss
configuration let's select that this
first one secret administrative pages so
what's the goal of this challenge other
words the aim is to try to find some
hidden pages which the administrator has
actually hide it from the user now what
we can do is while testing the Ella fire
nobility we have seen that this muted a
web application is actually including
all the pages from here from this
parameter pages so what we can do we can
actually try to brute force or we can
actually try to find different different
pages by doing some different attacks
like dictionary attack brute force
attack so to do so we have to start our
web suite so let me just open my web
suite here
so the security Miss configuration
issues actually occurs when a wrong
business or a web application logic is
made by the web application developer so
here you can see that my BOB suite is up
and running let me just go to proxy tab
and it's running on one to seven
localhost IP and port is 8080 let me
configure my proxy settings of Firefox
by going here to the options advanced
network settings and manual proxy
configuration and here you can see that
I have already configured my manual
proxy the through port 8080 just click
on OK and now if I just reload this page
you will see that my BOB suite has start
blinking so here you we can see the full
request so it's a get request and here
you can see the page parameters they're
actually including this PHP file so now
what's our aim is our aim is to try to
find some hidden PHP files which are
being included in this web application
so now let me send this request to
intruder so to do so just right click
and send to intruder and here you will
see that our intruder tab starts
blinking let me open this so through
this intruder tab we can actually attack
the web application through different
different ways like we can do password
guessing attacks we can do dictionary
attacks brute forcing attacks simplest
attacks and so on so the first thing you
will see here the target so here is our
IP address of mutiny Day and here is
port 80 so now let me just click over
here positions so the positions is the
main thing which we have to be take care
of now what's the position is so the
positions are actually the points on
which we want to do attack or we want to
repeat now first of all the first thing
we have to do it we are we have to clear
all the points so just click over here
clear ok now
is a request now what we want we want to
send this request multiple times to the
server but what we want that this file
this this thing after the page should be
changed in every request so now what we
can do is we have to select this thing
which we want to repeat or we want to
change then click over here add and here
you will see that this position has been
selected now so here the different
attack types but for the time being
click over here sniper now once we did
this we have to select the payload we
want to use and here you will see the
payload set 1 and payload type a simple
list there are a lot of another payloads
like run time file case modification
character blocks brute force earthday
it's numbers and but we are interested
over here simple list now let me just
take you inside the kali linux and show
you that the kali linux contains a
directory called as word list where it
has tons of words which we can use for
our attack so let's go to USR then share
then wordless directory and here you
will see a different directories
contains a different word list so as now
we are interested in dictionary attack
or a directory because we are finding a
directory or we are finding the page so
you can go to any of them these two
directories yet for the timing let's go
here and here you will find a lot of
text files already created by the
researchers so let's see that what's
inside a particular all the files let me
just see what's inside this small dot
txt file hit enter and here you will see
a lot of words and the file names which
are actually present so what we can do
we can configure our Bob suite to pick
all these words from this file and just
start at
but here is one limitation in Bob sweet
that we can add a list we can add a file
list but that's only available for a pro
version means we have to purchase a Bob
suite license or a pro version in order
to access that feature but for the time
in what we can do we can manually add
items in our list so let's just add here
demo dot PHP file name then admin dot
PHP success dot PHP secret dot PHP
hidden dot PHP and so on so forth like
just any random files dot PHP hit enter
so now what will happen is our Bob suite
will send the same request to the
Moutere web application and then check
it responds but it will send this
request by using these different pages
by adding here ok let's go back to our
payloads so now here you can see our
payloads has been selected so if I just
scroll down here you will see some
payload encodings so what we have to do
is we just have to remove this equals to
sign and here you can see that I have
removed this equals to sign now
everything is set now let's go here to
intruder and now click on start attack
click on OK and here you will see that
our Bob suite has started the interval
attack and now it's finished so here you
will see a request number payload it's
status code and its length so if I just
click over here demo dot PHP here you
will see it's request so here is the
same request but what's the difference
the difference is here if I just select
the admin you will see the admin file is
included in this request so if I just go
here demo dot PHP and now let's see that
is response versus response
so you can see the spoon squad is 200
okay now let's see the HTML content and
none let's just render the HTML content
let's see that how this page looks like
whether this page is present or not and
here you will see a 404 page not found
okay no worries now let's select this
admin dot PHP and here you will see that
we are successfully able to find a
secret page inside the mutilator web
application and here you will find we'll
just go here here you will see that a
secret PHP configuration page here you
can find a PHP configuration so most of
the time what the web developers do they
actually hide some important pages or
important directories from the user by
just changing their names so what an
attacker or a pen tester can do they can
just try to brute force or try to some
attack do any attack and just try to
guess that directories and here you can
see that what we are doing the same so
success dot PHP page not found and
secret dot PHP okay so here you can see
that we have found it another secret PHP
surfer configuration page hidden dot PHP
okay the same page seek a server and not
found and not found so this was how we
can try to guess a different pages which
are actually present on a web
application so if you want to add the
words from the file list then you have
to buy this Bob sweet Pro Edition and I
recommend you that if you are a
penetration tester working in any
InfoSec company or have a penetration
testing company then do by Bob sweet pro
version so in this video we have covered
their water security miss configuration
issues and how we can use the Bob sweet
intruder module to attack the MU tilde
web application and thanks for watching
this video