hello everyone now let's talk about SQL
injection so SQL injections are one of
the most popular server-side injection
attacks so in SQL injection attacker
tries to inject SQL query as input and
if the web application is not sanitizing
the user input then that Kure is being
executed on the database and if that
theory is successfully being executed on
the database then the attacker can dump
all the data from that database so with
the help of SQL injection the attacker
can insert something update something
and even delete something from that
remote database so SQL injection is of
various types like error by sequel
injection blind sequel injection time
based and boolean so depending upon the
SQL injection which attack I have found
so we can retrieve the data now let's
see how we can inject SQL experiece
inside the web applications now let's
see how sequel injection works in order
to test sequel injection vulnerability
we have to start our OS broken web
application so here you can see that the
OS broken up application is up and
running so let me open my Firefox and
let's start bricks burnable web
application which is inside OS bwa
so here you will find the OS bricks link
just click over that length let's go
here and let's select content pages so
here you will see there are total 6
content pages and all of them are
learnable to sequel injections but for
the time being for this course I will
cover this the content page 1 as the
basics 1 so let me open this up so as I
told you earlier that in this video I am
going to cover error base sequel
injection in which we will dump the
database through an sequel error so
before testing any application we first
have to find the logic behind that
application that how that application is
working and what kind of Curie's are
executing at the back end now let us try
to play with this application or with
this page so where you will see that
this page is showing the detail of users
user ID 0 and user name along with the
user email and here you will find a
sequel Curie which is being used for
retrieving this information as bricks is
a vulnerable web application so it's
showing us a sequel QT which is
executing at the back end but when you
will test the real-time web application
you will see nothing so if we look at
the URL here we find an additional
parameter called as ID and the value 0
is given to ID now let us try to give
any integer values
so it's giving us an error again that
user does not exist so the first part of
finding a sequel injection is to first
the application so what is the fuzzing
means the fuzzing means giving an weird
input to the web application so that we
can be able to break the sequel Curie
which is executing at the back end so
here you can see that I am I have given
and long integer values and alphanumeric
numbers but we are not able to break the
Curie so now what we can do if I just
write here ID equals 3 you will see a
user details which has ID 3 and much is
looking at this curie we can understand
that it's actually retrieving a data
from the database whose ID user is 3 now
in order to break the sequel Curie let's
add a single code and let's see what
happens so here you will see that we are
successfully able to break the sequel
Curie and here you can see the sequel
error now what are the other ways to
break the sequel queries we can also add
double quotes okay once again we are
able to break the query now instead of
double quotes we can add backslash so
backslash is used for escaping
characters in my sequel so here you can
see that backslash also works so
backslash single quote and double quotes
will work depends upon the application
logic because sometimes a single quote
will work and double code will not work
sometimes backslash will work and both
of them single quote and double quote
will not work so the main thing we have
to find is the application logic now
once we did with this once we completed
this part then the next step is
we have we have to try to remove this
error or we have to try to patch this
Curie but the condition should be the
single code should be remain present now
how to do so so just try an example so
here you can see a sequel error so let
me copy the last line of the sequel
error and let me paste it in my notepad
file and then we will analyze that how
this application is receiving our input
now instead of single quotes let's try
to add double quotes so let me copy this
line again and paste it in my notepad
file now let us add a backslash sign and
let's copy this thing and paste it here
so let me remove this extra characters
which we no need
so here is our input a single quote a
double quote and a backslash sign so let
me remove this limit run also so that we
can understand the logic better let me
give it so here you can see whatever
input I use that is giving the user
input is enclosed by two single quotes
here you can see so if I just give if I
just give one as an input then my one
will get enclosed in single quotes now
how we are able to break the sequel Kure
here you can see that we are able to
break the sequel puri but how it works
so let me write here a sample demo Kure
that is select star from table where
user ID equals and just for example this
is the query which is executing at the
back end single quotes again single
quote and here is our input ID number as
one so this is how our application is
treating our input so what our user is
giving is getting enclosed in these
single quotes so if we add a single
quote after one here you can see so if
we just add any single quote or a double
quote afters one so we are successfully
able to break the Kure how because here
you can see that now our application
will think that this Kure ends here due
to the single quote and this single
quote will remain as a empty this make
no sense so that is why we are able to
see this errors now how we can think of
to remove this errors so what if if the
user or rather our pen tester will add a
single quote before one also now what
will happen is we will successfully able
to make this curious and empty here you
can see there is a no value and between
this point we can execute our own sequel
curing so now let's do this thing so let
me just add a single code first okay now
before three let me add a single code
again and let's see how it works okay
so here you will see that we are
successfully able to remove the error
and here you can also see that our
single quotes are still present now the
next thing we have to do is we have to
comment out the rest of Tory so in order
to comment out the rest of Kure we can
just give two - signs and a plus sign so
here the plus sign is actually used for
giving a one speak one single space
because we are not interacting with the
database directly we are interacting
with the database through this front end
so there are some constants or rules
which we have to follow so that's why
after the these two comments we have to
give one space but we can use plus sign
because it's also used as a one space
and here at this point we can execute
our own sequel query and we'll try to
fetch out the data from database so in
order to check that whether we are able
to execute sequel query or not let's try
to write a sample and one one statement
so if I just write here and one equals
zero so this condition is not true one
equals zero so now if I just hit enter
you will see nothing user does not exist
but if I just enter here and one equals
one so here you will see that the
details comes back which means now we
are successfully able to execute sequel
query here now
let me open one notepad file and let's
just recap what we have discussed so the
first thing in order to find the sequel
injection is we have to find business we
have to find application logic so once
we find the application logic the next
step is we have to break the sequel
Curie through fuzzing so as I told you
earlier that fuzzing means giving a
weird input to the application and try
to break the application object so once
we are able to break the Curie the next
thing is to remove the error or to patch
sequel Curie till here at this point
remove the error and pass sequel GUI we
have completed this till here now the
next step is find out how many number of
columns are being used by this
application so now let's find that how
many columns are being used by this
application so in order to find columns
there is one function in my M my sequel
called as order by now let's use that
function so let's just write order by
and let's start with two so if I just
hit enters you will see nothing there is
no error which means there are two
columns which are being used by this web
application that's bricks now let's add
here five and let's see whether we got
an error or not okay there is no error
means there are five columns which are
being used now let's add here seven
so we have to go on increasing the
number so that we can able to find the
correct columns okay you can see there
is no error means there are seven
columns now let's add here nine okay so
here you will see that we got an error
and it's saying column 9 in order Clause
means there are total eight columns
which are present in the database of
bricks web application plus cross-check
so let's add here 8 and you will see a
no errors which means there are total 8
columns which are being used by this
bricks web application now the next step
is we will use a Union statement in
order to concatenate the previous Kure
so we want to execute this previous
query and our new Curie also so that is
why this function urine is used so I
will just write down here Union select
and all the column numbers so if I just
hit enter you will see there is no
errors which means this part is
executing successfully now the next
thing we have to do is so we have to
find that how many columns
are being used used by this application
for four hours Curie so now we know that
there there are total eight columns in
this BRICS database but now we want to
know that among these eight columns how
many columns are actually being used by
this curie so by just looking at the
details we can just do a guess that
there are three columns because there
are three values here you can see user
ID username and email so we can just
think of that out of eight columns there
are total three columns which are being
used by this BRICS web application or in
this curie a single disk uri now in
order to cross check that how many
columns are working what we have to do
is so here you can see our ID and we
have given a three value so let's give
any random value or any fixed value let
me just give here six seven all wrong
value and hit enter and let's see what
happened so here you will see that
instead of user ID username and email
we'll see here one two and three which
means the first three columns are being
used by this application and for this
page where we are currently writing now
we got our execution point now what we
can do is so we first of all we can find
a database name by using database
function instead of the first column so
now if I just hit enter you will find
the database name and the database name
is bricks so we can also execute any
sequel command in the place of the
second column because the first second
and third columns are being used so now
let's find the user name of this
database by writing user and two
parentheses and add here the second
and you can see the username s bricks at
the rate localhost now let us try to
find the database path by writing at the
rate at the rate data dia hit enter and
in the third one you will see the
database directory which is where slash
lip slash my sequel now the next step is
we have to find the table name because
now we know that what's the database
name the database name is bricks so let
me open one more notepad file and let's
write here that what we have retrieved
so database name we have found it is
database name is bricks let's go here so
the next thing we have to do is we have
to find the table name we have to find
the table name now let me write as Curie
let me write a simple query which we
will use in order to find the table name
so here is the Curie select table
underscore name from informations
underscore schema dot
where table underscore schema equals our
database name which is bricks in our
case so by just looking at this Curie we
can come to know that this means select
table name from information schema dot
tables where table schema is our
database name so if you are new to my
sequel and you don't know that what's
the information schema so let me just
tell you that what's the information
schema is so information schema is
actual standard way to store and
retrieve the data in database so it's
also an a generic template which all the
web developers I have to follow while
creating there
databases so now let's try to execute
this query and let's see whether we are
able to find the table names which is
present inside this BRICS web
application or not so let me remove this
database user data dir
okay there is one error let's find okay
so I remove this select statement okay
so now there is no error now let's try
to execute this Curie so I have already
written Union select so let's started
from table underscore name now we have
we will write this table underscore name
only in the first column so this will
display here and the rest of the query
we have to write after eight so table
name from from information underscore
schema dot
where table underscore schema equals the
database name which is bricks now if I
just hit enter we will see that we are
successfully able to retrieve the
database name sorry the table name which
is users here you can see the table name
users now as we know that the database
contains lot of tables so but here we
can see only a one table that is users
so in order to find all the table names
which is present inside this application
there are two ways the first one is we
can use limit function and the second
one is we can use group concat function
so let's see that how group concat
function works so before table name just
write down group underscore concat and
let's enclose this table name inside
these parentheses hit enter
and here you can see that we are still
able to see this user stable name which
means there is only one table which is
present inside this BRICS database so
let us go back to a notepad file so we
are successfully able to retrieve the
database name which is BRICS and the
table name which we found is users now
let us go back so now we are
successfully able to find the database
name and the table name none the next
thing we can find this we can find the
column number column names so in order
to find column names which is present
inside that users tables what is the
sequel query so the QT for finding the
column name is select column underscore
name from information underscore schema
dot-coms
where table underscore name equals the
table name which we found which is users
so this is a sequel query which we will
use to find out the column names so let
me edit this previous query so instead
of table name let me just write down
here column name and here you can see
that I am still using this group concat
function which means this function will
display all the column names which is
which is present inside this bricks web
application database so from information
schema dot columns where table
underscore name equals users
now if I just hit enter here you will
find a detail a long list of columns
which are present inside the user table
of bricks web application database you
can see there are long list of the
columns including user name password
user ID log names password again first
name last name user ID admin reset code
and so on so forth let me just go back
here so now we are successfully able to
find the column names and the database
name and the table name now what we can
do is we can set out the data which is
present inside a particular column name
like if you want to fetch the email ids
which is present inside this email
column then our theory is very simple so
the curie is select email so you have to
write down select followed by the column
name
this is email select email from and we
here we have to write down the table
name which is users so it's a very small
curie you can see here so let me write
here select email inside the group
concat because i want to retrieve all
the emails so email from users so let me
move this long curie from users which is
our table name now if i just hit enter
you will see all the email accounts
which are associated with this database
you can see Tom Ron and Harry
so same like email we can also find the
passwords of these accounts
okay
I think the passwords is not a correct
name of a column it's password okay and
here you will see the password admin Tom
Ron and it's kind of some hash so now
you can find out all that data which is
present in different different columns
by distributing this curing so this was
whole the process of sequel injection
that how we can execute a sequel query
and we can dump the data from the
database so in this video we have
covered their virtual sequel injection
and how we can find a sequel injection
vulnerability and web application and
how we can retrieve data from sequel
injection vulnerability thanks for
watching this video