hello everyone now let us talk about
XPath injections so x5 injections are
similar to SQL injection so in SQL
injection user-supplied input becomes a
part of SQL query
whereas in XPath injection user supplied
input becomes the path of XPath query so
if the user will supply a malformed
input then that can result into access
of restricted file contents so let's see
how XPath injection works now let's see
how XPath injection works so in order to
test XPath injection we have to download
this another one never web application
which is extremely vulnerable web
application xvw a so you can download
this application from this link so once
you download this application you have
to extract the file and then you can
host this application in your localhost
server of Kali Linux so here you can see
that I have already hosted this
application on my local o server and
it's up and running so this is how this
application looks like this application
also contains different kind of
vulnerabilities which you can test but
for the time being we are interested
only in XPath so here is the link of
that page X Box injection let's open
this page so here you can see a search
bar and here it is written search your
coffee so let's delete the previous
input so here is mentioned search by ID
so just for example let's hit enter here
one so here you can see that it has
displayed the item the ID is one so if
we change the ID let's change it to
three so where you can see that it has
displayed the item 3 which has ID 3 now
as I told you earlier that XPath
injection LDAP injection sequel
injection all kind of injection are
somehow same but instead of executing a
sequel query at the back end what
this Exim XPath do it actually receives
the input from the user which we are
just giving so it takes the user input
and forms a XML curie at the backend so
when the user input is not sanitized
properly what malicious can malicious
attacker can do they actually send the
malicious Curie and with the help of
that curie we are able to display all
the XML data here now let's try to read
the page source of this challenge now
let's have a look at the page source of
this challenge so here you can see that
right now I am inside the xvw a path and
if I do LS here is a file home dot PHP
which is responsible for taking our
input so let's see what inside this file
so here you can see it's a PHP file and
if I scroll down here is our XPath QT
which you can see this is XPath query
and it's whatever input is given by user
is just placed here and the curie
becomes slash coffees slash coffee and
ids the user input so if this input is
not sanitized properly then a user can
able to retrieve all the XML data now
let us go back to this challenge and let
us try to add here a sequel injection
payload which we used to bypass login
pages so it was or equals 1 now if we
just click on search you will see that
we are able to retrieve all the data all
the XML data here in front of us
so this is how the XPath injection works
with a little difference that instead of
forming a my sequel query it forms the
XPath query and retrieves the XML data
so in this video we have covered that
what is XPath injection and how XPath
injection works thanks for watching this
video