hello everyone now let us talk about
Metasploit framework so a Metasploit
framework is a tool used for penetration
testing exploit research and exploiting
the systems and vulnerabilities and
network so Metasploit framework is an
open-source tool and it's written in
ruby which means if you know the Ruby
language and you know how you can write
codes in Ruby then you can contribute
the Metasploit framework and meta spread
framework contains more than 1,200
exploits 330 plus payloads and 30 plus
encoders so before going further let us
talk about some important terms which we
will use in this entire video so these
important terms are vulnerability
exploit and payload so what is
vulnerability so as I told you earlier
that vulnerability is a flow or a
weakness in the system which let an
attacker to compromise the system and
what's the expert so exploit is the code
which an attacker use in order to
exploit that vulnerability and gets into
the system now what's the payload so
payload is defined as the activities
which one can perform once we are inside
a system
just for example we found one
vulnerability and we also found one code
which we will use in order to exploit
that vulnerability then once we are
inside the system then what kind of
activities we can perform can be defined
as the payload which we will use while
exploiting the target so now let us go
further so now let's discuss about
Metasploit architecture that how
Metasploit framework is organized
internally so here you can see that
matters here are the Metasploit
framework modules and here on Metasploit
interfaces and here are some libraries
so modules contains different kind of
directories which contains payloads
exploits auxilary modules encoders and
so on so what I am Metasploit interfaces
I will discuss in upcoming slide and
here you can see the Metasploit
libraries which contains different
Metasploit framework functions like MSF
base library MSF core libraries plugins
and so on so now let's discuss
about Metasploit real-life scenario so
what is Metasploit real-life scenario
what it means so it means that how
penetration testers use Metasploit in
real-life scenario or in real in real
time in order to penetrate into the
systems so in order to use Metasploit
there are three steps so the first step
is we will find open ports services and
their version numbers running on a
remote system so once we found open
ports and services running on them
then we'll try to find the version
numbers of that services and once we got
the version number what we'll do
we'll try to find exploit in Metasploit
framework database correspond to that
version number which we found and if
that exploit is present inside the
Metasploit framework database then we
will use that exploit in order to
exploit that system so this is a
Metasploit real life scenario which
every penetration tester follows now let
us discuss about Metasploit interfaces
so Metasploit interfaces are nothing but
just a different different ways in order
to use Metasploit so the first two
interfaces Metasploit web so by using
Metasploit web we can access Metasploit
by using browsers like Google Chrome
Mozilla Firefox and there is one another
interface called as Armitage so Armitage
is an Metasploit framework GUI
application which provides GUI features
whereas the last Metasploit interfaces
command line so by using command line
interface we can access Metasploit
framework through our Kali Linux
terminal and in order to use Metasploit
framework command line we have to write
MSF console in our Kali Linux terminal
now let's see how we can use Metasploit
by using MSF console now let's see that
how we can use Metasploit framework
through MSF console so to do that we
have to start our Kali Linux and I have
already started my Colin Linux and here
you can see my Kali Linux instance and
here is the Kali terminal so in order to
start Metasploit framework we have to
write here
MSF console
and here you can see that right now we
are inside Metasploit framework shell
well I told you earlier that what will
be our scenario our scenario will be
that as a penetration tester we will
first find open ports along with the
version number and services then once we
find the open ports we have to find a
particular exploit correspond to that
version number and if that exploit exist
in Metasploit framework database then
we'll use that exploit and try to
exploit the system so here you can see
that my Metasploit level linux is up and
running and it's IP is 192.168.1.1 o6
now what I'm going to do is I'm scanning
the open ports of Metasploit table Linux
through and map and I am performing
service scan you can see here and let me
just write down the IP address of my
display table Linux hit enter this will
take a little bit time because
Metasploit a linux contains lot of
vulnerabilities so that's why more than
10 or 15 ports will be open so that's
why on map will scan entire ports and
will try to fetch all their services and
their version number so we have to wait
for a time being and here you can see
the list of open ports their services
and their version number so for the time
being let's focus on this port port 21
and service you can just see here FTP
and their version is vs FTP D 2.3.4 okay
now we got the service services and the
version number now let's search a
particular exploit in the Metasploit
framework database of with this name vs
FTP D 2.3.4 and in order to search any
exploit and Metasploit framework
database we have to just right here
search followed by the exploit name or
the version name so vs FTP D and the
version name which is 2.3.4 and hit
enter so if the exploit exist in the
Metasploit framework directory or the
database then we can exploit the system
otherwise we cannot exploit the system
but as a pentester if you know how you
can make exploit then you can make a
particular exploit and can use that
exploit okay and but here is the already
n exploit which is present in the
Metasploit framework database you can
check its name so in order to use this
exploit just right down here use and
copy the exploit name so this exploit is
inside exploit Unix FTP directory and
this is the exploit name vs FTP D 2 3 4
backdoor let me use this and here you
can also see that disclosure date the
rank is excellent and the description
hit enter so once you hit enter you will
see that you are inside the exploit so
once we are inside the exploit the next
thing is we have to set our exploit so
how we can set our exploit that it will
triggers to Metasploit able framework so
what we can do is we will first find the
options we have to give so in order to
find that what kind of option this
exploit wants just write down show
options hit enter
so right now there are two options our
host and our port in which this exploit
wants so our port is pre default set you
can just see here 21 all we have to do
is we just have to set the
our host so what's the our host our host
is a remote host so we have to set the
IP address of Metis palatable Linux and
in order to set our host we have to
write down set our host space and IP
address so instead of IP address you can
also type the domain name so I have said
in my our host now let's check the
options again and here you can see that
my our host is set now all I have to do
is I have to write exploit or even you
can just write run and hit enter okay
now we have exploit Lee to the system
you can just see here backdoor service
has been spawned and found a shell
command shell open session 1 now we are
inside the shell of Metasploit a table
Linux means as a pen tester we have
gained the access of this Metasploit
table Linux through Metasploit framework
and you can just check here if I just
write here who are who are who am I so
it will give us the output just below
our command
so root we are root okay so let's print
out the working directory okay
is this and let's check the file listing
so these are the files and directories
which are present inside the Metasploit
table Linux just for us ensure that
whether we are inside a correct shell
let's create an demo directory so let's
create a directory named as demo hit
enter now let's go back to my disputable
Linux let's write here LS and let's see
whether our demo directory has been
created or not if I just write LS and
here you can see that this is a demo
directory which we have just created
through Metasploit framework and if you
just want to come back you can just
right exit
so once you exit your command session
will be closed now in order to protect
your server from Metasploit framework
the best practice is to close the pores
and hide their version number if that
port is not in the use it's the best
practice so thanks for watching this
video