hello everyone now let's talk about
showed on dot IO so showed on is one of
the most popular search engine used to
find devices which are connected over
the Internet
so with the help of Sudan we can find
IOT devices like webcams routers Scala
systems power plants and so on so forth
so Sudan is different from Google
because the Google finds the webpages
but whereas Sudan tries to find the
devices which are connected over the
public IP addresses so with the help of
Sudan we will see that how we can find a
public IP devices like web temps and
SCADA systems for more information you
can visit their official website that is
www.binaryoptionsgain.com or example
let's write down here web cam and you
can see that it will list out all the
webcams available around the globe along
with the IP address so here you can see
a web cam let me just open it in a new
tab and be sure that what you are doing
on the Sherando tayo ok so let me just
click over here on the browser ok so
here you can see that we are watching
this web cam also why because it's open
in order to protect your devices on the
public IP is to add the authentication
so by writing the web cam you can see
here it's showing us the details of the
web cam around the globe and on the left
hand side it's highlighting the
countries of which it's showing us the
result if you just scroll down
you can see the result so instead of
webcam we can also find the Cisco
routers the public Cisco routers of with
the public IP address and you can see
here the router details along with IP
address and their country like Thailand
Hong Kong United States so we can so you
can also find a particular device also
like you want to find the device of
Netgear so just right on that gear and
hit enter so here you can find the
details of the Netcare device so this
was all about the basic usage of show
don know what if if you want to find a
webcam but in a particular country then
what you will do is there any filters
which we can use yes so there are
filters which can be used inside the
show Don to get a particular device
according to our filter now just for
example you want to find a webcam which
are available in the city of New York so
we what we can do is we can use a filter
called a city then colon and inside the
double quote we have to write the city
name I just for example I am writing a
New York here and if I hit enter and
here you can see that the Sudan has
listed out all the webcams along with
their IP and here you can see that the
city is New York so what we can do is we
can also add a filter called as country
so country so let it be Canada so I am
just writing your CA so the thing to be
noticed is that if you want to add a
country filter so you don't have to
write a full name of a country so you
have to just write a short code of your
country like Canada and the short code
is
see a so apart from country apart from
city you can also add a filter of
operating system like OS and OS should
be Linux so it will list out all the
operating system and all the devices
which are running on the this operating
system Linux in the country Canada let
me just remove this filter country
filter and now let me just hit enter
okay and here you can see that it has
listed out all the IPS and all the
devices which are running on Linux here
you can see the Linux version Linux 3
point X and the country is Canada so now
apart from operating system you can also
add a filter of port like if you want to
find a particular port number or device
which is running on a particular port
number then you can by writing a port
followed by the port number so just for
example I have written here port 443 let
me hit enter and let's see what we get
ok so here you can see that it has
listed out all the devices which are
running on the port 443 and their port
port port 443 is open and as we all know
that port 443 is a HTTP port so here you
can see it SSL certificate detail and
you can also check this header the HTTP
header also so the HTTP response code is
200 then date connection X frame and
content length so the thing to be
noticed that you can only use filters if
you are login in sudan dot io so make
sure to login then you can use these
filters so this was all about sudan and
in the last be sure
that what you are doing on show Don so
thanks for watching this video