hello everyone now let's talk about
buffer overflow so buffer overflow is a
condition when user supplied input is
more than the memory allocated to that
user so that extra input which is
provided by user actually overwrite some
memory fragments so which results in
unexpected errors and unexpected working
of that web application so the different
types of buffer overflows are stack
overflow and heap overflow now let's see
how buffer overflow works then web
application now let's see how buffer
overflow attack occurs so as I told you
earlier that if the user input is given
more than the memory allocated to the
web application then the web application
will throw an error and through that
error sometime the web application might
reveals some interesting information
which user can use so in order to test
buffer overflow vulnerability we have to
start our OS broken web application and
here you can see it's up and running now
let me open my Firefox so the one more
thing you have to do is you have to
install this add-on called as web
developer so once you install this
add-on this add-on will comes like this
bar so once you install this add-on
let's open our OS broken web application
so let's go here over ASP web good so
once you click over here it asks us for
the username and password which is guest
guest but now I am already authenticated
and I'm logged in you can see here so in
order to test buffer overflow just click
over here at buffer overflow and this
challenge off-by-one overflow so if we
just look at this page it asks us for
the registration for a membership
registration here you can see so the
first name let's test it for the first
time Sharat Kumar and the room number
should be anything so now if I just
click on submit
here you will see that it's giving us
the available price plan list so let's
accept anything and now let's click on
accept terms and here you will see
nothing so here just it's saying we
would like to thank you for the payment
but what we have to do is we have to try
to exploit this webpage by giving input
in a very large number so the one more
thing we we have to do is let's go here
forms and now let's click over here
display forms details and here you will
see that this contains a hidden input
field you can see the hidden input field
so it's a form hidden input field now if
I just go back here and uncheck this you
will see nothing so let's go back here
now as a pen tester what we can do is so
we can just give any name and here in a
room number because the rule number
might be an integer so what we can do is
we can give a random room number a long
room number list which might cause and
buffer overflow so let me go back so on
my desktop you can see this file which
is six thousand numbers so this file
contains six thousand digits so let me
copy this file so I have copied all the
digits let me just go back here and let
me paste it and now let me click on
submit and now let's see that what kind
of hidden fields this page contains so
here you will see that this is the input
field which you can see and these threes
are hidden fields now if I just click on
accept terms so here you will see that
congratulations you have successfully
completed installation which means we
are successfully able to hit the memory
fragment which was outside the allocated
memory now if you just go here forms and
now if I you just
here display formfields here you will
see that we are successfully able to
find the information of different users
which have already registered to this
web application here you can see the
user details like Lewis Hamilton Anna
Smith and Ravan and so on so this was
the basic example that how buffer
overflow attack works so in this video
we have covered that what's a buffer
overflow attack and in the last we have
seen that how we can exploit buffer
overflow vulnerability and webgoat
thanks for watching this video