hello everyone now let us talk about
insecure direct object reference
vulnerability so this vulnerability also
referred as I do be so before going
further let me give you an example that
there are five objects or a five files
and there is one another file called as
demo so we can access all that five
objects if our request contains
reference of that demo file and if we
want to try to access that fife object
without the reference of the demo file
we are not able to access that objects
now what happen is an insecure direct
object reference the user supplied input
is used to access a particular object
and if the user adds something malicious
so that it can point to something
different object and so which means a
user tries to access a particular object
which he is not authorized to access to
so if the user is successfully able to
access that object which means that will
replication is insecure direct object
reference vulnerable so here is one HTTP
request you can see here and this
request is accepting one parameter
called as page and here is the page name
source viewer dot PHP so this is this is
our reference page and here you can see
the another argument or the another
parameter called as PHP file and the PHP
file which we are try to access is
called as user Paul dot PHP so we can
try this user Paul dot PHP if we are
making HTTP request with the reference
of this file source via dot PHP now
let's see how insecure direct object
reference works now let's see that how
direct object reference works then we
will able to exploit insecure direct
object reference vulnerability so in
order to test that vulnerability and to
see that how it works we have to start
our OS broken web application and we
have to open mutilate a
and here you can see the ovis mutilate a
link let me open this up so let's go
here
os 2013 and here you will found the
insecure direct object reference so
let's open the second challenge that is
source viewer now let's have a look at
the functionality of this page that what
it's doing so to see the source of the
file choose and click a view file so if
I if we just go here you can see that
there are a lot of PHP files here so if
we want to look at the source code of
any of them just select any of the file
and click on view file and here at the
bottom you can see the source code of
this file now let's try to analyze this
request through Bob sweet and let's see
that how this request is going on so I'm
starting my Bob sweet here and let me
also configure my proxy settings on my
browser
so manual proxy configuration is the
localhost IP and the port is 8080 let me
click on okay let me go back just go
here and start prop
so let's select any file in order to
read it source code click on view file
and you will see that Bob suite will
start blinking let's go here to the
proxy tab and here is the full request
which is going through our browser so
it's a post request and you can see that
the request is going to this link so
here is the page source for dot PHP it's
the page where we are writen you can see
here now let's go back so here is the
HTTP header
it's a host information user agent then
content length then referrer and at the
bottom here you will find the
interesting information which give us an
idea of how direct object reference
works so if we just look at here at the
first here it is written page and the
value of the pages source viewer dot PHP
which is this one and then it's an
additional parameter PHP file which you
can see here and the PHP file name is
the file name which we want to see here
you can see that we have selected user
pol dot PHP and here it is that present
so which means this page source for dot
PHP this one is actually acting as a
reference or ephra in order to view the
content of this page means if we want to
look at the page source of any of these
files then we can only able to look at
the page source if our reference is
given by this file source for your dis
file if this file is given as a
reference then we can able to look at
the source code of these files now let
me just click on forward and let's see
that whether we are able to see the
source code and here you can see that
here is the source code of the file now
as I told you earlier that what is
insecure direct object reference so
which means there are some files which
are not be authorized to view by some
another person means we are not
authorized to have a look at the source
code of that files
so what we can do in order to test that
whether this application is vulnerable
to unsecure direct object reference we
can try to view the page source of
different pages which are not listed
here you can see the list but the index
dot PHP page is not here so now let's
try to look at the page source of index
dot PHP and let's see that whether we
are able to view the source code of
index dot PHP and if we are able to view
the page source which means this link or
this web page is insecure direct object
reference burnable so let me click on
view profile again if you file and you
can see my buffs would start blinking
and here is that request again
now instead of upload file dot PHP let's
try to write index dot PHP and let's see
what happened click on forward forward
again let me go back here and here you
can see that we are successfully able to
view the page source of index dot PHP
file so we are not authorized to view
the page source but still we can able to
view the page source due to insecure
object reference so now let's try to
view the page source of this page itself
where we are right in so right now we
are on this page source via dot PHP
which actually letting us to view the
page source of different file so why not
we find the page source of this file
itself now let us try to do so let's go
here so let me just try it in the PHP
file parameter source viewer dot PHP
and if I just click on forward if I just
go back and here you can see the file is
source viewer dot PHP and we can able to
look at the paid source of this page
itself so this was how the insecure
direct object reference works so in this
video we have covered that what is
insecure direct object reference and how
we can exploit that thanks for watching
this video
you