hello everyone now let's talk about Bob
sweet so Bob sweet is one of the most
popular security testing tool so we can
use Bob sweet in order to intercept our
HTTP requests which is going out through
our web browser so Bob sweet contains
different different tabs and each and
different tab contains different
different functions
so the Bob suite contains tabs like
proxies intruders scanners so the proxy
tab is used for intercepting our
requests and it's a proxy function so
integral tab contains a different
different attacks which we can perform
on a remote website like we want to
perform a dictionary attack brute force
attack and the scanner module or scanner
tab in Bob suite is used for scanning
particular website and its vulnerability
there is one more interesting tab in Bob
suite called as decoder so the decoder
contains different kind of functions
which we can use in order to decode a
particular thing like URL decode basic
tifo decode so Bob suite is available in
two versions pro and free so the in kali
linux the Bob suite is already install
and it's a free version and if you are a
penetration tester so you can use Bob
suite as a pro version because it
contains more feature than free one so
Bob suite is freely available for Linux
Mac and Windows now let's see how we can
intercept our HTTP request by using Bob
suite now let's see that how we can use
burp suite inside Kali Linux and windows
so by default the Bob suite is installed
in Kali Linux and if we are looking to
use Bob suite in Windows then you can
download from their official website and
right now you can see that I am inside
my Kali Linux instance and on the left
hand side you will see this icon so this
is the Bob suite so let me just click
over hit and you can see it's a Bob
suite free edition so I'm using Bob
suite free edition so when the first
time you will use the Bob suite
so it asked us for this temporary
project and/or if you want to create a
new project so click on next
use Bob defaults and start Bob so this
is how the Bob Suite menu looks like
here you can see the different different
tabs and they have different different
functions like proxy tab is used for
intercepting our request then spider
used for crawler crawling the website
scanning the website intruder is used
for performing different attacks brute
force attack can different password
guessing attacks the repeater is used to
repeat our request then decoder is used
to decode the strings like basics T for
decode and URL encoding URL decoding
then there are some another options so
right now we are just interested on this
option proxy because we want to
intercept our request which is going out
from our browser and once we are here in
this tab proxy click on this options and
here you can see that our Bob suite is
up and running on this IP 127.0.0.1
that's a local host and port is 8080 now
what we have to do is we have to
configure our browser now let me open
this Firefox browser so in order to
configure the browser we have to go here
preference then advanced and here is the
network settings so we have to configure
the network settings and here so by
default when you will just open the
settings it will just like this you
system proxy so we have to click over
here manual proxy configuration and we
have to fill the IP address of the Bob
suite along with its port number and we
have to select this use this proxy
server for all protocols click on OK ok
now our Bob suite has been configured
now every request which will go out from
our browser will first go to the Bob
suite
and there we can intercept our request
and if we want to do some modification
we can then we can forward the request
to the server now just for example let
me just intercept this request
tutorialspoint.com and here you can see
I have requested tutorialspoint.com and
it's waiting now let me open my Bob
suite and okay this one is the request
of clients dot Google com let me just
forward it up okay and here you can see
the entire request so HTTP method is get
it's an HTTP version host is
tutorialspoint.com and here you can also
check the user agent and if you just
click on headers you can see here the
header name and its value and if you
just want to see the hex value of this
request so here is the hex value and if
you just click on forward then it will
forward our request otherwise you will
just click on drop then it will here you
can see that our request is dropped by
user Bob sweet error now by default the
Bob sweet is configured to intercept the
request which is using HTTP protocol now
what if if a particular website is
running on HTTPS then our Bob suite will
unable to intercept the request so to
configure the Bob suite to intercept the
HTTP request so what we can do is we
have to install Bob Suites our
certificate so in the URL bar just write
down HTTP but hit enter and here you can
see the Bob sweet menu and on the right
hand side at the top you can see here
see a certificate so click on this link
and here is the Bob certificate so just
save this file and open this file so
this is the Bob sweet certificate you
can see here so and if you just want to
look at the detail you can so this
certificate is verified and issued by
ports figure which is the company that
maintains the Bob sweet
and if I scroll down you can see the
issuer name issuer country then
certificate serial number certificate
fingerprints along with it hashes and
here you can see the fingerprint of
public key now just click on import and
we have two right here password okay
click on OK and here you can see that
our certificate is successfully imported
let me just close the certificate now
and let me just write here tutorial
smart again let me just forward is
forward this request ok here you can see
it still HTTP request no HTTP here you
can see it says TTP but forward this and
it will be redirected to the HTTPS you
have to wait for a time being
okay so this will give this error so
click on advanced and add exception
click on confirm security exception and
now here you can see that our Bob suite
can intercept HTTP traffic here you can
see the HTTPS along with this lock sign
and if you just want to look at its
header you can click on forward and here
is the HTTP website so the same thing
you can do in order to intercept the
request of Facebook or any other social
website or any other website which
running on HTTPS and here if you just go
to STP history you can see the our
recent stdp request which was made by
the user so let me just turn off it
intercept and close the Bob suite so
once we close a Bob suite and if I just
open any web site you will see the proxy
service is refusing the connections so
this we will see this error
whenever Bob speed is not running so we
have to change our settings again back
to use system proxy now this will work
here you can see
despite the short introduction of Bob
sweet
so thanks for watching this video