hello everyone in this video we'll talk
about VirtualBox so what is VirtualBox
so VirtualBox is one of the best
virtualization software used in a small
computers so VirtualBox is made by
Oracle so it's freely available for
Linux Mac and Windows so it's the first
thing we need in order to setup our
testing lab so for more details you can
check their official websites and you
can download the VirtualBox from here
from this link and now let's see that
how we can install VirtualBox in our
system now let's see that how we can
install VirtualBox in our operating
system so here you can see that right
now I am at VirtualBox dot R and here
are different download links so
depending upon your pairing system you
can download one of them so I have
already downloaded the VirtualBox setup
which you can see on my desktop so I'm
let's double click on it ok click on
next next ok so now it asked for the
various things like you want to create a
shortcut in a quick launch bar you want
to create a shortcut on desktop so
uncheck these two click on next
ok yes and install
okay now click on finish' and it will
start VirtualBox for us ok so here you
can see that the system first menu of
the Oracle VM VirtualBox so here are
some few options like file machine help
so by clicking on new we can create a
new virtual machine and by clicking on
file we can import our appliance and we
can export an appliance so here you can
also change some network settings so
this was all about this video so in the
next video I will show you that how we
can install Kali Linux inside the
VirtualBox thanks for watching this
video