hello everyone in this video we'll going
to know about penetration testing and
vulnerability assessment so before going
deep into penetration testing and verne
ability cess meant first of all let us
know that what is vulnerability so
what's our nobility it's actually a flow
or a weakness in the system which let
the attacker to compromise their system
or in the short sense it's actually just
kind of flow through which attacker can
compromise your system or hack your
system now what is vulnerability
assessment so vulnerability assessment
is an important technique which ensures
that our system is secure
now what's this technique is what's this
process so this process is actually
identifying the vulnerability making the
points that where it was found and in
the last making a report of it so this
is a process of identifying quantifying
and making a report of the
vulnerabilities and by telling the
organization that what's the security
impact of these vulnerabilities now
what's a penetration testing so
penetration testing is an extended
process of a vulnerability assessment so
as I told you that in vulnerability
assessment we'll find the
vulnerabilities will scan the
vulnerabilities will measure the
vulnerabilities but in penetration
testing we'll try to exploit the
vulnerabilities we'll try to get the
access of the system so that's why
penetration testing is called as
extended process of the vulnerability
assessment so it's a process of
evaluating exploiting the
vulnerabilities and in the last making a
report of it so it's an extended process
of our nobility so what it includes it
includes scanning in AM rating
exploiting and reporting the
vulnerabilities and their security
issues so how does this process going so
on what are the steps to perform the
penetration test so the first step is
scanning so scanning includes scanning
different targets different websites
different techniques so once we scan the
open ports like open services running
and the version number
we'll do one ability assessment so here
you came to know that vulnerability
assessment is actually a part of a
penetration testing so once we perform
the vulnerability assessment then the
next step is to exploit the
vulnerabilities so once we exploit the
vulnerabilities
we'll make a report and we'll submit
that report to an organization so
penetration testing and vulnerability
assessment are actually two important
techniques which ensures to any
organization that the network is secure
so in every organization in their
premises actually conduct penetration
testing and vulnerability assessment to
secure the network so now let's have a
look at the difference between
penetration testing and Virna build
assessment as I told you earlier that
these two techniques are actually a part
of vulnerability management process so
penetration testing is actually
exploiting the vulnerabilities and
vulnerability assessment is just making
a report and just identifying the
vulnerabilities so it's extended process
it's a small process and in the last it
includes exploiting and it includes
telling the impact of the
vulnerabilities so this was all about
penetration testing and vulnerability
assessment so in this video we have
covered that what is vulnerability
assessment penetration testing and the
difference so thanks for watching this
video