hello everyone now let's talk about
unvalidated redirects so anomaly dating
redirects vulnerabilities are one of the
most popular vulnerabilities and are
often found in order web applications so
before going further let's talk about
redirects so what are redirects so
redirects takes users from one web page
to another web page or sometimes from
one web application to another web
application so sometimes it's necessary
to redirect user from one web page to
another example is login pages so these
kind of vulnerabilities are often found
on e-commerce websites where redirection
occurs while the time of payment or
while checkout example we purchase one
thing and if we want to pay the money so
we can abuse the functionality of
unvalidated redirects so now let's see
how unvalidated redirects works now
let's see that how unvalidated redirects
work and here you can see that right now
I am on OS muted a web application let's
go here over 2013 and in the last you
will see a section of unvalidated
redirects and forwards so let me just
open the first page credit okay
so right now you can see that we are on
this page credits and on this page you
will see a lot of hyperlinks so as I
told you earlier that in unvalidated
redirect vulnerability what is our goal
our goal is actually to redirect the
user to some another website so just for
example if I just copy this link and if
I just open this link you will see that
we we just get redirected to a
particular website which is just
mentioned in this hyperlink you can see
here so let me just go back
and let me just paste this link so if if
we read this link carefully so here you
will see that it's accepting an another
parameter called as forward URL and here
is the URL to which we just gets
redirected if we just click on that link
so our main goal of unvalidated redirect
says to try to redirect the user to some
different website just for example if I
just write here tutorialspoint.com and
now if I just hit enter and if I am just
able to redirect to tutorialspoint.com
which means this length is unvalidated
redirects vulnerable and this web
application is unallocated redirects
vulnerable and here you can see that
here we are successfully able to
redirect user to some another website so
this is because of a poor user sanitized
input and there is no database check for
this redirection so in this video we
have covered that what is unvalidated
redirects vulnerability and how a normal
unrelated redirect works so thanks for
watching this video