hello everyone now let us talk about
sessions so what are sessions so
sessions are server-side storage
information which is present till a user
is interacting with that web application
or with that server now how that
information is stored on that server
what kind of information it is so the
information which is stored on a server
till the user is interacting with that
web application is in the form of
session IDs so what are session IDs a
session ID is a long random alphanumeric
string which uniquely identifies users
on that website means every single user
contains different different session IDs
and how that session IDs are derived are
depend upon the web application logic so
sometimes what happen is the session IDs
are also stored inside cookies so the
important characteristics of every good
session ID should be it should be random
the second one is it should be long and
it should be alphanumeric now what are
the difference between session ID and
cookies so cookie is stored on a client
site through browser and the sessions
are stored on server sites so in cookie
we can see the data which is inside the
cookie in the form of name and value
pairs whereas in session IDs we can see
our data so that the session IDs are
secure whereas the cookies are not
secure and it can be stolen by using
JavaScript
now let's see how we can use Bob suite
in order to find the session IDs now
let's do some session ID analysis so in
order to see how session ID looks like
what we have to do is we first have to
set up our Bob suite and here you can
see that right now I am inside my Kali
Linux instance let me configure my Bob
suite so that we can intercept the
request because most of the times the
session ID is present in our HTTP
request but some of the application may
store session IDs in the form of cookies
in our browser so here is my Bob suite
and let me also open my Firefox and we
know that the buff suite runs on this IP
localhost IP and the port is 8080 and
let me configure my firefox browser
proxy settings by gluing going here
preferences advanced network and network
settings so manual proxy configuration
so this is the Bob suite proxy IP and
here's the port number let me click on
ok and here let's open
tutorialspoint.com ok so the first one
request is a simple HTTP request it's
not send HTTP so let me forward this ok
let's go here to tell connect advanced
let's accept this exception and now you
can see that our Bob suit will intercept
HTTP request off tutorialspoint.com here
you can see now the request is HTTP
request and here you can see the cookie
some different kind of cookies okay let
me forward this ok and if you read this
request here is an additional
information called as PHP session ID so
by just looking at this at the first
glance we can say that this is a session
ID because Harrah's written this PHP
session ID so this is how the session ID
looks like a long random string and
alphanumeric string so in the most of
the web application if I talk about
Google Facebook if you intercept the
request you will found a hell of a
detail a lot of details containing these
kind of IDs differen different IDs so
then that time it will be very very
difficult to distinguish that what us
what are the session IDs and what are
the different and other IDs but here at
the first glance we can say that
this is session ID because most of the
times the word developer do so what they
do is they actually change this
parameter name to any different name so
just for example if there is written
UTMC and another if there is written XYZ
instead of PHP session ID then you can
just think of that how difficult it is
to analyze that what our session IDs
among these all of them so finding a
right PHP session ID or any different
any other session ID is also very tricky
task so in this video we have covered
that what a session ID how session arey
looks like characteristics of a good
session ID and thanks for watching this
video