hello everyone now let us talk about
netcat so netcat is also called as
tcp/ip Swiss Army knife and netcat is
used for transferring the data by using
tcp/ip protocol so we can read and write
data by using tcp/ip protocol and netcat
so by using netcat we can make a
connection with any server website or
any networking device so netcat has also
has ability in order to connect on a
particular port which means by using
netcat we can even connect on a
particular port on a remote server and
the main feature of netcat is that we
can also listen on a particular port and
we can listen for a remote connection
and if user wants to connect with us on
a specified port then we can in order to
use listener in netcat now let's see how
we can use net gate in Kali Linux now
let's see how we can use netcat in order
to fetch some HTML data by using HTTP
1.0 and HTTP 1.1 requests so in order to
start netcat we have to start our Kali
Linux and here you can see that right
now I am inside my Kali Linux instance
and this is the Kali terminal so in
order to start netcat we first have to
write NC for the netcat followed by the
website name or the server IP address
with whom you want to connect followed
by the port number so I am connecting
with this website by using port 80 and
if I hit enter so here we have to
specify the HTTP method then HTTP
version and then we have to write the
hostname
hit enter and here you can see that it
has fetched all that sh t ml content or
data of its index dot HTML pH bus using
HTTP one point or request and if we read
this you can see here 200 okay and here
is the PHP version number and if I
scroll down you can see the entire HTML
data now let's make some another request
by using STP 1.0 version and we will see
the difference between HTTP 1.0 and HTTP
1.1 because I told you earlier that if
you request a one resource by using HTTP
1.0 version so our server can handle
only one request but if we use a strip 1
point 1 then our server can respond to
the multiple request of resources in a
single connection now let's connect with
google.com through port 80 and now this
time we will use HTTP 1.1 so just
specify here version 1.1 and we also
have to write hostname here again and if
I hit enter here you can see our HTTP
header along with some a HTML content
and here you can see that we are still
connected and we can also specify some
another request so this was the
difference between HTTP 1.0 and HTTP 1.1
that we can request only one resource in
a 1 connection in HTTP 1.0 but in HTTP
1.1 we can request multiple resources so
this was the short introduction of
netcat that how we can use not cat and
thanks for watching this video