in this video we will look at open
redirect or unvalidated redirect or
forward
[Music]
[Applause]
so the outline of the video is what is
unvalidated redirect of forward second
demo of the unvalidated redirect of
forward and in last real-life reports
and bounty slash rewards so first what
is unvalidated redirect of forward in
this security bug website redirects or
send the user to another malicious web
page which is crafted by an attacker so
that user get trapped into a phishing
type attack let's see the demo which
will give you more clarity on the topic
so here I design a scenario of T
unvalidated redirect and forward as you
can see here is a web site and this is
the IP address of the web site so this
website is nothing but it is a localhost
which is running on my computer and this
IP address of this website has nothing
to do with the unvalidated redirect or
forward just let us assume that is our
trusted website and we use this website
on regular basis so here is a web page
of this website and you can see this web
page saying this is my awesome page and
here is a link which says click here to
go to whom pants I click on this link I
redirected to the home page let's go
back to the home page now if I right
click on the browser and go to view page
source I can see there is a dedicated
web page to redirect the user from one
page to another page of the website and
this link is vulnerable to the
unvalidated redirect of forward let's
copy this link and paste it on the
browser this parameter redirect is
taking the input and redirect the user
from current page to the input page now
in this web application if this redirect
parameter is not check properly then it
is vulnerable to the open redirect and
forward so I'm typing here another
website for say www if this page
redirects you to the wwe.com that means
it can also redirect a user to some
malicious web site
which could be official page let's click
enter as you can see it redirect me to
the google.com that means it is
vulnerable to the invalidate redirect of
forward this is not only the parameter
which is vulnerable to redirect there
could be a scenario where we enter
username and password as soon as we
click on login the web application
redirecting us to the home page
that means the page after the login so
there could be a parameter which is
redirecting us after giving our username
and password so if we can find that
parameter and we enter some malicious
link then after user logged in it can go
to another website which is malicious
web server so now let's see some real
life reports which would be helpful for
us now as you can see this is a hacker
and dot-com and this is an open report
so anyone can view this report now let
me show you this link it is a vulnerable
link it was reported and now it is
resolved so it is no more reproducible
as you can see this is a Mavenlink app
dot Mavenlink calm and slash logout from
mobile parameter is true and written
path so this written path parameter was
vulnerable to open redirect as you can
see this person gives google.com and it
direct the user to the google.com so it
was vulnerable to open redirect and
Mavenlink solved it now here you can see
the report and now it is resolved now
the about bounty so this person gets $25
from Mavenlink for reporting this bug
now let's see another kind of redirect
here you can see this person reports to
key base if I type key base dot IO and
after slash I'll enter some another
website it redirects to me the another
website that means this was another
scenario of the open redirect now let's
see very popular website which is
twitter.com which was also vulnerable to
open redirect as you can see this link
HTTP def
twitter.com was also
vulnerable to cope in redirect and as
you can see it is resolved now and the
bounty was of $1,120 open redirect bug
for big companies could be very harmful
there are also some program which do not
consider it as a harmful bug that's all
for this video thank you and have a nice
day in this video we are going to look
at clickjacking security will the
outline of the video is first what is
clickjacking
second demo using dvwa and at last
hacker one support this is our OWA SP
page about clickjacking
so it says click jacking also known as
UI redress attack is when an attack uses
multiple transparent or opaque layers to
trick a user into clicking on a button
or a link on another page when they were
intending to click on the top level page
so explanation of this line will be
clear when I give you a demo on dvwa so
for the explanation of what this OVAs
page says i will show you through dvw it
although there is no model for
clickjacking but when you see this setup
and reset database there is a button for
creating and reset database so suppose
this button is very crucial for us if I
click on this button then our whole
database will be reset so whatever be
the changes that we date will be cleared
out so this is very crucial button for
us and we really do not want to click
this button so here I create the HTML
page and in HTML page you can see I have
used an iframe tag and in that iframe
pad I used an attribute source and the
value is our setup page so if I open
this page
you can see you can see this chance to
win an iPod this part so there are two
pages the first page the inner page is
dvwa page and the outer page is my own
crafted page you can see here the
another button which is click here so
now go back to OS page and read it again
click tracking also known as UID a gas
attack so what we did we did receive
user interface when an attacker uses
multiple transparent or opaque layers as
you can see there are two layers the
first layer is of dvw and the another
layer is crafted specially crafted layer
there now read it again click tracking
also known as you are you dress attack
when an attacker uses multiple
transparent or opaque layer to trick a
user into clicking on a button or link
on another page when they were intending
to click on the top level page so this
crafted page chances to win an iPod and
the button here this click here button
so this is our upper layer the user
intended to click on upper layer button
but he will be fooled to click the lower
layer button and and this way he will be
harmed so this is the clickjacking
attack you can read on or WSP more about
it if you are application developer and
you want to know how to defend against
attacking here it is you can read about
it here now let's see Adam so this is
our D bit of low page in this page we
have a setup button as I told you so
this button can be very harmful for us
because whatever with the changes we did
in database will be cleared out if I
click this button so what attacker did
he create his own page and in that page
he uses iframe and in that iframe he
loaded the setup page and he also
created a button which says click here
using some CSS what he will do he will
hide the upper layer button by changing
the opacity so this is CSS property
opacity and what it is doing it will
change the opacity it will make the
lower layer transparent let's make it
for 0.5 and see what our defects let's
refresh this page and you can see it
will get little transparent not fully
transparent if we change opacity to zero
you will see there will be no lower
layer if I go up and I see chance to win
an iPod if I go down there will be a
button as a user I will think that it is
a chance to win an iPod and I'll click
the button but I am getting fooled by
the attacker and the reset button will
be clicked this way our click get
hijacked the name comes click jacking
this means our click get hijacked so it
is click hijacking and that may click
gently so let's try return so as you can
see now I change it to 0.1 this is for
showing purpose in real attacks they
make it 2-0 only so that the lower layer
does not show but here for seeing the
demo what I did is I make it to 0.1 so
as soon as I click on this button the
setup will be reset so I clicked on it
and you can see the database has been
created I don't know whether you are
able to see it or not because if I
change the opacity again then this will
be vanished let's let's do it let's do
it again one more time by changing
opposite to 0.5 and i refresh the page
now if I click here you can see the
Brittain if I click here you can see the
lower layer button click and changes has
been made so this is clickjacking now we
will see the real life report so this
was the clickjacking report reported to
Yale and the report number is two one
four zero eight seven so this person
reported to Yelp and it was resolved and
the mounting was of $100
so here
it is tricking a user into unknowingly
bookmarking unwanted business adding
events through their profile they are
interested in editing their star rating
on divorce so this - shows the Yelp and
attacker can click a user into
unknowingly click on this click on the
button and can be fooled to do these
three things and he was awarded with
hundred dollar bounty the another
important thing that I want to tell you
is the click taking work is not
acceptable by every bug bounty program
before reporting them clickjacking you
must read their policy what are in the
scope and what are not in the scope as
you can see in this report one four six
nine four eight Zomato disclosed zuma
took closed it as informative you can
see here zametov reply thank you for
detailed report according to our
security policy click check-ins won't be
considered as a security issue we will
try avoid this issue in feature we are
closing this report as informative so
some programs accept this bug and gives
bounty and some programs are considered
who do not consider this as a security
issue so this is it for this video
thanks and have a nice day in this video
we are going to look at a POC video
which was reported to Khan Academy and
in this POC video we will see a little
bug which leads to click jacking attack
the click dating video in this course
then first go and understand the concept
of clickjacking and then continue with
this video as you can see here it is a
ver data on khanacademy.org where
students learn HTML so as you can see
the eye film is restricted in this
editor because of clickjacking attack so
it says sorry but security restriction
on this side prevent you from using
iframe text as you can see that to
prevent click dating attack developer
restricted the album death as well as
embed tag and object tab you can see
here then object that is used there
shows the restriction and
sellout DTAC and same with embed tag but
now the frameset tag and friend tag is
allowed so develop will forget to
restrict those thoughts and those that
can be used for click jetting attack
so when films and film tag used as you
can see the Canada admit web page is
inserted in frame so this was a very
little bug which leads to click jacking
attack and it was reported to can attack
me now it is no longer reproducible so
this could be an example of weak web
application security thank you
[Music]