in this video we are going to look at
outline of the course so the first
introduction of bug bounty platform we
will look at the websites which provide
bug bounty programs and we will see how
you can start with bug bounty programs
then we are going to set up our lab we
will install our own web application on
which we will understand and learn the
security issues then we will cover
topics like local file inclusion remote
file inclusion unrestricted file uploads
tab napping and many more all the topics
that we are going to cover will be
explained with demo and also with
real-life reports I'll show you real
life reports and the bounties that are
rewarded in return and after the
completion of course I will tell you how
will you enhance the topics that you
learned in this course I hope you will
enjoy the course
hello everyone if you're curious to know
what are the security bugs in a web
application and how security researchers
/ hackers making money by reporting it
to a respective companies then you are
at the right place
[Music]
this course is all about bug bounty or
you can call it how to earn money
through finding security issues in web
application so the first question is
what is bug bounty programs in brief the
bug bounty program are the programs in
which companies or organization invites
the web application security researchers
or hackers to find the security bugs /
vulnerabilities or security issues in
their web application and when they
reported to the company they completely
boards them with some bounty or some
other stuff and that's how both get
benefited and there are some examples of
rewards like this t-shirt this t-shirt
is given by Beth government in their bug
bounty program and it says I hate the
Dutch government and all I got was this
lousy t-shirt
another t-shirt is given by Sony in
their bug bounty program which says
secure at Sony and there are many other
companies or organization who gives
t-shirts hoodies etc and their bug
bounty programs the another type of
reward is a Hall of Fame in this type of
reward the company have a dedicated web
page which shows the faces or profiles
of a security researcher who had them in
being secure the another type is the
money if you do not know what is this
this is the hacker one webpage I will
tell you later what is happy one so you
can see here the bounty of $1,120
is given by Twitter calm to this person
so this was very little introduction
about the topic bug bounty in the next
video we will see the outline of the
course in this video we will look at the
platforms where you can find bug bounty
programs one of the popular platform is
hacker one or in short edge one as you
can see this is the website where anyone
can create an account and start with bug
bounty programs so as we click on this
tab for hackers and go to program
directory you will see a lot of programs
as you can see here they are also big
companies programs
minimum bounties also mentioned there
are also some programs which do not
provide bounty but gives point in return
and points are beneficial in hacker one
so here is aa who uber Twitter Adobe
let's click on one of the program and
see what our policies so here is Yahoo
bug bounty program and you can see
policy are mentioned here and there is a
lot of things in policy the first thing
is Yahoo bug bounty program rules then
reporting rules that in scope domains
and properties this means what are the
domains that are in scope and here out
of scope domains that means what are the
scope that are not eligible for bounty
or that are not eligible for even
testing you can also see findings not
eligible for bounty this means these
mentioned bugs are not eligible for
bounty if you report them they will not
give you bounty and there are also
rewards and legal the thing is you have
to read this policy before starting your
quest for bugs you should read this
policy for every bug bounty program that
you are going to participate in the
another famous platform is buck trout
you can explore it by yourself and you
can also create an account on this and
you can also use Google search to find
some isolated bug bounty programs too so
this was a very short intro about bug
bounty platforms thank you and have a
nice day
[Music]