in this video we are going to look at
file intelligent vulnerability line of
the video is first what is file
inclusion vulnerability second type of
file inclusion vulnerability local file
inclusion and remote file inclusion
third the demo of both lfi and era file
using dvwa and in last real-life reports
at Packer one also in this video I will
introduce you with OWS P which stands
for open web application security
project so the official website of OWA
space definitely dot o w ASP dot R so
here we are on the website of Oh W ASP o
w ASP is a project run by security
community to help the web application
developer in developing more secure web
application by providing very useful
information about security bugs or
vulnerabilities we will learn about LF I
and RFI through OWA SP website so here
is the OWS be page of Ella file which is
local file inclusion so let's read what
us say about Ella five local file
inclusion alpha Mona's alpha is the
process of including files that are
already locally present on the server
through the exploiting of vulnerability
inclusion procedures implemented in the
application what are they trying to say
is when a web application is developed
in such a way that a file which is
stored on local server is included using
include function of the programming
language or a scripting language and
when this include function is not
properly implemented or the checking on
this function is not done properly that
attacker can take advantage of this
function by including some other
sensitive file located on the local
server and attacker can read this
sensitive file also this is all what
they
to explain you in this page there is
also a page for remote file inclusion
remote file inclusion is also the same
the only difference is file that is
included is on the remote server it is
not present on the local server
remote server means on the other website
as you can see this link the file which
is included is on different website if
you did not get what I'm trying to
explain
don't worry I will give you a demo of
lfi and Aero file which will give you
more clarity so here is the owh PDF site
you can explore it by yourself at some
other time now let's see the demo of
both lfi and RF I'll start the exam and
run these two services Apache web server
and MySQL database then go to your
localhost and start DBW let's login with
username admin and password password see
at your left section before starting
with file inclusion we go to add dvwa
security because we are at learning
phase we are going to select low
security on this dvw a click on submit
and it will be submitted now go to file
inclusion if you are seeing this warning
then don't worry this is for RFI when we
look at RFI we will sort it out so let's
see what is local file inclusion now at
this page you are seeing that there are
three files which says file one dot PHP
file do dot PHP and files the PHP if I
click on file one dot PHP I'll see our
file which says hello admin your end IP
address so this section is nothing but
it is a file which is included in this
dvwa weather equation so the
functionality of the web application is
this website is including a file which
is stored at local server fine if I
click on file to this section shows me
another file which says I need a
password it correct along and so on
if I click on file 3 then this web
application is including tied file so
this section is nothing but it is a file
which is included using some include
function of the programming language and
as you can see this parameter page
parameter is taking input as an filename
so if I save file to dot PHP
it will include file 2 so this parameter
is not sanitized properly in this case
let's see if it can include some other
sensitive file so for that for learning
purpose let's go to our exam directory
and in that same directory we have
htdocs folder and in that - to Doc's
folder we have dvwa - master so let's
open text editor this is only for
learning purpose so if I create a web
page which says you should not read this
file fine so if I save it on htdocs only
by renaming it sensitive dot PHP let's
save it so I create a file create a PHP
file which is a sensitive file this is
only for learning and understanding
purpose so say this is my local server
and at this server I have a sensitive
PHP file which should not be read by any
other person now go back to your DVD
blue here so using this parameter if I
include this sensitive file then this
file will be shown on the screen and
this is a sensitive file this file
should not be seen by every other person
so if I enter dot dot slash this dot dot
slash double dot slash means one
directly back so if we are at this
directly see we are at dvw -
star and inside that we have a directive
vulnerabilities and inside that we have
a directly fi so first go one directly
back which is from fi two
vulnerabilities then another directly
back which is from vulnerabilities to
dvwa master and from that directly we go
into dvwa two extra dogs and in that
directly we have sensitive page that we
had create sensitive dot php' as soon as
I click enter the file is included and
it says I'm a sensitive file and using
this file inclusion I read this n
certified so this is Elif ID now if I go
back to OWS P page you can see it is not
only limited with reading sensitive data
this can lead to something is outputting
the content of the file but depending on
the severity it can also lead to code
execution on the web server code
execution on the client side such as
JavaScript which can lead to other
attacks such as cross-site scripting
which we see in later videos
[Music]
[Applause]
now let's see a demo of our f5 for
starting RFI we have to first allow the
URL include function for allowing this
URL include we have to go to our exam
directory now if you are using Windows
then you have to go to your C Drive or
the drive in which operating system is
installed and inside that drive there
will be a folder of zamp
and inside that Sam folder there will be
a file PHP dot Ali and I and for Ubuntu
users we have go to back our lamp
directory and inside that directory we
have etc' directory and inside that if
we have a PHP dot ini file so we have to
change this PHP dot ini file we open it
with editor if your Windows user please
open this file using your notepad and
search for allow underscore URL as you
can see this is allow underscore URL
include so it is off right now we will
on it so that we can perform our fi now
I have on it save it and close it there
is one thing we also have to do in
Ubuntu system is we have to change this
PHP dot ini permission so for changing
permission we have to right-click and
open in terminal and type C as you do
sudo CHM OD triple7 and the PHP dot ini
ini enter the password now this will
change the permission and now we can
edit this file if you are not able to
edit this file then please change your
permission of this fight so please
change the permission of this file and
then added the file now we have to
restart our zamp
software again first stop the MySQL
database service then stop the Apache
web service we will start it again and
then the changes will occur now refresh
the page and you'll see the error
warning corn so for our fi what we can
do is for say we can include another web
page which is not on the local server
for say some Wikipedia page so this is
the Wikipedia page on our fi if I copy
this page and paste it here
this parameter which is not checked
properly if I paste it here then this V
capito page gets included in this page
so this is our fi remote file inclusion
a file which is not located at local
server but it is located at some other
remote server we can include that file
also so this is the difference between
lf-i and lf-ii
so if I go to OS our fi page you can see
here this is a vulnerable host website
and this parameter file is vulnerable
and here we input some malicious page
which is on some different website so
this is our F file now we will look at
the real-life reports of our fi and
alpha so this is the report with number
one six seven five here you can see this
is the case of local file inclusion
which was reported to Yahoo and the
bounty was of $1,390
although there is no detail of the verb
but the concept was same only second
report number is five nine double six
five this is also case of local file
inclusion vulnerabilities in concrete
five version five point seven point
three point one so this is also a report
with same bug so this report at one
eight three nine seven eight is the
local file inclusion vulnerability
report which was reported to US
Department of Defense as I told you
hacker one is one of the famous platform
and you can see that US Department of
Defense or
the bug bounty program on Hacker one so
this is great these are some real life
reports you can also explore hacker
one.com and can look for other reports
present there so this is it for this
video thank you and have a nice day
in this video we are going to look at
unrestricted file upload vulnerability
video is first word is unrestricted file
upload second demo by using dvwa and at
last third hacker one reports starred
your zamp
and run these services MySQL database
and Apache web server then go to your
browser open your dvwa and change your
dvw security to low for blending purpose
click on file upload and you will see
this screen this is the page where
person upload the file by clicking on
browse and go to its own system i've
seen this hundreds of times on different
websites now I will tell you what is
unrestricted file upload suppose a web
developer did not restricted on the
extension of file that is going to be
uploaded by user then this vulnerability
arises for say this is a form to upload
a picture and as we know the extension
of picture can be gif or jpg or some
other extension but what if I upload
some code file for say code dot PHP
instead of image file if web application
allowed to load a code file then this is
the vulnerable point if I open and
return and write some HTML file which
say I'm a cold fine not an image file
let's save it on our download folder by
extension Co de dot HTML now let's try
to upload it if the file upload
successfully then this is vulnerable to
unrestricted file upload this
is happening because web developer did
not restrict the extension of file let's
click on open and you can see it is
uploaded successfully so we know the
destination where file successfully
uploaded let's try to visit there as I
click enter you can see the code is
executed so this is the unrestricted
file upload now what could be the impact
of unrestricted file upload an attacker
can upload a PHP file which is nothing
but our shall give you a lot of
functionality like seeing a file like
creating a file like renaming a file
editing a file so this could impact a
website to be defaced an attacker can
deface the website using this
vulnerability also let's see how let's
create a new file and started with PHP
so what this line is doing it is taking
a parameter CMD and executing whatever
be the command is passed to this
parameter for learning purpose let's
open a terminal so this is the terminal
if i type LS command then this will show
me what are the files presented in the
directory so this is the command okay so
this PHP file is going to do same save
it in our download folder and name it sh
e ll shell dot PHP fine upload this file
from upload section click on browse and
go to shell dot PHP and open it then
upload because there is no restriction
on extension of file then this file will
get upload successful day now it is
uploaded here let's open this now give
the command CMD this is equal to LS as
you can see it will show the files which
are present in the directory now let's
go back to the upload file and let's
create a file we say hammer D face page
and save it now again uploaded because I
make change in code file then I'll
upload that code file again which is a
stable page open it and upload it now
let's try to visit there see it is or
deface page now the task is we have to
copy this page from here to the main
directory now whenever I visit dvwa it
opened their index page
fine and this is our index page if I
rename this defaced page as an index
page and I copied to main directory then
whenever they open this website the
defense page will open and this is how
other side that defense let's try so
again shell dot PHP command is equal to
first of all I am renaming the file CP
code dot HTML to code to index dot PHP
let's move this index those HTML index
dot PHP to run directly back which is
from uploads to my table then another
directly back from hackable to DBW
master and now let's try to visit again
our website and you can see the website
gets defaced and this is one possibility
of this bug so this is a very critical
bug now let's see real life reports so
this is malicious file upload bug and
you can see through this little person
able to upload a PHP file see the image
it is calling a PHP info function which
shows the configuration of PHP so this
was resolved and was reported to Square
and bounties of $2000
the another report is reported to
informatica and it was also resolved and
the third report is reported to money
word and the bounties of 100
I hope you get what I was trying to
explain so this is it for this video
thank you
[Music]