in this video we are going to look at
tab napping security issue the outline
of the video is first understanding tab
napping using hacker once publicly
disclosed
report and second POC video of hack
event report first
what is tab napping tab napping is a
phishing attack in which a new tab
replaces the parent tab and instead of
parent tab it opens a phishing page
let's see a report it will give you more
clarity on the topic so this is our
hacker one report and the report number
is two eight zero five double zero this
is the tab napping report and it was
reported to info Graham by this person
Suresh so the credit of this report goes
to this person now let's see what is in
the report so details of the report is
when you open a link in a new tab the
page that opens in a new tab can access
the initial tab and change its location
using the window dot of my property so
if there is a link see this this is the
anchor tag of the HTML and we are using
here this target attribute and the value
of the target attribute is underscored
blank it means it opened the link
document in a new window or tab if it is
present here then there are the chances
of tab napping so the point of this
issue is whenever a person click a link
and in that link if our target attribute
is used with the value underscored
length then this vulnerability can
arises let's see a POC video of this
that will give more clarity there is a
POC video also in this report let's
download it this is the video as you can
see this is the website of info Graham
calm in that left side we can create our
own project as you can see this project
has some video and we can create a link
of that video so this person added the
text edit the text and create
the link on this video so the link of
this video is added to its own server
this is the local server that he is
running and this is the IP address of
that server so he pissed that IP address
off his server and and the index dot
HTML file contains this school let me
show you the code so this code so the
index file contained this code what this
code is doing it is replacing the parent
tab by this website which is HTTP
attacker.com it could be any site it
could be a phishing web page of the same
website let's go back to video and play
it again so he added the link of his own
web server which has index.html and in
that index dot HTML the code was there
he shows what this link looked like as
you can see here this target attribute
is used with the value underscore blank
so it opens a new tab whenever a person
click on this link now as he clicked on
the link you can see you can see this
parent tab is replaced by attacker com
so this was from this report and he
reported to Instagram and this is
resolved now another report is reported
to open exchange and it is also resolved
now and the bounty of this report is
$666 now let's try it by ourselves so I
so I have localhost and I copied this
into a file and save it on our htdocs
folder by the name tab dot festival now
in my download folder I created a web
page tab knapping dot HTML let's see and
in this file we have a same condition
that has showed on you POC video so
let's open it with browser and see
whether the tab mapping works or not
so this is our webpage which contains a
link that says click me I click on this
link and this page open and see you can
see and you can see our original web
page is replaced by attacker.com
so this could be a some phishing page of
the same website and a person can scrap
into the phishing attack this is it for
this video thank you and have a nice day
in this video we are going to look at
cross-site scripting vulnerability the
outline of the video is first what is
XSS then demo using dvwa and in last
real-life reports first what is
cross-site scripting I'll explain you
while giving demo using dvwa so here is
dvwa and let's login using our default
username and password that is admin and
the password password now go to your dvw
security and change it to lu and now go
to your exercise reflected now before
starting what is exercise I want to tell
you there are many types of accesses
access this is a very wide topic and
there are many types of accesses so in
this video I will show you only
reflected accesses and I will also tell
you about stored excesses but you can
read more up on OWS P so let's go to
reflected exercise and see what is
exercise so this is a website in this
website a user can enter some data if
this data is not sanitized properly then
user can enter HTML tags and because
there is no check on the input user
provide website allows HTML tags that
user provided if I use BTech this is
bowl tag which make a word board if I
say hello h ee l hello and i use this
bolt head and i as I enter submit you
can see this is default hello and this
is hello that we entered and you can see
it becomes board so what happen have
side allowed HTML tag also and if some
web side
allows HTML text to be executed then
there are the chances of cross-site
scripting and why we call this reflected
cross-site scripting because in whatever
user input it gets reflected let's see
what would have new species so it is
type of injection because at I can
inject some spirit in which malicious is
cripple okay so I slipped that Tom's
user in some way that is malicious
escape are injected into otherwise
banning and trusted websites accesses
attack occur when an attacker uses a web
application to send malicious code
generally in the form of browser side
script okay we will enter JavaScript
also and that is browser side script
okay let's see the page source so I
entered hello
let's entered something else say dvwa
and I submit if I go to their page
source and search for dvwa here so this
is reflected here hello dvwa so if I
enter some thing in bold that that is
hello and if I go for hello hello here
you can see I entered this this is as a
whole and website allows allows me to
enter HTML tags there could be a chances
of XSS now let's try to enter script and
think that I want to say if a website
allows any HTML tag to be executed then
there could be a chances of accesses
that is also known as HTML injection
which is a different vulnerability so
let's try with script now a script tag
is used in HTML to run JavaScript so if
I call a function which says alert hello
and this will this will inject this
script and you can see our alert box
popped up and this is how reflected
cross-site script Forks let's recall
what I am trying to say
so if any website is reflecting some
user input in their view page source and
in that input of HTML tag is allowed or
script tag is allowed then there is a
chance of cross-site scripting and how
is it stored different to them here if i
refresh the page then the data input is
vanished but in stored it that is told
told excesses can be found in some block
type of web application like this name
message sign gas book you can explore it
by yourself let's see some reports so
this is the report that was reported to
blockchain and bounties rewarded was of
$400 now let's see the application at
this is vulnerable to reflected XSS
slash HTML injection through the URL at
the block index page so here what is
happening here so whenever this person
is typing something here after this 1 1
6 0 4 5 7 it is reflected on the web
page so now we go to the page source and
see how he can break the HTML tag and
can start the new HTML tag and he was
able to do that and he entered the HTML
tags the another report is reported to
grata P and you can see the image file
with an alert box so this was reported
to create EP the another report another
reflected excesses report is on v-mail
and this is reported to V mu and the
bounty was of $100 you can see he
alerted domain of the website so this is
all reflected accesses there are various
type of exercise you can read about them
and this is it for this video hello
everyone this video is the continuation
of XSS video accesses video then go back
to exercise video and watch it and
underst
the concept so in this video the main
goal is to understand that the excessive
bug is not only found at such bar only
there can be many parameter in our
website which could be vulnerable to
excesses
so here I'm going to introduce you with
open bug bounty which help us to
understand what could be the parameters
that could be vulnerable to exercise by
understanding the reports on this
website so the web address of this
website is www.antakungfu.com - as you
can see here it is that their security
community helped more than 1 lakh
websites to be secure now if we go to
the quickest patched section and click
on this report this is already patched
report so it is no longer reproducible
but we are learning what are the
parameters that can be excessive
vulnerable so we are going to look at
the vulnerable URL and you can see this
is not a link of a some such bar you can
see after this id id is equal to 13
whenever a user input something then it
is getting reflected and because of
reflection of the input accesses can be
triggered and you can see here a
screenshot also which says open bug
bounty dark you can explore this website
by yourself and this will be very
helpful for your exercise bugs
thank you and have a nice day
[Music]
[Applause]