in this video we will set up our lab so
that we can learn and understand the
security bugs the first software we need
is a
[Music]
[Applause]
Zam helped us to create our localhost on
which we will run our own website for
learning if you already know how to run
localhost then you can use your own
familiar software so let's download this
app first go to google and type X the
MPP or go to their official website
which is Apache friends dot org now on
this website you'll see the download
section for different operating systems
here it is for Windows system for Linux
system and for mac system i am using
ubuntu which is a linux distro so i will
click on linux if you are using windows
you can click on windows let's click on
linux and a prompt comes in so i already
downloaded it so i will not download it
now if you are using windows and you
download the installer then you can run
the installer by double click on it now
if you are using linux then i'll show
you how to install it now go to your
download folder where the file is
right-click and open in terminal or open
your terminal and change the directory
where the file is located
now type c-h-i Modi to make the file
executable type CH m OD + x and the file
name XA MPP here now press enter the
file will be converted into executable
now run it with super user permission so
type as you d o space dot for slash and
the file name press enter enter your
password and you'll see our installer on
the screen now you can install it like a
Windows System click on next and install
the software if you have completed the
design and install the software now go
to your computer and go to your opt
folder and then inside it land folder
and
find the files you are using window
system then your directory will be C
Drive or any other drive on which
operating system is installed inside
that drive you'll find exam folder and
inside the exam folder you'll find
htdocs folder so this extra Doc's folder
contains your webpages now if you are
using your Windows system then you can
run your exam by double click on its
icon if you are using Linux then you
have to do some more tasks to run it
right-click and open in terminal or just
open your terminal and change the
directly by using CD command which is
change direct now here type s UD you for
the permission of super user then press
dot slash and name of the file which is
manager - Linux
- x64 dot run this file now press ENTER
and enter the password and you see the
application now go to your manage
servers and study or Apache web server
and my skill database fine now go to
your browser and n type 127.0.0.1
if you are running Windows then you can
double click on your sampai con and
you'll find a product like this only or
similar like this you have to start the
services Apache web server and my skill
database for further videos so that's it
for this video in next video we will
install more software for setting up our
lab thank you and have a nice day in the
previous video we had installed zem
software now in this video we will
install and setup damn vulnerable web
application or in short
[Music]
[Applause]
the VW is a vulnerable web application
which is used for learning purpose you
can go to their official side which is
dvwa dot co dot PUK and you can download
the zip file from there before
downloading this zip file we have to
change the permission of htdocs folder
which i told you about in the previous
video if you are using Linux then we
have to change the permissions of htdocs
folder so for that we have to go to our
opt folder and inside that lamp directly
and in so on the lam directory right
click and open in terminal or just open
in terminal and change the directory by
using CD command now right here CH m OD
seven seven seven and then htdocs this
will change the permission of st docs
and now we can copy any file into this
folder okay we have to take the
permission of super user also so type su
do and then enter the password this is
for Linux user if you are Windows user
then there is no need of changing
permission you can copy any file into
your as to doc Snyder clean now
permission is changed go back to your
browser and then click on download
section of dvwa now I am using archive
manager to extract the folder into the
htdocs folder if you are using Windows
you can use Wynn area or you can just
right click on the folder and extracted
now go to a computer then opt lamp and
inside htdocs'
okay now the files are successfully
extracted it's time to start our zamp as
I told you in previous video how to
start them if you are using Windows then
you can double click on the icon of the
Sam and if you are using Ubuntu then go
to your lamp folder and right click open
in terminal and run
zamp by using this command now enter the
password and zamp will start on this on
this we have to start two services first
is a patch of web server and the second
is MySQL database now now let's check
whether localhost works or not
ok it is working fine go back to your
lamp go back go back to our htdocs
folder and then inside dvwa - master go
inside config and right click on
conflict dot anc dot PHP dot bist file
right-click it and open it with editor
now change this DV password here this
variable we have to change this from
password to none we just simply cancel
this out and then we save it by clicking
ctrl s and rename this file also which
is conflict not include dot PHP ok now
go to your browser and type 127.0.0.1 a
star and then setup dot PHP you will see
this page here go down and click on
create wizard database this will create
the database now it will redirect to
this page dvw - master login dot PHP now
you can login by using default password
and username which our username is admin
and the password is PA SS wo Rd which is
password
as you can see this is our dvwa which is
a vulnerable web application on this we
are going to learn many web application
security bugs so you can see on the left
side there are many bugs mentioned and
turbine tool on most of this in this
course
[Music]