welcome to module 20 of our course this
module will focus on automated web
application security testing the three
approaches used in the automated
software security testing or white box
gray box and black box testing white box
testing is a technique which
necessitates the full knowledge of an
applications code and can utilize static
code analysis tools by contrast black
box testers are unaware of the source
code and treat the application like a
literal black box where the user
parameters are the input and the
generated page is the analyzed output
gray box testing combines the two
methods testers may know the source code
but don't delve deep enough into
analyzing it the testers could also be
unaware of the code but have other
information on internal functioning of
the application if that's the case a
gray box tester could come up with
better attack scenarios while utilizing
the tools and techniques of black box
testing this module will talk about
black and white box testing since gray
box testing is a subclass of sorts of
black box testing and is not directly
supported by specific tools it won't be
covered here you can see here the hobby
advanced SQL injection tool application
which can be used for blackbox testing
it serves to detect and exploit SQL
injection vulnerabilities let's enter as
the target the URL of an example we
talked about in the module on SQL
injection attacks
[Music]
the entered URL is correct and displays
a normal website as you can see the tool
first searches for a keyword which is
later used to specify if a query has
been successful
next it identifies the SQL injection
attack as an attack on the unprotected
numerical variable the tool has detected
that the server uses MySQL v database or
newer versions the number of columns
used by the query has also been found as
well as the column which will be
displayed on the website
[Music]
the name of the used database has also
been discovered now we're completely
sure that the tested page is vulnerable
to SQL injection attacks let's use other
features of this tool to retrieve
additional information on the database
as you can see the current user has been
displayed as well as database version
current database hostname installation
directory and passwords for the root and
test users the passwords are hashed but
a potential attacker could take a shot
at cracking them you can also see that
the current user has access to the test
MySQL and information schema databases
using the tables function you can load
databases accessed by the user and then
load a set of tables used by the
database you can also load table columns
and the data stored in the tables
as you can see the tool has
automatically detected an SQL injection
vulnerability and exploited it without
knowing the source code there are
similar blackbox testing tools used to
search for the XSS path traversal and
PHP injection vulnerabilities
remember that blackbox testing tools
utilize existent attack scenarios and
may not be able to cope with more
complicated cases in this case the
manual analysis of a web application
behavior and preparing unique attack
scenarios the methods used in gray box
testing might be helpful if you have
access to a website's code you could
also utilize white box testing tools you
can see here the rips framework a PHP
scanner used for testing applications
written in PHP several files used in
previous attacks have been placed in the
scripts directory
[Music]
each containing a different type of
vulnerability such as the SQL injection
XSS and PHP injection vulnerabilities
let's now check the results of analyzing
the code in this framework scanning is
started as you can see two SQL injection
vulnerabilities and one file inclusion
vulnerability have been found a report
has also been generated which contains
the number of scanned files and
statistics on including sub pages in
this case the scripts are autonomous but
if they included other files the
framework would also scan them you can
see here the number of potential sinks
which are the actual locations where a
vulnerability is exploited these could
for example be the functions which
communicate with databases or which
include files functions declared is
self-explanatory and indicates the
number of functions declared in analyzed
files unique sources indicates the
number of sources user input parameters
sensitive sinks specifies the number of
vulnerable sinks that are reached by
unfiltered user input the SQL injection
vulnerability is the first detected hole
you can see here lines up the vulnerable
code the used parameters once you click
on the question mark information on the
vulnerability class and the detected
case will be displayed
the source here is the get variable
which contains the parameters the sink
is the MySQL query function which
execute SQL queries if unfiltered source
data reaches the sink this potentially
could trigger a vulnerability
exploitation the vulnerability here is
the SQL injection flaw the shown
information also includes a description
of a given vulnerability case examples
of vulnerable code and exploitation
scenarios techniques for removing the
flaw and other related topics as you can
see this tool could be helpful in the
quick and efficient detection of
potential code vulnerabilities naturally
the framework could also return
so-called false positives or script
lines which are not actually vulnerable
in their specific usage this could
happen because a detailed analysis of
each case might not be feasible or
because the analysis depends on too many
external factors or is simply too
complicated nonetheless all information
on potentially dangerous locations is
valuable
you can view here a report on the second
occurrence of an SQL injection
vulnerability in the guestbook PHP file
along with the similar information
finally you can see here an instance of
PHP injection vulnerability you can also
find out more on this specific
occurrence and the vulnerability class
in general to scan the application for
XSS vulnerabilities switch the framework
to a different mode as you can see the
XSS flaw has been detected in this case
an SQL injection vulnerability could
lead to the injection of HTML code if we
switch the source type to data coming
from databases or files the tool will
also detect stored XSS vulnerabilities
such as our guestbook script as you can
see the tools used for blackbox testing
and white box testing might be really
helpful remember though that auditing
security needs the experience and brain
power of actual humans so don't fully
rely on software rather use it as
additional and valuable help that's all
in module 20 and it's also the end of
this course I hope that the resources
and advice we've given you have proved
useful and very interesting thanks for
your attention please feel free to check
other training courses which you can
find on our website see you
you