welcome to module 12
in this module we'll discuss direct
static code injection attacks a direct
static code injection vulnerability is a
special instance of the PHP injection
flaw it occurs when users are able to
affect the data pass to a file stored
server-side where the file is further
processed by a PHP interpreter let's
take a look at an example designed to
illustrate this the file contains a
simple script which logs visitor
parameters a file is open server-side
next the script writes data to the files
such as a user agent session length and
IP address date and time is generated by
a PHP interpreter an IP address is
referred by a web server which means
that both values will have a specified
format user agent on the other hand may
hold any format as you can see the input
is unfiltered and is logged directly to
a file let's now take a look at a file
used for browsing the logs our database
file which holds visitor records is
added to log view PHP the include
function parses the file and executes
the embedded PHP code you can see here
sample database entries let's see now
how the script works in practice
[Music]
as you can see the file has logged an
entry which contains our session history
the IP address session length and user
agent let's now use the live HTTP
headers add-on which enables you to
modify HTTP requests and also makes it
possible to alter the user agent string
first open the page again so that live
HTTP headers may capture the requests
generate a new request based on the
captured query as you can see all data
can be freely tampered with before it's
sent to the webserver
giving us a chance to manipulate the
headers let's try to put the following
record into our database
as you can see no error message has been
displayed let's take a look at the
database you can see here our PHP string
let's find out how the file will affect
the behavior of the log view PHP script
the injected PHP code has been executed
as predicted
[Music]
what could be done to evade the
exploitation of these vulnerabilities
first bear in mind that parameters like
HTTP user agent our user input and
cannot be relied upon as they may hide
malicious scripts second remember that
the include function is used for
including files that contain PHP code
since our intention here is only to
display the contents of the file the
include function is non-essential you
could replace it with the echo file get
contents call let's see how this affects
the functioning of our script
as we can see the PHP code has been
displayed but has not been executed is
this enough to secure ourselves from an
attack unfortunately not if the code is
displayed only a hacker may inject an
image code instead of PHP resulting in
an XSS attack let's try to simulate this
scenario
to do this make slight changes in the
request
[Music]
our database now contains HTML code with
JavaScript let's see if this affects the
reading of logs
as we can see the JavaScript code has
been executed which makes this an
instance of a cross-site scripting
attack these types of attacks will be
discussed in greater detail in module 14
for now remember to never underestimate
the risk connected with inadequate user
input parsing we could use the HTML
special cars functions to convert
characters used in HTML tags into
entities that are displayed but not
interpreted
[Music]
let's see how the script will behave in
this situation clear the edit data from
the database and execute another HTML
request
[Music]
as you can see special characters have
been converted to HTML entities they are
displayed on the page but JavaScript
code has not been executed which means
that we've managed to successfully
protect ourselves against a code
injection vulnerability that's all in
module 12 thanks for your attention and
see you in the next module which will
focus on SQL injection see you there
welcome to module 13 this module will
focus on SQL injection many web
applications today make use of databases
to store data if that's the case SQL
queries need to be an integral part of
these applications SQL queries are used
to retrieve and pre-process specific
data stored in a site database these
queries are often generated dynamically
using input parameters passed through
the get and post methods an SQL
injection vulnerability occurs when
users can manipulate the final content
of an executed SQL query take a look at
a sample script designed to illustrate
this the first page we'll discuss is a
simple login form which first connects
to a database
[Music]
a form is displayed if the form is
passed to a script an SQL query is
generated which retrieves appropriate
database records for the submitted user
credentials if this operation is
successful an appropriate message will
be displayed if it fails a corresponding
message will appear to the user
let's see how the script works
here's the login script
[Music]
we have successfully logged in because
the database contains records for the
admin user holding the test password now
enter invalid user credentials as
expected the login has failed notice
that user supplied data is not filtered
or validated in any manner this means
that users have control over the result
SQL query try to think what a potential
attacker could do in this situation
let's see what will happen if the
following data is sent
[Music]
while these credentials are certainly
invalid altering the SQL query results
in a successful login take a look at
another example
we can see here a simple application
which loads articles using an identifier
pass through get the ID 1 value holds a
sample article with the content test
article let's see what will happen if we
change the query slightly
[Music]
since no content has been displayed we
might assume that the application is
vulnerable to SQL injection attacks
let's try to verify if this is the case
add in a string which will constitute an
invalid identifier but which won't
change the behavior of an SQL query in
which it's placed
as we can see the approach has worked
this confirms our suspicions we may
freely alter the end of an SQL query
still we need to find out which table
the query works in how many columns the
table has by using the order by keyword
used to sort records you may discover
the number of columns returned by an SQL
query order by might be used to specify
the number of a column by which columns
will be ordered if the number is greater
than the amount of columns returned by
the query the query will be incorrect
and won't return the requested result if
we submit one as the specified value the
columns will be sorted by the first
column which should always exist confirm
this by entering the following address
let's now try to specify as the value a
number so great it probably won't
correspond to the number of columns
returned by a query in this way we'll
make sure the query is working as
predicted
as we can see the query indeed has not
contained 100 columns this is why no
content has been displayed the database
engine has interpreted the query as
incorrect
now let's submit several values to
discover the exact number of columns as
we can see the query fails with the
parameter of 10 it does not work with 5
the operation is successful with the
number 2 so we know that there are at
least two columns but no more than 5
let's try with 3 the query fails for
this value which means that it returns
exactly two columns we'll use the Union
function which allows you to combine
result sets of select statements from
both sides Union requires the statements
to have the same number of columns
[Music]
the attempt has succeeded we now know
that the database supports the Union
function none of the values we passed
has been displayed the reason for this
is that the page only displays the first
result set while the ignored second
result is the one which was added by
Union once we had the and one equals
zero string to the first request will
cause it to return no results and so our
request which is glued by Union becomes
the only request this time one of the
numbers we passed in a select statement
has been displayed the displayed number
two means that the value of the second
column is displayed on the page and may
be used for passing data we'd like to
retrieve from the database let's use
several standard functions the user
function returns the name of the current
database user
in this case this is the test user
working on a computer where a database
server has been launched the version
function returns the version of the
database what else could be done in this
situation starting with MySQL 5 the
software is equipped with information
schema a special database used for
storing information on the structure of
all other databases and tables which can
be accessed by users this is a form of a
database reflection mechanism the first
way of using it in SQL injection attacks
entails the discovery of table names
[Music]
select table name from information
schema in tables which contains
information on all tables viewable by
the current user the head of the table
contains the system tables as well as
information schema tables to discover
other tables use the limit function
which allows you to set a result range
[Music]
100 is too big while 20 still shows the
system tables
the xxx value has returned the users
table the name looks promising will now
use the columns table from the
information schema as you can imagine
the file contains column names viewable
by a current user
[Music]
at a condition which specifies that
we're interested in user table columns
column name is the name of a database
field which contains column names
as we can see id is the first column
name the second is disabled attempts the
next is login which looks interesting
the fourth column is pass in this way we
have specified a current user and can
access the users table which contains
the login and password
as you can see the first record of the
table defines administrator we can also
display the past column
to see the password unencrypted to
prevent this we need to remember several
steps the first step is to put all
parameters in quotes while this isn't a
security measure per se it is the basis
allowing for the data to be filtered
further in the case of this script the
identifier is always a numerical value
using the info function we can make sure
that the return value will always be a
number if a string is placed at the
start of a function the zero value will
be returned let's see how this works in
practice
as we can see the attack has failed what
can be done if the query has to be made
up of strings notice that if attackers
are to manipulate the content of an SQL
query they need to use quotes you can
now filter input data for quotes using
the MySQL real escape
preg replace add slashes or HTML special
cars functions the HTML special cars
function can also help you protect
yourself from XSS attacks let's see if
this works
[Music]
as you can see this time the attack has
failed as well let's also see what could
happen if a user working with the
database has rights to operate on files
the rights are set while creating users
or granted by administrator a normal
user very rarely has file operation
rights but they are enabled by default
for the root user use the load file
function in SQL which enables you to
load the contents of the file
as you can see the contents of PHP in E
have been displayed the function enables
users to access all files to which the
current database server user has access
rights logging data to a file is also
possible first let's prepare a string
which will be saved in the website
directory
a PHP code which calls the PHP info
function
the directory contains only two files
[Music]
as you can see a test PHP file has been
created after sending a request you can
even run it the value one comes from our
select statement as the Select into out
file function logs all columns returned
by a query this won't do much to stop an
attacker from saving the file with PHP
code so how do we protect ourselves
against SQL injection attacks as you can
see if database user configuration is
poor file operation becomes possible
remember you shouldn't work with your
database using the root account as the
root user has full file rights
permissions to operate on files and
unlimited access to all database tables
it's good to disable file operation
permissions while creating new database
users that's all in module 13 thanks for
your attention and see you in the next
module which will focus on cross-site
scripting vulnerabilities
welcome to module 11 in this module
we'll focus on the PHP injection
vulnerability this vulnerability occurs
where a user has the opportunity to
execute a malicious PHP code by
modifying the parameters passed to a web
application this situation could take
place if input parameters are passed
into the PHP functions that allow the
direct or indirect PHP code execution
the first function group are the include
family functions include require and
require once which serve to include and
parse files containing PHP code the
second function of this type is eval
which parses and executes provided
strings the third function is pregger
place used to verify regular expressions
the parameter e could be passed to this
function allowing for the execution of
PHP code passed in a part of a regular
expression as the two latter functions
are rarely utilized in standard web
applications we'll focus on the first
function this sample source code will
help you understand the concept
you can see here a simple PHP script
which utilizes the user provided
variable site for specifying which page
should be added to the include function
the content of the website is provided
depending on a specified file as we can
see user provided parameters are not
filtered in any manner a user has
virtually full control over the file
name let's see how this works in
practice we can browse the website and
as we're doing so the file names in the
address bar are changing assume that a
hacker has successfully uploaded a file
which contains a PHP code to the server
perhaps you're a bit skeptical after all
uploading PHP files is certainly
disallowed by the site or the service
doesn't accept any files from users it's
common though that websites allow users
to upload avatars pictures and other
image files let's see if an attacker can
still smuggle in a malicious PHP code if
files are checked for correct format
[Music]
you can see here a specially crafted
image that looks like a normal JPEG file
its content is displayed all image
functions will interpret it as a correct
image file but let's take a look at
what's hidden inside
as we can see PHP code has been embedded
in the image let's try to pass it in the
address bar as you can see the script
injected into the image has been
executed but even if an application has
disabled uploading images a hacker could
still use other vulnerabilities to
launch a PHP injection attack file
operations in PHP like including allow
not only direct file references but also
enable protocols such as FTP HTTP and
special data protocol
in the case of data protocol it is
possible to pass file content in
protocol reference parameters since the
file is generated on the spot the data
is encoded in base64 let's use an online
encoder to generate an encoded stream
try to encode the following string
converting it into a base64 string use
special data streams syntax and paste
the encoded PHP code as we can see the
code has been executed let's try to
think of how we can protect ourselves
against this attack the first solution
is to modify the configuration of PHP
any
the allow URL include option might be
used to enable or disable the inclusion
of special files which are accessed
through the protocols we've mentioned
after disabling the function you need to
restart the server for changes to take
effect
as you can see this time the attack has
failed because the options were disabled
attacks which utilize images are however
still feasible as you can see the
underlying cause of the problem is the
fact that users practically have full
control over the string pest - the
include function you can deal with this
by adding static extensions to included
files
[Music]
by doing this we can prevent an attacker
for manipulating the extension
the image has not been included this
time controlling extensions in this way
is enough for PHP 5.3 and newer
additions but older PHP versions allowed
the usage of special character percent
zero zero the null byte or end of string
marker was placed in the target string
passed to system functions causing the
extension included by a web developer to
be dropped
since this vulnerability was often
exploited for attacks while the need to
include the percent zero zero marker and
user provided parameters was rare the
character has been disabled you can also
specify a folder in which the function
include will operate to prevent users
from tampering with the beginnings of
filenames and disable special protocols
the next step is to use the preg replace
function to remove the dot and slash
characters which makes it impossible for
a potential attacker to control the
inclusion path creating a list of files
which can be included and blocking all
other references seems like the best
solution if you can't implement this
method try to deter a potential attacker
by filtering input that's all in module
11 thank you for your attention and see
you in the next module which will cover
the direct static code injection attack
see you there