welcome to module 2 this module is
designed as an introduction to data
hiding what specifically is data hiding
the term was coined for placing data in
a directory which is apparently
inaccessible for the normal user the
data is not protected by any other
attack prevention method the only
security offered by data hiding is it's
apparent obscurity the exact location of
the data is unknown what could go wrong
as we can easily imagine data hiding is
far from safe anyone who discovers the
directories either intentionally or by
accident may access hidden confidential
data we may compare data hiding to
burying a treasure in your backyard if
someone knows the treasure is there or
discovers it purely by accident they may
dig it up and take it the same may be
said of web applications if we hide data
in this way and by hiding we simply mean
the links aren't viewable or published
the information is still not safe data
hiding is very often used in conjunction
with the robots.txt file
the robots protocol prevents web robots
used by search engines from accidentally
indexing or categorizing data we'd like
them to ignore here's what the file
could look like
as we can see the file contains
instructions specifying which
directories and their contents should be
ignored by web crawlers unfortunately
the file is quite often used to describe
locations containing confidential
website data many website developers
believe that storing such data in
robots.txt will prevent them from being
leaked by accident robots.txt is purely
informative relying on bots to cooperate
and honor the instruction to not index
specified directories it is however not
taken into account by web servers
additionally as you can see any user may
access the robots file if we put
confidential information such as data
location in robots.txt we practically
invite and in tacker to try and steal
them the example shows two specified
paths which should not be accessed by
web robots the directories admin and
data a lot of potentially interesting
data may be stored there let's see
what's inside
as we can see after we have typed in the
path a page opens we may browse it
freely this is the essence of the data
hiding process the method doesn't give
you a link to the page but if its
location becomes known it may be
accessed without trouble it's the same
for the other directory after you type
in the path you may access all data
which in theory should remain restricted
although this scenario may seem a bit
abstract web developers often use it
purely because it is convenient for
end-users
if you follow news from the security
branch you may have heard even lately of
websites which have protected critical
data through the data hiding method this
has led to a major leaking x' applicants
resumes being leaked from job search
sites is an example of problems
connected with data hiding another
example is the American Express website
which left the access to application
developers administration panel
unprotected by and large data hiding is
not a safe attack prevention method
remember that confidential data must be
secured with an authorization scheme
don't simply rely on robots.txt the file
does not give you a lot of security and
may just become the hole through which
an attacker slips in this is all for now
thank you for your attention and see you
in module 3 which will talk about how
web applications may be affected by
brute force and dictionary attacks
welcome to module three this module
focuses on brute force and dictionary
attacks these types of attacks are the
easiest form of targeting web
applications that consist of checking
all possible rule-based or dictionary
combinations of logins and passwords
cracking the password may not take a lot
of time so in practice these types of
attacks are often unsuccessful the HTTP
off scheme is the first authorization
method that may be exploited for attack
it is implemented in all web browsers
and virtually all web servers enables
setting it in an easy way here we'll
talk of HTTP auth implemented in the
Apache web server the core of this
scheme is HT access the file used for
many purposes including HTTP
authorization if you store it in a
directory accessed by a web server all
the files contained in the directory
will become protected with the user ID
and password you may specify the message
which will be seen by users and indicate
the file containing passwords used for
authorization let's now try to create
such a file in Apache the command HT
passwd is used for this purpose here you
may see the syntax for calling the
command
to create a file containing passwords
you must first enter the name of the
target file it's good to mention that
files with the extension HT passwd and
HT access are protected by the web
server by default and may not be
accessed by users regardless of this
it's better to put files outside the
document tree of the web server next we
enter the username and password our
password here is 1 2 3 4 the file has
been created now let's see how this
works in practice
we'll use the live HTTP headers add on
the extension allows us to view the live
communication between browser and server
as we can see the webserver has a set
special header
ww authenticate instructing the browser
to authorize the user first we'll enter
an incorrect password as we can see the
browser encodes the login and password
with a base64 scheme and a special HTTP
header is set the server decodes the
string and compares it against data
stored in HT access let's now submit the
correct login and password
as we can see this time the
authorization is successful browsers
remember requests for authorization and
the provided data the information is
transported automatically with each
attempt to access protected resources
because of this no further authorization
will be needed let's now try to launch
an attack targeted at this authorization
scheme to do this we'll use Hydra an
application that enables dictionary
attacking of variety of utilities
including the HTTP auth scheme and web
forms we can see here the description of
parameters of calling Hydra for the
parameter L let's submit the file
containing a list of user names
let's see what these dictionaries look
like they're simply a list of words
which may constitute user names or
possible passwords we can also see that
the files include our login and password
next we submit the file containing the
passwords dictionary we also need to
submit the address of the web server
which will be analyzed and the name of
the attack
[Music]
next as a method parameter we submit the
path to resources which require such
authorization let's now try to start the
command as we can see the sample attack
has been successful once service has
been targeted 21 login and password
combinations and also our access
information have been found it may be
worth it to take note of another
authorization scheme it's a simple login
form created in the PHP language it is
displayed by default if a user submits
the form to script the provided data are
compared against the data held by the
corresponding variables to login the
user must type the username admin and
the password root let's now see in
practice how the scheme is working
submitting incorrect login and password
will cause the message error to be
displayed if the correct information is
given the message logged in may be seen
now we'll find out how Hydra may be used
to launch an experimental attack on the
form indicate dictionaries which will be
analyzed by the application the
dictionaries include the correct login
and password to our script so the
attempt should be successful here the
server name must also be given this
method is called HTTP POST form as the
form is passed via the post method
method parameters are the forms address
data string and the message displayed
with each failed login attempt
[Music]
provide the string representing the
encoded form after the : the value user
is changed to login selected by the
application while pass is similarly
changed to checked passwords we also
need to pass the field go field which is
used for logging in enter the message
displayed with the failed login attempt
after the second : let's see how this
command will work as we can see the
attack has been successful the login and
password combination has been found the
demonstrated examples used ready-made
dictionaries let's think what could be
done if we didn't have access to such
lists or that for some reason they
remain ineffective the solution is John
the Ripper a password cracker which also
enables the generating of password
strings for brute force types of attacks
[Music]
the John MMX version is faster as it
utilizes special processor instructions
while it may be quite aged the
application is still fully functional as
we can see the command may be executed
in different modes we're interested in
the incremental mode which generates
character and digit streams this may
prove useful in brute-force types of
attacks the incremental mode assumes the
parameter mode which defines character
sets used to generate new passwords
let's start with the standard set digits
[Music]
you must add the parameter STD out to
write the generated passwords to
standard output alphanumeric characters
is the second mode another is all a mode
for generating passwords from all
characters
[Music]
generated passwords are passed to a
standard output although they may be
redirected to a file to generate a
dictionary the dictionary may in turn be
used as a parameter of calling Hydra as
we can see the file has been created
[Music]
so how can we protect ourselves against
these threats the first and most
significant solution is to force users
to use strong passwords the stronger the
password the more time a brute-force
attacker will need to check all possible
combinations of characters passwords
should not use words listed in popular
dictionaries it may often be worthwhile
to introduce a scheme for blocking a
user session after a limit of failed
login attempts is reached we must
remember however not to provoke an
account lockout a situation which occurs
when users are locked out of their
accounts we'll talk more about this in
the next module that's all for now
thanks for your attention and see you in
the next module
welcome to module 4 of our course this
module will focus on account lockout
vulnerability
we'll start with helping you understand
the core of this concept we may talk of
an account lockout vulnerability if an
authorizing script which monitors the
number of login attempts is set to lock
user accounts after a limit of failed
logins has been reached if an account is
blocked without blocking the IP address
used for attempted logins a potential
attacker who has obtained the username
and attempts to log in to its
corresponding account may exploit this
by blocking the account of a normal user
the attack results in a denial of
service and may cause users additional
problems this authorization mechanism is
frequently implemented in online banking
if the user submits a valid username but
enters an invalid password for three
consecutive attempts the account is
locked to unblock it the user has to
contact a branch or call a helpline the
procedure could be helpful in preventing
attacks as the potential attacker has
only three guesses at the correct
password for the targeted username on
the other hand anyone who has acquired
our username may use it to successfully
deny us of our own bank accounts take a
look at the example of how this
mechanism works
we can see here a simple website created
in PHP the site employer is a simple
database based login mechanism as we can
see a PHP session mechanism is being
utilized here we're connecting to a
database let's see if the session has
successfully started if it has load
information from the database on whether
the account is locked if it is simply
stop the execution of the script here's
the part responsible for logging users
out it deletes the session variable
which identifies users if the session is
correct
a displayed message notifies users that
they are logged in and may logout if the
session fails a login form will be
displayed after sending the form we may
load data on the user who is matched to
the given login if we managed to obtain
the information it is processed further
but more on this later if we're not
successful an error message appears now
back to finding a user who holds the
specified login if the account is locked
we disable the login option and display
a message stating the account is blocked
if the data is valid declare a PHP
session and display the link in the main
page
if the provided password doesn't
correspond with the password stored in
the database we first display an error
message and then check the number of
login attempts first the field will hold
zero the value will increase with each
failed login attempt if it becomes equal
or greater than two this means that at
least three failed attempts have been
made we display an appropriate message
and block the account in the database
denying the user access to the account
if the limit of login attempts has not
been reached simply increases account in
the database as we can see IP address
and special cookies are not checked here
which means that the account will be
locked without regard to the computer
used for login attempts let's see now
how the service works in practice for
the purpose of this example a user admin
has been added to the database the
password is test let's try to log in
using these credentials we've logged in
successfully we may now return to the
main page and logout as you can see the
mechanism is working correctly log in
again
refreshing the page will display a
message stating the user is logged in
successfully but let's see what a
potential hacker could do with this
situation
switch to the private browsing mode new
cookies will be collected and so a new
PHP session will start the user is not
logged in for this session
[Music]
the page opens and as we've predicted
we're no longer logged in let's try to
imagine how an attacker could exploit
this situation the attacker knows the
admin account has been created in this
service either because he made a correct
guest or because he acquires this
information in some manner now submit an
invalid password the message displayed
unsurprisingly states that the password
is incorrect let's do this again
[Music]
after the third failed login attempt the
message states that the account is
blocked and the user must contact an
administrator this means that the
attacker won't be able to try new
passwords this means that the attacker
won't be able to try new passwords the
same message will display each
subsequent login attempt let's see if
this will happen as we can see the
account is locked let's find out how
this affects a user who has already
logged into a service switch off Firefox
is private browsing we're back in the
previous session as you can see the
account has been locked the session
exists in the system but the database
stores information that the user is
blocked we can see that this mechanism
could be a source of problems for normal
users a potential attacker could block a
user account knowing only the login and
this information is frequently
explicitly displayed on websites all it
takes to block a user is to submit
several incorrect passwords if this
mechanism is implemented for example in
an online auction service an attacker
could temporarily prevent the user from
bidding in an auction how can we prevent
this attack blocking the computer used
for failed login attempts is a better
alternative to locking users out of
accounts this could be achieved for
example by tracking and banning an
attacking computer's IP address there's
little chance of the attacker and
targeted users sharing the same IP
address and on the upside this approach
prevents normal users from experiencing
problems while we're still able to
thwart brute-force attacks on our
service
[Music]
that's all in module four thanks for
your attention the next module will
focus on web parameter tampering see you
there