you
welcome to module five of our course in
this module we'll discuss web parameter
tampering attacks these types of hacking
events occur when manipulated parameters
are passed a script for example through
get or post and affect the functioning
of a service and lead to unpredicted
script reactions critical information is
commonly referred through hidden form
fields this is especially true of web
applications integrated with external
payment gateways a malicious user may
exploit this occurrence by intentionally
modifying transferred data if the
information is not verified server-side
the functioning of an application could
be affected let's take a look at a
sample script designed to illustrate
this problem you can see here a page
confirming the purchase of item numbered
one two three four
[Music]
after clicking confirm the purchase will
be executed and a confirmation message
will be displayed with the transaction
price let's now see the HTML source code
used here as you can see a form is
generated which contains an item
identifier and surprisingly item price
let's try to change the values passed in
the form for this purpose we'll use the
live HTTP headers add-on first we need
to intercept an HTTP request to the
service and use the replay function to
change the query and alter the values of
the referred parameters
[Music]
you can see here the content of the form
referred by post along with the price
field let's try to change the value as
we can see the price displayed by the
script has been changed if this
information was not only displayed but
also used for other purposes for example
transferred to a payment gateway or used
to charge an account a user could try to
deceive the application and modified the
amount paid remember that critical
information shouldn't be made available
to users it has to be stored server-side
all information referred to users may be
tampered with and modified by them this
is why it cannot be relied upon
[Music]
unfortunately many websites still use
hidden form fields to refer data to
payment gateways after a transaction is
completed they don't check if the actual
transaction price equals the expected
sum if critical transaction data is
passed client-side its integrity should
be verified by hash functions or other
cryptographic mechanisms that's all in
module 5 thanks for your attention
in the next module we'll focus on the
path and information disclosure
vulnerabilities see you there
welcome to module six in this module
we'll talk about the path and
information disclosure vulnerabilities
the vulnerability occurs when an
incorrect script execution returns an
error on a website which reveals too
much information to visitors while this
feature is helpful in developing an
application or searching websites for
errors it may at times lead to an
information disclosure that enables a
hacker to see the full service structure
and search it for potential weaknesses
let's see a sample script which
illustrates the problem this simple
script first connects to the database we
have earlier created for this
presentation and then includes a second
file main PHP
[Music]
user input entered into the file is used
to generate an SQL query that loads
articles from the database if the query
is successful the site will display the
article if it fails the site displays an
error message containing the SQL query
which provoked the air this might be
helpful while building web applications
when visitors find errors they can
report it to administrators making
website building easier and faster
unfortunately a potential attacker may
use the disclosed information to exploit
other application vulnerabilities let's
now see in practice how the script works
the database identifier 1 holds an empty
article so entering this path won't
cause errors what will happen though if
we pass an invalid identifier which will
cause the SQL query to be syntactically
and grammatically ill formed as we can
see the generated query is incorrect 1/8
is not a numerical value and should be
placed in quotes if this error occurs
the content of the query is displayed
this dangerous revelation allows an
attacker to realize that the service may
be exploited through the SQL injection
vulnerability a type of vulnerability
which will be discussed later
moreover the names of the fields and
tables used in the database are also
revealed to the hacker which makes the
potential attack even easier let's go
back to our script for a moment as you
can see we don't check if the ID
parameter has been given at all what
could happen if this is not specified
it turns out that the PHP interpreter
has returned more error notices the
messages disclose the number of the line
which contains the error and file name
in the full path if the filename is
hidden through for example mod rewrite
the message will display the original
name of a PHP file this exploit may also
reveal the service structure with
directories and above all disclose the
path to the directory containing our web
application this could be exploited
through a path traversal or PHP
injection attack as these types of data
could be very useful for a potential
hacker it's essential to avoid
information disclosure notice that the
connection to the database is executed
in index.php while main PHP assumes that
the connection has already been set what
happens if the main PHP file is launched
in isolation both main PHP and index.php
are stored in the same directory which
is accessible by the user
as we can see the execution of the
script is not successful here as the
connection to the database has not been
set this results in more error notices
let's think of how we may protect
ourselves from these types of
vulnerabilities and reduce the amount of
output data when an error occurs we may
go back to the incorrect query discussed
earlier in that case we could simply
disable displaying SQL queries while
displaying them is a helpful feature for
developers the information should not be
disclosed to all visitors it's better to
log the information into a file or only
display the query after checking whether
the current user has administrator or
developer privileges as you can see the
message has not been displayed now
unfortunately this does not solve the
problem with returning error messages
where no parameters are passed at all it
may be worthwhile to prepare yourself
for all possible error scenarios errors
may occur as a result of a user or
service mistake they may also happen as
a result of a potential attacker testing
the application for vulnerabilities in
such cases our script could be called in
a way which is not originally provided
for this is why it's useful to protect
the application against at least several
obvious problems in this case we could
configure the script to check if a
parameter has actually been given the is
set function audits whether a given
variable or identifier has been set if
it has not been set an error is not
returned instead the value false is
returned
[Music]
you
as we can see the error message has not
been displayed let's now look into
another scenario launching mein PHP in
isolation to demonstrate the process we
first need to get rid of the protection
mechanism we've just implemented as we
can see error messages are being
displayed we need to make sure that main
PHP won't be launched in isolation here
you may enter a constant that signifies
that the code needed for the script to
run has been launched for example set
the constant header run which signifies
that the code from index.php has been
executed and may be utilized
the constant will be set in Maine PHP
only if the file is included from within
index.php let's see if this produces a
change
as you can see main PHP has not been
executed at all in this case we could
also prevent the attack in another way
[Music]
if the costume is not defined the
execution of script is blocked
if scripts are stored in another
directory you may try to use HT access
to quickly deny users access to these
files reporting errors is also managed
by the PHP any configuration file
[Music]
this is achieved through two variables
error reporting and display errors error
reporting defines the types of errors
which will be reported
while display error disables or enables
displaying errors if it is set to OFF
errors will not be reported let's switch
it off the Apache server needs to be
restarted for the changes to take effect
okay as we can see the code does not
display errors that's all in module 6
thanks for your attention and see you in
module 7 which will focus on forced
browsing see you there
welcome to module seven in this part of
the course we'll introduce you to the
concept of forced browsing forced
browsing is not technically a
vulnerability nor an attack the term is
simply descriptive of a situation where
a user doesn't browse through web
application resources by clicking URLs
but accesses content by manual
identification of resources and may gain
access to restricted parts of a service
imagine the company that sends client
emails linking to a page containing
sensitive data like the client's
personal information account balance and
so on this could look something like
this what's immediately striking is the
identifier contained in the past
it's a numerical value and could easily
be substituted for another parameter as
you can see changing this parameter will
display private information of another
client this could constitute a breach of
the personal data protection act or lead
to the leaking of valuable personal data
of the company's clients another
instance of forced browsing is the
identification of vital service
directories which store libraries
configuration files and other files use
to dynamically generate content
these files should be restricted from
final users as accessing them could lead
to errors that result in leaking
sensitive data or the script acting
autonomously in ways that were not
provided for by the application
developer if access to these files is
not authorized in any way forced
browsing may also constitute an example
of data hiding web developers want to
restrict users from accessing files but
don't use any other methods of
preventing this in the case of web
applications developers often use common
directory names to store service files
an example of such a directory is Lib
which could contain library classes or
full libraries used by a web application
another directory is classes you can
also see here unsecured files which in
isolation could lead to displaying
errors other examples are include and
includes the include directory doesn't
exist in the service but you can access
the includes directory which often
contains configuration files if the data
is stored in a file whose extension is
not linked to any interpreter or the
data is contained in any or XML files a
user may be able to see the contents of
the file and for example discover
database credentials
since the consequences of forced
browsing could be very serious you need
to remember that while building a web
application you should never simply
assume a visitor won't be able to access
certain parts of the service all
directories have to be secured
and directories containing data which
has only used server-side should be
located outside the web server or
blocked in an HT access file you also
need to remember that incorrect file
extensions could lead to the leaking of
crucial data like configurations or
service source code finally while
displaying data to restricted groups of
users don't solely rely online generated
identification numbers it might be a
better idea to use hash functions to
generate less predictable identifiers
better yet be sure to implement
cutting-edge authorization mechanisms in
your application
that's all in module seven thanks for
your attention and see you in the next
module which will focus on path
traversal attacks
welcome to module eight of our course in
this module we'll focus on path
traversal a path traversal vulnerability
occurs where a user may alter the
parameters referred to a web application
to determine which files could be loaded
by the application let's take a look at
a sample source code illustrating the
vulnerability you can see here a simple
website created in PHP the contents of
the sub page are loaded from a file
stored outside the web root directory as
we can see get is used to pass the name
of the file which will be displayed the
file get contents function retrieves the
content of the file but doesn't parse it
notice that an attacker is able to
freely manipulate the name of the file
which will be displayed by the
application we can see here a website
which is working normally the address
bar contains the variable site which is
used to specify a loaded file let's see
what will happen if we submit the
index.php file as a parameter take a
look at the source code of the page we
can see here the source code of
index.php this is extremely dangerous
since an intruder may use the
information to find other code
vulnerabilities or display configuration
files that contain critical data like
passwords to databases mail servers or
FTP let's try to think of other ways in
which an attacker could exploit this
vulnerability
insert the name of a non-existing file
the returned error information contains
the full path to the page file this is
an example of a path disclosure
vulnerability which was discussed
earlier we also know that the web server
of the site is Apache in the exam
framework
this helps us guess the location of the
PHP in E the string dot slash pest at
the beginning to the file get contents
function in theory restricts the access
to the current directory in practice by
using standard special directories dot
dot you may be able to navigate to
parent directories in this case we'll
climb five directories up as you can see
the contents of PHP in E have been
displayed using this method you can
access virtually all files stored in the
webserver provided that their location
is known and they may be accessed by a
PHP interpreter this is an extremely
serious attack which could lead to the
disclosure and leaking of critical
information concerning the server or the
web application itself let's see how we
can protect ourselves whitelisting
consists of creating a list of files
which can be accessed by a script and
comparing the files selected by a user
against the list
another form of whitelisting is
specifying the characters expected to be
present in the inputted file name if the
user provided parameter doesn't conform
to the specifications of the whitelist
the file will not be read
unfortunately this solution is either
impossible to implement or simply
impractical as you can see in this case
an attacker even has control over the
file extension
let's try to predefine the extension
will modify the existing instances after
a restart we can see that the extension
has been added permanently to the end of
the string passed to the file get
contents function and may not be
manipulated by potential attackers in
PHP additions older than five point five
point three it was possible to pass the
end of string marker percent zero zero
which was included without validation in
the string past two filed gets contents
this enabled an attacker to delete the
added extension the problem has been
solved in newer versions of PHP in a
word it's important to employ protection
mechanisms to prevent hackers from
reading restricted directories even if
we assume that the files with allowed
extensions won't contain critical data
filtering out the dot and dot slash
characters may also be useful let's now
try to implement this mechanism the
function will delete the dot and slash
characters let's see if this is enough
as a security measure as you can see all
dot and slash characters have been
deleted which certainly makes it harder
for potential hackers to attack our
application
[Music]
remember that there's always a risk
present if users are able to modify
application parameters to change the
name of the processed file that's why
all input parameters must be treated
with extra caution and be properly
filtered that's all for module 8 thanks
for your attention and see you in the
next part of the course
welcome to module 10 and this part will
talk about the web parameter delimiter
vulnerability this vulnerability occurs
where a website utilizes a simple text
file instead of a database for storing
data server-side and where the text file
separates data with a specified
delimiter if the user provided data blog
to the file is not properly filtered an
attacker may be able to tamper with the
structure of the database and as a
result change the interpretation of the
stored data take a look at this sample
code of a website designed to illustrate
the problem you can see here an example
of a database file the first field in
the database represents user name the
second field represents password the
third email address and the fourth field
specifies a user type a user with
administrator privileges or normal user
now let's take a look at a file used for
registration in the service as we can
see a simple form is displayed for user
provided data next a file is open and
the input is written to it the data is
separated with the same delimiter we've
previously seen in our database
finally the field normal is added which
specifies the user has normal privileges
you can also see here a login script
which loads the entered login and
password you can also see here a login
script which loads the entered login and
password if the following login and
passwords are entered a database file
will open the file will be separated
into more lines via the file function
the function explode separates each file
line into different fields
the login and password provided by a
user are compared against the stored
credentials and if matching data is
found in a line an appropriate message
will be displayed next user type is
verified and reported let's see how this
works in practice you can see here a
login form enter the login and password
of an existing user as we can see the
user administrator is logged in and
recognized as a user with administrator
rights let's try to register a new user
use regular for the username and user
for the password the registration has
been completed successfully let's take a
look at our database now as we can see
here the information we entered into the
browser has been added to the database
let's try to login now as we can see the
login is successful now let's go back to
the registration form and try to make
use of our knowledge about the used
delimiter and the database structure
register the user hacker with the
password hack and the following email
address add the delimiter character and
type in next to it the marker which
specifies administrator account
[Music]
the registration is successful let's see
what our database looks like now as we
can see the data in the first fields has
been logged normally but other fields
contain the added delimiter and injected
administrator identifier as we see that
index.php only loads the first four
fields this probably means that the
record will represent a user with
administrator privileges let's try to
see if this is true as we can see the
user is logged in and has administrator
privileges how can we protect ourselves
against this attack the core of the
problem lies in the fact that input may
contain an injected delimiter which is
used in our database this could be
solved by adding the STR replaced
function which serves to delete all DES
limiters from user input
let's register a second user now
[Music]
use the prepared string let's take a
look at the database now as we can see
the delimiter has been cut out and the
structure of the database has not
changed in order to confirm this login
to the service as we can see the attack
has failed this time that's all in
module 10 in the next module we'll focus
on PHP injection see you there