welcome to module 14 in this module
we'll discuss XSS or cross-site
scripting attacks an XSS vulnerability
occurs when user supply data which is
transferred to a web application through
get or post methods is not adequately
filtered allowing for an attacker to
inject an external HTML code into the
generated page the HTML may contain
embedded JavaScript which is executed in
a victim's web browser data such as
session ID cookies could be intercepted
this way a hacker may also gain access
to a victim's computer the so called
sploit packs are toolkits facilitating
the exploitation of browser
vulnerabilities once a potential victim
opens an infected web site using a
vulnerable browser the split pack
installs malware such as Trojans or
viruses on the system XSS attacks are
usually divided into two subgroups
reflected XSS attacks take place when an
exploitation string has been sent by a
victim's computer through get or post
whenever they visit a vulnerable page
for example if the vulnerability occurs
in variables passed through the get
method victim has to be persuaded to
visit the specially crafted web site for
the attack to succeed
the second XSS vulnerability class is
stored XSS the attack occurs when an
attacker is able to save malicious code
to a server for example in a database or
a file which means that a victim doesn't
have to be lured to a specially crafted
page and can instead be targeted while
browsing a normal service for example
while reading web site Commons or a
guestbook let's now see an example of
the reflected XSS flaw
you can see here a simple script which
simulates browser actions search engines
embedded in web applications will very
often redisplay the string supplied by
users the same mechanism is employed
here the content of the form is sent via
the get method and the search result is
displayed let's see how the script works
in practice as you can see the string
has been displayed we might notice that
user provided data is not filtered which
means that an attacker has full control
over the shape of HTML code which will
be reflected and may use this to inject
a JavaScript
[Music]
all it takes now to execute the code
embedded in the link is to send the URL
to a victim and persuade him or her to
click let's now move to another type of
XSS vulnerability stored XSS you can see
here a simple guestbook script comments
are passed to script via post and then
saved in a database all comments will be
next retrieved from the database and
displayed as you can see since the
script doesn't validate input either we
can expect that it will also be
vulnerable to HTML code injection since
the malicious code will be saved in a
database this would be an instance of
stored XSS attack you can also see here
a simple control panel
if valid user credentials are submitted
and checked in the database and the user
is logged in the site will display an
appropriate message imagine that the
browser represents a guestbook
administrator
[Music]
we've logged in successfully imagine
that the other browser represents a
hacker trying to exploit the XSS
vulnerability for the purposes of this
presentation we created a script which
creates a script tag and sets the
address of a sniffer which is a type of
software that can capture a user supply
data pass through the get method in this
case the sent data is the content of the
cookie variable finally the tag is added
to the dome tree this provokes an
attempt to load the script and the
sending of the get request which will
contain cookies the sniffer PHP file
logs all referred parameters to a
sniffer logged file the file could be
stored in the service which has been
taken over by an attacker in this way
the attacker could obtain access to data
stolen from the vulnerable website in
our case this data is a PHP session ID
let's copy the script and try to add it
to the guestbook
as we can see new elements have been
added to the page the site source code
now contains our script in this case the
code has been immediately executed on
the attackers side and so the first
entry in the sniffer log contains the
attackers session ID imagine that a
logged in administrator visits the
guestbook page
[Music]
as you can probably guess the script
which sends data to the snipper
has also been executed on the admin side
the sniffer log file holds admin session
ID let's try to exploit this using the
live HTTP headers add-on modify the
request sent to the guestbook by setting
the stolen admin session ID
[Music]
as we can see the attacker has gained
control over the administrator session
you probably realize by now how serious
XSS attacks could be how can they be
prevented though the simplest way to do
it is to filter all input user provided
data should be treated with caution as
it could contain malicious elements if
it is not necessary for the users to be
able to add HTML tags we could employ
the HTML special cares function the
function converts all special characters
used by an HTML interpreter such as the
opening and closing tags or quotes in
HTML entities the entities are displayed
normally but are not rendered by an HTML
interpreter
let's see if setting this function helps
let's try to exploit the reflected XSS
vulnerability once more
[Music]
you
as you can see this time the code has
been displayed which suggests it hasn't
been executed the code of the site
contains the and LT and GT characters
they're displayed but not used by the
HTML interpreter to identify tags if you
want to allow users to insert HTML tags
in your application using the BB code
mechanisms might be a good idea BB code
encloses tags and square brackets and
then translates them into individual
HTML tags that's all in this module see
you in the next part of the course
welcome to this part of the course in
this module we'll help you understand
the concept of xst or cross-site tracing
attack we found out in module 14 that
XSS vulnerabilities could lead to
serious damage sessionid cookies theft a
usual target for these attacks had
become so common that a special
mechanism has been introduced to prevent
it the HTTP only parameter has been
added to cookies resulting in the sent
cookie to be stored in a browser and
transferred to HTTP requests but not
accessed by JavaScript this is served to
neutralise many attacks let's now see
how this mechanism works in practice
[Music]
you can see here a simple PHP script
which sets a cookie and the HTTP only
parameter we've just mentioned it is
initially set to false we'll cover this
part later let's now focus on the line
which should display the content of a
cookie set on the server side using the
live HTTP headers add-on we're able to
see the communication between the
browser and user as you can see the
content of the cookie has been displayed
the contents of the requests includes
the set-cookie header with the name
value and expiration date of the cookie
let's change the HTTP only parameter to
true clear the live HTTP headers logs
and refresh the page
this time the cookie has not been
displayed and cannot be accessed by
JavaScript
as you can see the HTTP only parameter
has been added to the end of the cookie
definition virtually all web browsers
support the HTTP only attribute if it is
set by the server the browser's will
block JavaScript access to the cookie
which helps to minimize the fallout from
XSS type attacks this mechanism was
initially believed to be an adequate
security measure a new technique has
been developed which serves to
circumvent it this is called the excess
T or cross-site tracing method as we
know HTTP protocol enables sending
requests of various types the most
popular among them are get and post
requests the head request is also used
to query a server for headers only there
are also other types of queries for
example the trace request which is
implemented and enabled by default in
most web servers the query reflects user
headers all headers sent by a browser
including cookies are returned as a
server responds by using the XML HTTP
request object
setting the request type to trace and
submitting the address of the attacked
server an attacker could read the
contents of the cookies without using
the document cookie variable instead the
attack exploits the data returned by
text responds by passing the HTTP only
mechanism let's see the site behavior
again
as you can see an error has been
reported as a violation of security
mechanisms many web browsers have lately
begun to block less popular and rarely
used request types which could be
utilized as a means for bypassing
security mechanisms disabling trace
requests could prevent an attacker from
running xst attacks this request is used
mostly by developers to debug browsers
and Ajax requests however its use and
normal applications is so limited that
it seems like a good idea to block it
while today xst attacks are nearly
impossible to launch it's still useful
to keep in mind the possible attack
scenarios and to block trace requests at
the server level either in firewall
rules configuration files or HT access
that's all in this module the next
module will cover cross-site request
forgery attacks see you there
welcome to module 15 in this module
we'll talk about cross-site request
forgery or CSRs or xsrf attacks a
cross-site request forgery attack occurs
when a user who is authenticated on a
web application is tricked into
unintentionally executing an action in
the service a good example of this is
persuading an administrator to click a
URL which deletes an account of another
user the administrator is of course
unaware of this how can victims execute
actions without realizing it this is
what could happen if a specially crafted
link is clicked and executed through an
exploitation of the XSS flaw we've
discussed earlier let's now take a look
at a sample site code which illustrates
this scenario assume as a starting point
the guestbook we've talked about in the
module on XSS attacks this unprotected
version of the application allows users
to submit any HTML code the second part
is an admin script which verifies if an
authenticated user has admin privileges
if this is the case the script enables
him or her to add a user holding the
login and password indicated with
parameters sent through the get method
if a user who has not logged in visits
such a page an appropriate message will
be displayed
the third script enables logins to a
service and utilizes the same database
table for authenticating users
[Music]
if the submitted data is valid an admin
session will be activated you can see
here to web browsers with unrelated
sessions in progress which indicates
that there are two different users
assume that the browser on the left side
represents an administrator of an
attacked service while the browser on
the right represents a hacker who's
trying to gain control over the service
as you can see the attacker is not
logged in and is not in possession of a
valid login or password which means that
it won't be able to perform any actions
in the service on the left is our admin
assumed he logs in using admin as a
username and test as the password as you
can see the admin has logged in
successfully let's confirm this the
attacker is still not logged in
let's now see what a cross-site request
forgery attack looks like you can see
here a guestbook script let's submit to
it an image which once clicked will
execute an HTTP request to add a user to
the service
[Music]
let's take a look at the script we need
to pass the action variable with an add
user value the user variable containing
a username and the password with a
password as you can see an image has
been included which hides a link to the
admin service in its source now confirm
that the attacker is still not logged in
and that the account has not been
created
as you can see the account does not
exist in the system let's assume now
that the administrator decides to visit
the guestbook
the image has not been displayed because
its URL refers to a site that is not an
image the administrator could pay no
attention to the fact that the image has
not displayed and won't notice that a
request has been executed that adds a
user to the database let's see the
result now a new account has been
created for the attacker and he is
logged into the service try to think of
ways in which we could prevent exposing
ourselves to these attacks a good first
countermeasure is securing the
application against XSS flaws however
users could still fall prey to such
attacks through their websites to secure
an application from performing
significant actions in the background in
a potential CSRF attack you can require
reauthorization or introduced
additionally generated tokens the
database could store random one-time
strings which would be added to all
forms generated in a hidden field in a
service this would allow you to check
server side and the submitted token is
still active thanks to this method if
hackers won't know the currently active
tokens their attacks will be foiled on
the other hand using only the post
method without using get requests cannot
guarantee application security as an
attacker could use JavaScript to
generate a post request that's all in
this module thanks for your attention
and see you in the next part of this
course which will focus on using a
browser to spy on data
[Music]
you