welcome to the course on web application
attacks over the next modules we will
cover the most significant issues
relating to common types of web
applications susceptibility and talked
of the ways in which you may defend your
applications against attacks the first
module will focus on configuring the
computer environment so that it may be
used for further presentations and
experiments let's start with the xampp
package its components include the
apache HTTP server the PHP interpreter
MySQL database server a PHP myadmin tool
for database management and other tools
for developing web applications we will
use the Firefox web browser and find the
xampp package
[Music]
you can see here the xampp website
select the Windows installation version
[Music]
install the package without changing the
default settings
[Music]
after the xampp installation has
successfully completed the control panel
will open it serves as a tool to manage
the individual components of the package
well pin it to the taskbar to make it
easily available for future reference
none of the components are running so we
may safely modify our configuration to
support the editing of text files
install the free syntax highlighting
text editor notepad plus plus its
features include system shell
integration which makes possible the
editing of files through selecting
options from the context menu for each
file
[Music]
let's open the directory xampp package
in apache backslash comp you will find
the file HTTP decom which contains the
configuration for apache the directory
modules has been copied to the desktop
from the disk attached to the course
book you may also download it here
hacking school comm forward slash get
whp it contains examples of the next
modules will also include applications
needed to illustrate some of our topics
we want it to be accessible from
browsers the configuration file contains
the section directory it indicates to
Apache the presence of a folder and sets
access options for each folder
we see here the definition for the
htdocs directory that comes with the
xampp framework we can copy the
definition let's now copy the full path
two modules and paste it to the copied
directory definition changing the slash
Convention is also necessary as the
Apache package supports and prefers
Linux convention even if it's launched
on Windows we must now logically define
the relationship between the path
entered and the browser and the defined
directory for this purpose use the
command alias we can see the calling of
the command let's redirect modules to
the security directory
[Music]
now let's launch the Apache server and
check its configuration next start the
MySQL server we can see that the
security directory may be opened and
accessed the default page for the X M
framework is running let's now use PHP
myadmin
[Music]
and a test user with access to the
localhost set the password to test and
grant the user access to a database with
the same name all the basic access
privileges are granted to the user
[Music]
let's also select the option file
normally this would not be done however
for the purpose of one of our
demonstrations this is necessary the
user has been added correctly we must
now import database dump which will
create tables needed in the next modules
and add sample data
[Music]
let's now install the Javie advanced SQL
injection tool and create a shortcut in
the directory of module 20
[Music]
next download the rips package for
testing PHP applications extract it to
the directory of module 20 we now need
to download John the Ripper a tool for
cracking and generating passwords
extract the Windows version to the right
folder next we download another
universal brute force password testing
software application Hydra
[Music]
the software is released as source code
which needs to be extracted to a folder
of the right module to compile it we
need cygwin the package enables
compiling and starting of linux
applications under the windows system
[Music]
use the default installation options
select one of the servers containing
copies of the cygwin packages take time
to pick the right server not all servers
are equally fast an installation time
depends on the server the packages we
need to install are
[Music]
make sure all of them are selected and
click Next the installation of the
cygwin package depends on our internet
connection and hard-disk
this may last quite long so don't be
discouraged
[Music]
the package has been installed open
terminal and go to the directory
containing the Hydra source code
launch the command configure so that the
installation script can check whether
the necessary libraries have been
installed next we may launch the command
make which will perform the write
compilation
[Music]
after the compilation copy the binary
file to the right directory launch the
Windows System terminal and make sure
the application is running as we can see
the application needs several libraries
that are components of the cygwin
package they must be placed in the
directory containing the binary file of
our application
[Music]
the necessary libraries have been added
and the application is running correctly
[Music]
in this way we've made the environment
ready for work and other experiments
thank you for your attention and see you
in module two which discusses the data
hiding method