welcome to module 16 this module focuses
on the spying of web application traffic
as you've discovered in module 14 which
focused on the XSS vulnerabilities
exploiting these flaws could have
serious consequences for users of
vulnerable services user data such as
session IDs could be stolen and malware
could be installed on a victim's
computer as you know it's feasible to
execute any JavaScript browser side
there are also other means of exploiting
these holes using several simple tricks
an attack is able to write a script
which will monitor all operations
executed by a web application user and
which will be active as long as the
given browser window is kept open you
can see here a simple code for the
sniffer the load sniffer function
launches the sniffer first it creates a
secondary XML HTTP request object used
for Ajax requests then loads all links
and forms in a website let's see the
sources for these functions
the collect links function is used to
load all link tags from the current
document and replace target addresses
with JavaScript function calls where the
links URL is the parameter in the
collect forms function the forms target
address is replaced by a function call
which assumes the number of the form of
the parameter let's now take a look at
the load URL function
[Music]
at first the sent to attacker function
is called which we'll discuss in a
minute its source is set to the URL
which a user attempted to click and
parameters are set to have the frame
fill an entire page the frame is added
to the website's Dom tree and display
delay is set to 400 milliseconds after
this time the site should preload the
script tag is also added which loads the
code of our sniffer next the load
sniffer function is called to parse the
page let's now focus on the sent to
attacker function
[Music]
we can see that a referral address is
being prepared which will pass captured
data such as website URL or form content
to our sniffer through the get parameter
XML HTTP request object references to
pages from other domains are disabled in
virtually all browsers for security
reasons to circumvent this a script tag
is created and the generated sniffer
link is submitted as the URL next the
tag is added to the dome tree so an
attempt will be made to load the script
which will execute the get request and
send data to the sniffer let's see the
significant ow as you can see all pass
parameters are logged in the sniffer log
file as for now the sniffer log is empty
let's take a look at the source code for
our website in this case the sniffer has
been injected directly into the code but
it's equally probable that an attacker
could have inserted it into the service
using the cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities you can see here several
links to sub pages and a forum
the sniffer code is not executed on the
subpages let's see now how the site
works in practice
[Music]
you can see here the main page links
have been replaced with loadurl function
calls let's click on the first link this
page has also been parsed by the sniffer
let's open the second and third links
now go back to the main page put a
string in the forum and try to send it
let's see the contents of a sniffer dog
file as you can see all calls have been
captured including the values sent
through the forum a potential attacker
may be able to monitor all operations
performed by a victim in this way let's
try to think of ways in which we could
protect ourselves against these attacks
as web developers we should above all
take care of the XSS vulnerabilities we
should also make use of a frame killer
if our page is open in an iframe the
code will redirect an entire browser
window to the frames URL causing the
page to reload outside the frame in this
way the page outside the frame with all
embedded scripts will be skipped as
users we should be on alert if the
address in the bar does not change even
if we have browsed through several pages
what's more if by hovering over a link
we discover that the displayed URL
executes JavaScript we should remain
extra cautious
some newer browsers disable JavaScript
access to frames with URLs and domains
different than the URL of the window
that's all in this module thanks for
your attention and see you in the next
module where we will focus on session
hijacking welcome to module 17 in this
module will help you understand session
hijacking which is a type of attack that
consists of an interception of a session
session hijacking attacks allow an
attacker to gain unauthorized access to
services by taking over the active
session of an authorized user how can
this be carried out as you know HTTP
protocol is stateless to maintain user
state cookies have to be introduced
cookies are stored in web browsers and
often contain unique user identifier
which are processed server-side to set
up sessions containing user information
while an ID is assigned to a specific
user the exploitation of the XSS
vulnerabilities we've mentioned in
previous modules could allow an attacker
to steal a cookie with user session ID
to access services the same could be
achieved by using scripts which monitor
user actions let's see how this works in
practice
take a look at this very simple script
if you visit the admin log in PHP URL
the admin variable is set for the
current session which means that the
user will have administrator rights the
test.php file is also available the file
utilizes the PHP session mechanism and
if the admin variable is set the message
Hecht will be displayed the
vulnerabilities have been successfully
exploited if this is not set the message
not hacked will be displayed imagine
that a normal user is being authorized
in a service during this process a
unique session ID cookie is generated
and session information is saved
server-side let's use the live HTTP
headers add-on to see communications
between the user and server
[Music]
as you can see once the login.php
address is entered a PHP sess ID cookie
is sent to the server the cookie is used
by default to store PHP session IDs if
the administrator falls prey to an XSS
attack or data transmission has been
intercepted an attacker can obtain the
content of the cookie let's open a
private tab which uses a new set of
cookies rendering the previous session
inactive
[Music]
visiting the test.php URL doesn't give
us access to the control panel this time
let's use the live HTTP headers add-on
again as you can see a different PHP
session ID is sent to the server the
add-ons replay function allows you to
freely modify the set request will set
the admin session ID using the cookie
we've previously acquired next we send
the request to the server using the
replay function as you can see the
access has been granted how can we
protect ourselves against these attacks
the first prevention method is securing
the application against XSS
vulnerabilities as these types of flaws
might be used to leek session ID cookies
used in our service using the encrypted
HTTP protocol will guarantee that
intercepting cookies won't be feasible
outside of the users computers you can
also add the HTTP only parameter to
cookies which should disable JavaScript
access to cookies a frequent
regeneration of session IDs is also a
good idea especially after a successful
login another prevention method is
checking the IP address related to the
session the address should not be
changing while the session is in
progress if it is this could point to a
potential session hijacking event many
ready-made scripts implement their own
session mechanism which checks the IP
address used in a session that's all in
module 17 thanks for your attention and
see you in the next module which will
talk about session fixation attacks
welcome to module 18 in this part of the
course we'll talk about session fixation
attacks session fixation is a subclass
of session hijacking session hijacking
involves the interception of a victim's
session ID
session fixation occurs when an attacker
finds a way to make a victim who has
access to an attack service use a valid
session ID supplied by the attacker if
the victim assumes the session ID and is
correctly authorized in the attack
service the attacker could take over
this session and gain service access
this is possible in the standard PHP
session mechanism if a user has no
session history saved in the cookies and
the idea is sent through the get request
it will be adopted as the new session ID
[Music]
let's see a sample script which
illustrates this scenario you can see
here two files admin login PHP simulates
the behavior of a script which logs
users into a control panel it sets the
admin variable used to identify the
administrator in a session variable test
PHP is the second script the script
checks if the admin session variable is
set if it is the message hacked will be
displayed if it is not not Hecht will be
displayed the echo session ID function
which shows the current PHP session ID
is also set for transparency let's now
see how this vulnerability works as you
can see a potential hacker wouldn't be
able to access the service the message
not hacked is displayed session ID is
also displayed the ID could also be
obtained by using the live HTTP headers
add-on as you can see the same session
ID has been set in the PHP SSID cookie
let's use it now assume that a cracker
has lured an administrator into clicking
on a crafted link the link looks like
this
the administrator has logged into the
service and as you can see the PHP SSID
variable containing the attacker session
ID has been passed in the URL let's see
what the effects of this are on the
attackers side as you can see the
attacker has gained service access how
can we protect ourselves against these
attacks preventing session fixation uses
similar methods to those recommended for
session hijacking above all it is
crucial to recheck a user's IP address
and other user unique data the frequent
regeneration of session IDs or at least
the regeneration of session IDs after
successful login is also helpful by
doing this we make sure that once a new
idea has been generated the ID known by
the attacker will become invalid
that's all in module 18 the next module
we'll discuss the phishing concept
thanks for your attention and see you
later
you