welcome to module 19 which will examine
phishing phishing attacks target users
and user groups rather than specific
applications or servers the attack
consists of an intruder attempting to
impersonate entities such as companies
or financial institutions in order to
trick a victim into visiting a specially
crafted website designed to look like
the legitimate service the page is
instead set up to deceive users and
steal submitted passwords and other
types of sensitive information early
phishing attacks mostly targeted bank
customers attackers try to register a
domain similar to the official bank
domain and then set up a website which
masqueraded as the legitimate Bakke page
next they send emails to potential
customers of the bank which requested
them to log into a service and unlock
their account these attacks have become
widespread you can probably find a
number of phishing emails in your
mailbox but what are the distinctive
features of these attacks first of all
the address to which the email will
direct us will frequently look
suspicious if you pay close attention
you'll discover typos in the domain name
or weird parts at the end of the URL
since diacritical marks have been
allowed in URLs Fisher's make use of
internationalized domain names to launch
attacks another key aspect is the look
and feel of the service the layout might
differ slightly from the layout of the
legitimate bank website the site could
contain graphic errors and some elements
could be non-functional early phishing
attacks were constructed with
painstaking precision so the forged
websites were nearly undistinguishable
from legitimate services today phishing
emails are sent in bulk and websites are
created semi-automatically
which means that the forged websites
will rarely look legitimate enough to
deceive us
what's more these attacks are launched
internationally by groups of criminals
who frequently don't speak the native
tongue of the attacked institutions
customers the messages are translated by
free machine translation services and
abound in grammatical and syntactical
errors sometimes they are practically
incomprehensible we'll take a look at
some sample messages which serve as a
warning
[Music]
you can see here an attack which targets
users of a popular auction service the
attackers have done a good job
recreating the design of the service
the address is wwl egg row tomorrow the
home taro top-level domain should alert
us you can see in the image the content
of a message sent in a different
phishing attack everything seems to
point to it being sent from allegro
servers remember however that attackers
can use gates which allow them to adopt
any email address to make sure the email
has really been sent by Allegro and not
by Fisher's you should carefully examine
the headers which record specific paths
used in sending the email also as you
can see the message contains serious
linguistic errors which again should
alert us this is another example of a
phishing attack targeting a popular
social networking service the message
looks innocent on the surface but let's
pay attention to the fact that the URL
begins with ww8
remember that if the sent message is
formatted in the HTML the visible URL
could be different from the actual
address to which you'll be directed you
can see here a message sent to customers
of a bank how can we protect ourselves
against these attacks first of all you
should be careful with submitting
sensitive data such as passwords
identifiers or credit card numbers
remember that very few companies request
such information to unlock an account
this is especially true in the case of
banks you can unlock your account by
calling a consultant or contacting a
local branch of the bank another key
point is never trusting the links
contained in incoming mail even if the
link seems trustworthy it's better to
manually provide an own you
rather than click on the link provided
in the message by doing so you'll be
sure that the website you visit is the
legitimate service then you can make
sure whether the information passed in
the message that an account has been
locked was true if there really are any
problems use the official service and
its functionalities to be sure that you
don't give up crucial information to
attackers it might also be worth it to
check HTTPS certificates an increasing
number of websites use the encrypted
HTTPS protocol to verify server identity
you can display in your browser the
details of a certificate and check its
validity subject and issuer browsers
attempt to verify key information such
as expiration date or issue or
trustworthiness on their own you can
however check by yourself whether a
certificate has been issued for the
service you are trying to log into if
you suspect phishing it's good to
contact the service administrator and
share your suspicions by sending them an
original email this could help in
verifying the information contained in
the email and protecting other customers
if you want to contact the administrator
remember not to use the reply option as
the email address could be forged check
the legitimate service page for contact
data another good idea is to examine the
physical URL of a link don't rely on the
text displayed in the HTML messages it's
safer to copy a target address and make
sure it leads to a legitimate location
if the URL seems suspicious don't visit
it
that's all in module 19 thanks for your
attention and see you in module 20 which
will discuss automated security testing