this section is related about JavaScript
and accesses attack so in this section
we are going to take a look at various
points like first of all we will learn
about some accesses and JavaScript
attacks then we will perform practicals
on accesses by using effect of accesses
then we will learn about some more
interesting commands in XSS attack which
is also called chichi and then I will
show you the defending techniques
against accesses events so first we are
starting with the first video of section
4 which is XSS and JavaScript attack so
in this video we are going to take a
look at first of all what is XSS attack
and what is the process of accesses
attack let's start with XSS attack
introduction so accesses is also called
CSS and the full form of X CSS is got
cross-site scripting so accesses
audiences are seen accesses attack in
the second point you can see X's attack
is a kind of attack in which katako
inserts malicious commands in the web
application so what kind of malicious
comments they can use they generally use
JavaScript right inside accesses attack
attack I use malicious JavaScript to
insert these malicious commands in the
web applications in general dumb
accesses attack has three types
persistent attack non persistent attack
and Dom based attack persistent attack
means the attack which is persistent
which is also called server-side attack
non persistent means which is not
permanent which is not persistent
that is also called client based attack
document based model or document object
model is the third one now we will learn
what is the process of accesses attack
so here you can see on the screen that
this is the process of XSS attack and
I'm going to explain you that how it
works for example this is the attacker
right and the attacker is inserting some
malicious commands inside the server so
this is the server you can see right
this is the web server this is the
victim or a regular user of the website
pod reader he basically sends a request
to way by using browser
he's sending the request that request is
going to the web server so in return the
it is showing in the browser right and
here it is going to the attacker so what
is the process here basically attacker
has inserted some malicious script
so when any user is trying to access
that particular web application maybe
the user is reflecting to some other
website or redirecting to some other
website which is owned by attacker or
there is a possibility that the cookies
of the victim can be sent to the
attacker an attacker can use that cookie
to access the website so this is the
basic process of accesses attack he
inserts some malicious JavaScript in the
web server and redirect the victim to
that particular malicious website