hello and welcome students to the web
security course I am Sunil Gupta I'm a
Saba security specialist author and a
public speak let's talk about the course
overview what we are going to learn here
in this course is we have divided the
course into six sections first of all we
will learn about introduction about web
application security then we will learn
about information gathering in which you
will learn how you can gather
information about web applications then
we will learn about the various
injection attacks like SQL injection
command injection line injection etc
then we will learn about accesses attack
or JavaScript attack later we will cover
the CSRF attack cross-site request
forgery attack and logic flaws and then
finally I will show you that how you can
avoid and detect some other one remedies
what are the course goals so you can see
here that the course is designed to
provide the fundamental or the basic
skills regarding web security threats
and detection techniques and here you
will evaluate the issues available
inside web security and how you can
detect these kind of paper attacks that
we will talk about in this course if you
talk about the set up then setup is
quite simple that we have a Kali Linux
operating system and we will create a
server on that and we will perform
attack on that web server using Kali
Linux operating system and that type
server contains various kind of
vulnerabilities like SQL injection XSS
CSRF so we will try to perform
transition testing on the web server and
I will also show that how you can detect
and remove these kind of vulnerabilities
so why you should take this course
because here you will not only learn
about that how you can find out the wall
nobodies in the web site and how you can
detect it you will also learn about
various kind of Kali Linux tools and
techniques and here you will learn about
web pension testing and how you can
secure your website so this is all about
the web security goes
you