hello and welcome students to various
injection attacks so in this section we
are going to take a look at various
points like first of all we will learn
about what is SQL injection and their
various injection vulnerabilities what
is the effect of SQL injection on
applications and then we will learn
about various kinds of spill injection
commands using SQL injection gici and
then the prevention techniques from SQL
injection the last rap so let's start
with the first video of section 3 SQL
injection and various injection
vulnerabilities so in this video we are
going to take a look at couple of points
first of all we will learn about what is
SQL injection and then we will learn the
process of SQL injection in web
applications so first of all what is SQL
injection attack so as we already know
that SQL injection attack is basically
the number one attack on web
applications and if it is available in
your web application then you should
remove it immediately so let's learn
about SQL and SQL injection so SQL is
called structured query language as you
can see in the first point right this is
the full form of SQL and what is the
skew logician so SQL injection is an
injection attack you can see here it is
injection attack and where attacker
inserts malicious scripts and database
to get sensitive information so it's a
quite simple concept that it is also a
command based attack right and attacker
needs to insert some malicious command
right and by using that script or that
command database provides you
information so that kind of attack is
called SQL injection attack in which
attacker tries to insert scripts in the
database and getting the valuable
information in return what kind of
information attack again get from SQL
injection that is in the third point so
SQL injection attack can provide sense
it will function like username the
unpassed word so what kind of user name
and password for example admin username
the admin panel of the website and
attacker can get the username and the
password of the admin panel and attacker
can wipe out the complete data from a
database what else and attacker can get
phone numbers of customers right fax
numbers addresses of customers so this
kind of sensitive information and attack
it can get from SQL injection attacks
process let's talk about SQL injection
process
it's quite simple so here you can see
this is a very simple scenario in which
you can see this is the attacker and
this is your database or you can say web
server and attacker tries to attack on
the web server so what is the process
processes for it simple right and
because attacker needs to use Internet
to access the web server of that
particular website right and it's quite
simple attacker needs to insert some
commands which is SQL in comments and
this database will provide you all the
information to attack a browser so this
is called basically SQL Lucien process
what kind of commands we can use in SQL
injection that I am going to cover in
the next video and this is just a
process that I'm going to provide you
some information about it right and this
is a quite simple scenario alright
because anyone can access websites and
web site has web server and that server
contains database so the attacker
needs to attack on this database to
gather information about tables columns
as the data which is valuable to
attacker to the our target means if you
consider as an attacker then your target
is to gather the information from the
database of the website that we are
going to learn in this section so this
is all about this video about SQL
injection introduction and process
you