you
this section is wilted about CSRF and
logic flops now in this section what we
are going to learn first of all we will
learn about what is CSRF and then we
will learn about the effects CSRF for
applications we will perform some
practicals the form of few treats in the
last video we will learn about all the
different techniques about CSI refer the
overview of cross-site request forgery
attack in this video we are going to
take a look at couple of points we will
learn about what is CSRF attack and then
we will explain about the process of
CSRF attack on the button equations so
let's talk about CSRF or CSRF or xsrf it
is also called xsrf what is the full
form of CSRF cross-site request forgery
is the full form of CSRF it is also
called accessorize what is the meaning
of CSRF and how it works so CSRF attack
is a major attack on web application I
already told you that
SQL injection exercise and CS atom these
three attacks are the most important
attacks available on web applications in
which attacker executes unwanted action
in web applications to trick the user
absolutely correct so basically if this
is the browser and if this is the user
who is using the browser so what can
happen for example if user is trying to
send or transfer money from his bank
account to his friend's bank account so
what can happen
the attacker can trick the user so what
will happen it will basically change the
query of the user and it will transfer
the fund from his account to somebody
else account so this is the kind of
scenario inside CSS and this is a simple
scenario but they are multiple scenarios
are available in CSRF that we will talk
later in the videos so here's the
scenario right so he is the victim who
is trying to use web site who is trying
to use a web server right and he has his
cookies right so what is the use of this
attack in terms of attacker
so attacker will trick the user and user
will automatically redirect you some of
the
malicious website he will not be direct
to the genuine website he will redirect
to some malicious websites what can
happen now attacker can basically steal
the cookie or session of this victim and
can take over the complete session and
can manipulate his personal accounts as
well so this is the kind of CSRF attacks
when attacker manipulates the query
generated by the victim all right
this is all about CSRF and the process
of csr