which is avoiding or detecting other
vulnerability now in this section we are
going to take a look at various points
first we will learn about buffer
overflow vulnerability addiction then we
will learn about denial of service and
their detection brute-forcing attack
password forcing attack on the web
applications and then we will learn
about some more file uploads and
transferable abilities and their
detection buffer overflow vulnerability
detection so in this video we are going
to take a look at couple of points we
will learn about what is buffer overflow
validity and then later we will learn
about some detection techniques of
buffer overflow first what is buffer
overflow one little bit is so you can
see here that what is buffer buffer
overflow is a kind of attack where
program tries to insert more data than
memory allocated in before it means the
memory is less but you are putting more
data in the memory so at that time
buffer overflow can happen so what it
can do it can basically crash your
program of corrupt your data it can wipe
out your data it can crash your data and
you are not able to use that kind of web
application so now we are going to learn
about buffer overflow inside Metiria
Kali Linux so open motilal inside Kali
Linux and then we will perform some
practical on buffer overflow techniques
so I'm here at Kali Linux operating
system and we need to start the mighty
leader inside the browser so here this
is over smutty lady and we need to
perform buffer overflow attack in the
blood location
so to do that let me find out the buffer
overflow so select OS 2017 select
injection other attacks and then you
will find buffer overflow and click on
repeater so here it is right repeater
please enter string to repeat and number
of times Ruby before that I need to
check the theory behind it so it may
click on hints and videos and if they
click on buffer overflow so this is
buffer overflow right what is buffer
overflow as I already told you but let's
repeat it buffer overflow may occur when
input is too large to fit in inside the
space allocated I already told you that
space is less and you are putting more
data inside it but this is called buffer
overflow so narrow down the exact
length of input that overflows of a
little input parameter this is the
exploitation right and this is example
Peas repeater is vulnerable right this
is the paged repeater which is one label
and the time to repeat has some
production and it is cast to an integer
even if you've overflowed time to repeat
by submitting a value larger than int
the system should cast the number the
thing is quite simple you can insert any
amount of data inside this webpage right
and this should not happen in actual web
application actual web application
should have limitation in the web pages
right
you cannot put more data than integer
limit and if you are able to insert more
data than the integer limit obviously
this is a case of buffer overflow all
right now let me show you how it works
so let me go back to the matinee
local Oh slash mati ledee hit enter and
here we need to select with on 17 other
buffer overflow and repeated so here you
can see it is asking that string to
repeat so we need to provide the string
here string means a kind of work for
example my string is hello alright and
number of times to repeat so I can
repeat the string millions of times or
billions of times if this web
application is vulnerable to buffer
overflow attack for example let me try
with
20 lakh times because this is above the
integer limit or any other limiters
right so you can click on repeat string
and you can see here that web
application has been crashed completely
right you can see here I am NOT able to
see any options available here I'm not
able to do anything on this web
application so this can happen if buffer
overflow is available in the web
application I have repeated that string
20 lakh times right and you can see here
that I am not able to open any option
which is available in the web
application right you cannot see any
button available in the Hat part right
it means the web application has been
pressed completely all right so this can
happen if user tries to insert more data
than the space located all right this is
called buffer overflow attack on a web
application and we have successfully
attacked on a web application and web
application is pressed now completely
all right now let me come back and yeah
now it is fine but at that time the web
application was pressed and that was a
problem because of buffer overflow
attack now you can click on reset DB to
reset your database alright so you have
learned that what is buffer overflow
attack and how it works how you can
perform a practical on buffer overflow
inside an application and how you can
crash the complete web application by
using buffer overflow now the question
comes here how you can detect or avoid
this kind of vulnerability what are the
best practices to avoid buffer overflow
so buffer overflow doesn't happen with
every coding length absolutely correct
because not each and every programming
language is vulnerable to buffer
overflow some programming languages are
vulnerable and some are not for example
buffer overflow happens in C language
absolutely correct it happens in C
language but languages like Java Python
and dotnet
doesn't allow this kind of quality so
these kind of programming languages are
secure for buffer overflow that means
input validation input validation is
really important term because whatever
user is inputting in that web
application
first of all application should test it
that the input is
or not and after that it should send it
to the lab server but it's so input
validation is really necessary down to
avoid buffer overflow inside web
applications so this is all about buffer
overflow