hello and welcome students to the
section 2 of the course information
gathering so what we are going to learn
in this section first of all we will
learn that how you can gather
information about web application all
the basic concepts then we will learn
about how you can identify the machines
and the OS of the web server then later
we will learn how you can find out the
port numbers and the services available
in the web applications and some more
spidering tools regarding websites so
first of all we are starting with the
discovering the infra off web
application in the first video of
section 2 we are going to learn that how
you can gather information about the web
application and then the techniques to
discover and gathering this information
so to do that we need to open the
browser of the operating system you can
use Windows or Kali Linux doesn't matter
so I'm using Kali Linux here and open
the browser of Kali Linux and then we
will open a particular website to gather
information about the web applications
so here I am at Kali Linux operating
system and first of all you need to open
the browser of Kali Linux so and open
google.com inside it hallee you can see
here that I have opened the Google
inside the Firefox now the website we
are going to visit is who is and hit
enter so you can see here that you can
see there are so many results available
regarding who is so which one is the
right one right because we cannot use
all these websites you can see in the
second page as well all these websites
are available but let me tell you which
many is useful for us so you can type
who dot is right and hit enter now you
can find out the real URL regarding who
is which is this one who dot is is the
right URL of who is Right who is search
domain name web site and IP tools are
available so click on that and open the
website
here-take so this is the search box
available inside the who eats website
here you can type the domain name as
well as the IP address right IP address
of web server or the website name you
can put here so for example I'm trying
to search information about the sample
website valve web comm right you guys
can also search it because it's a sample
website so anyone can use it so you can
type here one the web.com I want to
gather information about this website
the basic information right and you can
hit enter so now it is gathering
information from Internet and from the
destroyed directories and providing
information right here on one platform
now when you come down so you can see
here that this is the Registrar info
right the name you know DNS si the
server is this one right come down and
you can see here that these are the some
important dates available for example
when the domain will expire when it was
registered and when it was updated now
these are name servers IP address are
available this information is really
useful in pen testing process now come
down and you can see here that the name
of the company a kinetics limited this
is the address of the company this is
the city Tortola this is the postal code
available right country and phone number
is also available so if you want to
contact to the company then you can use
this phone number if you want to send a
mail to the company then you can use
this administrator at the rate a
kinetics dot-com as I already told you
that this website is a sample website
provided by a kinetics company alright
so this information is actually useful
and you are gathering information about
any web site or web application all
right let me come up and if you can
click on history
so it is loading history for us that you
can see here there are 285 historical
who is it records now
Indiana's records
about the DNS domain name server is
really important you can see here that
all the information about DNS is
available here now
diagnostics you can see here that there
are two entities available here one is
ping and one is traces so what is ping
ping is basically a process to check
that the web server is live or not so
you can see here that they showing us
the requests coming from the server it
means that server is life this website
is actually running and this is the IP
address of web server now if you come
down then you can see this is the trace
trace route means the number of hopes in
between two machines for example my
system is running one live webcam
website right so I'm connected with the
server of Walda web dot-com so how many
hopes are between me it means my system
and the server of Walla web.com which is
listed here right so you can see here it
is showing us 22 hopes are available
between me and the server of the babcom
so these all information is actually
available on this website
right you can also try other websites
regarding who is but this website is
actually the right one so remember who
dot is is the website which can provide
you all the basic information and you
can gather all the information right
here on one platform so this is all
about discovering information about a
website
you