welcome ladies and gentlemen to this
video today we're talking about web
security and again we're talking about
injections especially about SQL
injections to follow up with this
tutorial you can with it rule of songs
pizza es y dot yes and heck decide if
you want to yeah so but first everything
you learn here is for securing your own
web applications and not to hack anybody
else's so this is legal and it's really
evil
so also I'm not liable for any special
or direct or indirect damage for any
other damage resulting from the use of
information presented in this video so
let's get started with injections again
an injection is used by an attacker to
introduce or inject code into a
vulnerable computer program and change
the course of execution so we can use
anything that posts something on the
server which uses an SQL statement
behind to get data from the database all
right so we can even use the order thing
we even can use the Select box here if
you go to the Select you see that we
have here different types of values all
right so if you're if you are in hacker
you can test out if these values have to
have something have something to do with
the SQL statement even simply by
changing the value so I change this to
two for vegetarian and as you see I
thought the salami pizza and prosciutto
pizza so it has to do something
with an SQL statement behind so this
value is used by an SQL statement so we
can use this well you feel for injecting
our SQL so what we are going to do today
is we're trying to output every username
inside of this menu so we want to output
Pizza the username here and password
inside of the ingredients okay so let's
take a look at the SQL injections so
there is probably a statement in the
only server that looks something like
this select star from pizza where type
equals type we don't know how this field
is called we don't know how this table
is called and we don't know how many
fields are selected there but as we know
a hacker always tries to some sometimes
he tries 500 times and then it works so
we have to test out how many fields we
have there and as I know how many fields
we have there are six fields and we can
simply try this out by making a union
select so what a union select does is it
combines two tables or to select
statements within one within one
resulting table okay so it selects T's
and combines this table with this table
so we could inject a select username and
use a password from user and this will
probably look something like this
so if we copy this and I try to work
just in
my database you see that it combines
these two tables so if we try to inject
these SQL statement inside of here we
simply have to do Union select then 1 2
3 4 5 6 we have to test it out if you
don't know how the table structure works
behind so if we do something like this I
copy this can you see that we will get
back
Oh copy this of course we have to go to
what Darien if we do this you see that
we get back to 4 5 so we know that the
second field is displayed as the as the
headline here so we can inject the
username inside of the second statement
and the fourth statement are the
ingredients so we could and check the
passport inside of the ingredients so if
we copy our statement and we of course
the hacker has to know how the field in
the table is called so if he doesn't
know that in the field is called user
underline name or user underline
password then he will not get any
results but as we tested it out 100
times we found out that to use a name
inside of the table is called user
underline name and the password is
called usual underline peewee PW so if
we again select our vegetarian here we
will get
everything from the user table so we
have to use a name and to use the
password and as you see the password is
stored as plain text inside of the
database and this is really really bad
it's a real really bad habit okay so we
have to employ one with this password we
have to employ two with this password we
have to Peter with this password and we
have the salmon with the password so we
can now simply login with employee to
employ two and put in the password and
we're locked in as employed two and now
we can post something evil inside of the
secret jet okay so this is pretty pretty
bad so why does this work okay so let's
have a look at the Pizza list here
so again I'm using the old MySQL query
to get this bad result and this is
another way how to do this because this
is really bad we don't have a prepared
statement and we don't have a
placeholder so what we do here is get
all pizza entries select star from pizza
there is nothing to inject because there
is no verbal as you see we have a
variable called type and this is the
cookie type so we save something in a
cookie and we can look this up if we set
post type which is this then
with that new cookie with the post well
you Pizza type for 30 days so we will
have this every time we enter the order
page because we have a cookie here set
for this alright so and inside of these
if a cookie is set we set the type to
the cookie and our cookie looks like
this statement and this is our cookie
okay and we simply say select if we
select a vegetarian or meat we have
something to inject because if type
equals one we have something here to
inject okay so we can say and check the
type and the type is set to Union select
1 2 3 4 5 from user and put the user
name and user password so this will make
a query on the database and for every
row we will print out these data and as
we have seen in the database we get back
something like this so it will print out
every every single row until we're done
and we are just playing this for the
user so how can we change this at first
get rid of the oh my SQL and we're using
the PDO
so what we do here is we call the PDO
object that we create in my handler and
we saved it in the TB okay and then we
create a prepared statement for that and
this simply gets pre passed from the
database and the database knows how
these statement looks like so everything
that is inserted in this placeholder
with the colon will be ignored if there
is another SQL statement so it executes
this with the placeholder code type and
if there is any SQL in it it will simply
parse it as a string and not as a
different SQL statement so this won't
work anymore so now we get we will fetch
all the all the all our results and we
say for each or while or whatever pizza
is row and ten we get for every single
row we have here we output our
information so if we try this again you
see it's not working anymore so if I
type in vegetarian it will show me what
Taran if I type in meat it shows me the
meat if I type in alt it gives me all
but what happens if I try to inject my
SQL again so we're copying this again
and we have our Union Select statement
here we click on select and it's not
working so now we have a safe
application here and
I hope you enjoyed this video you
learned a lot and of course don't forget
to give me thumbs up to hit the
subscribe button and to share this video
everywhere on the Internet so see you in
the next video bye