welcome ladies and gentlemen to the
third video of web security and hacking
today we are talking about JavaScript
injections and first off everything you
learn here is for securing your own web
applications not to hack anybody else's
because it's illegal and it's very evil
so just use this information to make
your web applications more secure and of
course unreliable for any special direct
or indirect damage for any other damage
resulting from the use of information
presented in this video so what is
injection I have a citation from
Wikipedia which is directly on point and
injection is used by an attacker or
hacker to introduce or inject code into
a vulnerable computer program and change
the course of execution so what this
means we need something an input field a
text field a form where we can post a
code to the server and this code has to
be stored in a database and this code
that we save into a database has to be
shown on the website to be executable so
we save something in a database which is
later on used for displaying on the
webpage and execute our code because
every browser executes JavaScript so
today we are learning about is
injections so we need to store a string
into the database which could be
something like script load my script
loaded and this string is displayed on
website and browser execute the
JavaScript code so this will result in
something like this and you can use the
webpage root of sums Pizza es y es for
studying this video and I'm using my
local host portion and I'm going to the
guestbook
as you see we have something to inject
here and I try to I'd write a script
script we closed the script tags and
inside of here we simply use alert you
got hacked
for example okay and what happens if we
post this all right every time
the guestbook side is loaded to the
browser checks there is a script tag and
then execute the script inside of the
script tags so it displays you've got
hacked in alert box so if we take a look
at the page source we have our script
here you see just place the script tag
and execute the code inside of here and
if we take a look at the adair h source
we see we could do anything
with JavaScript so we see okay there is
an ID we copy this and we want to hide
the guest book the complete gas book
okay so I write a script script and
inside of here
I say document dot get element by ID
posts my ID inside of here then we say
style with zip bility style visibility
and we set the visibility to hidden okay
so if we post this to the server
you see our guestbook is hidden now
because we add with our script we add a
star
on our guest book which says
visibility:hidden of course you can
inject anything inside of this if the
creator of this web application does not
secure the web application so we could
go to google google jquery and go to the
hosted libraries and we could inject
jquery for example i mean there is
already jquery on this webpage so it
does not make any sense
but if i would i could post the jquery
library inside of here then make a
script and use jQuery to make the
guestbook with a bowl again for example
so I would post something like this get
my ID and say CSS and with the bill it t
visible with bull so try this and as you
see D gas book is visible again and we
have injected jQuery inside of our
guestbook so this is pretty evil you see
visibility visible and inside of here we
have our jQuery library and here we use
our jQuery so what can we do to make
that not work so we learned about the
strict tax function in PHP before so I
use this for my
for my sin feedback form and we need to
make sure that nobody can inject script
X anymore because a script tag is simply
a HTML tag which could be injected so if
we do something like this to our insert
guestbook every HTML tag will be
stripped away also the script tag so if
we save this and go back to our page and
we're posting something like this and we
post the script again and we say for
example alert again for example this
will not work anymore because if I send
a feedback you see it strips the script
tags away and we're not allowed anymore
do you inject JavaScript so this is one
way to make sure that you cannot in
check JavaScript to your web application
so we are pretty secure now okay
so that's it for this video don't forget
to give me a thumbs up to subscribe to
my channel and to share this video
everywhere and we see us in the next
video bye