welcome ladies and gentlemen this new
tutorial today we are talking about web
security again we are talking about
injections especially about SQL
injections today so you can use the web
page relations Pizza es y es for
following this tutorial I will reset
this page every now and then so that you
have a great experience hacking this web
page okay so let's get back to the slide
show web security so first of everything
you learn here is for securing your own
web applications and not to Hank anybody
else's okay and because it's illegal and
it's evil and of course I'm not liable
for any special direct or indirect
damage or for any other damage resulting
from the use of information presented in
this video so injections again what is
the injection according to Wikipedia
injection is used by an attacker or
hacker to introduce or inject code into
a vulnerable computer program and change
the course of execution so for an SQL
injection we need a formula that uses
SQL an SQL statement to do something in
in our web application so with web with
SQL injections we can select insert drop
update everything from a database okay
so if our web application is not secure
enough of course if our web application
is secure this is not possible
and we will learn about prepared
statements about the PDO PHP data object
which gives us the opportunity of
prepared statements with placeholders
and all that stuff and we will learn
about that a little bit later but to use
to make use of SQL injections
Hecker has to know the code-behind or
has to guess what what's the code like
that's working on a server so for a
login form it's possible that you have
asked a SQL statement that looks
something like this select star from
user user is our user table where every
user is stored and then we select the
user where the username is equals to
username which we input here for example
and then user password equals to the
user password which we input here for
example so if a hacker knows that we're
not using a prepared statement and we
are using just the variables here he
could inject some SQL here because the
database does not parse the SQL
statement before and knows where is the
hole and then put the placeholders in in
these holes because the database simply
parses the SQL statement and this could
end up with an injection that looks
something like this we say select star
from users where username equals and
then we close the we close the rotation
mark for username and then say or 1
equals 1 route the route or double dash
is simply commenting out everything what
is behind that route or hash tag ok or
double dashes so this this hack only
works if there is something else wrong
with the web application so let's take a
look at our web application so we have
my handler here
every time our login page gets fired it
goes to the my handler inside of this if
statement and of course this web
application is just programmed in two
hours I don't use any object-oriented
style it's just straight off and really
really damp but here we have our select
statement and as you see we simply input
our our variables so it's injectable at
first okay but then we have to count how
many rows we get back and if the web
program has something like is greater
than 0 then we can inject this because
if we say or one equals one and one
equals one is always true a select
statement gives back true or false and
if it's true it gives you back every row
and if not it's it's if if it's false
you don't get any row so we make this
select statement true because we select
every every user where user name is
empty or one equals one and one equals
one is always true so we will get back
every user in this database so if there
are five users in a database we will get
back every five users so the row count
will result in five and if there is
something like result equals one this
whole heck would not work because the
number of the result of num rows is five
and not one but if there is something
like greater than zero inside of the web
program then it will work because five
is greater than zero and this is great
so let's try it out we simply say
rotation mark or one equals one route
login
and as you see we are locked in and we
have a username great so we can do
stupid stuff in the backend creating new
pizzas or posting in a secret chat or I
don't know what you want what you want
to do so that's it for this video
no that's not it for this video because
I want to show you how you can make this
web application most acute so okay this
is the don't do this part
okay so we're commenting this out and do
this why use the videos PDO object so I
show you we create a new video object
which has some functions like a prepared
statement function and we use this video
simply by telling we have name post
username and then we make a prepared
statement and instead of setting our
variables inside of this prepared
statement we put placeholders inside of
it like : 1 column 2 and then we say
execute this statement and inside of the
execution we could say that the
placeholder 1 has to be filled with the
variable name and the empty placeholder
2 has to be filled with their password
ok so and then we simply make a rope
round and if this is equal 1 then it's
we will login this user ok great so this
is pretty secure now because if we try
it again
and say something like this login user
does not exist
great so you we are safe
what happens here so the prepared
statement gives you the opportunity to
make holes in inside of your SQL
statement okay so we call a function on
our PDO object which is created inside
of the variable DB and where is it here
and then we have a function this called
prepare and there is a similar function
in almost every programming language all
right so use always a prepared statement
and use placeholders instead of
variables what happens the PDO object
sends this request to the database the
database parses this statement knows
there is a hole on this two points
because if there is a del a colon it
knows okay this is a placeholder for
something and I know the complete
statement and if there is a second
statement to get sent inside of display
soulders just use it as a simple string
don't do anything else with it so it
parses the statement before and then it
gets back sense the T placeholders to
the database and the database execute
the statement with the variables for DES
placeholders and if there is a second
statement inside of it it simply use it
it use it as a string and not as a
special insert statement or something
else so this is pretty secure now
but what we also have to do you should
use password encryption because this is
pretty unsecure if you have a password
without any encryption but we will learn
about this in the next video so what are
we going to learn in next video in the
next video we are using this formula to
output anything that's inside of the
user database so instead of displaying
the pizzas here we are using test form
to display the username and the password
alright so that's it for this video if
you liked it don't forget to give me
thumbs up
to hit the subscribe button and we see
us in the next video
don't forget to share this video of
course bye