welcome ladies and gentlemen to the
second video of this tutorial series we
will learn about web security and at the
beginning everything you learn here is
for securing your own web applications
not to hack anybody else's because this
is illegal and of course I'm not liable
for any special direct or indirect
damage for any other damage resulting
from the use of the information
presented in this video so just use this
information to make your own
applications better more secure but do
not hack anybody else because this is
evil and it's Leu so we start with
injections like in the last video an
injection is used by an attacker to
introduce or inject code into a
vulnerable computer program and change
the colors of execution so this is the
citation from wikipedia and today we
will learn about HTML injections so what
do we need for an HTML injection we need
a heck ball website or web application
which does not try to figure out which
content gets saved into the database and
which content from the database gets
displayed on the web application show so
they don't try to delete HTML tags or
something like that so we need to store
a string in the database through a form
or a text text input and for example
like h1 and closing tag h1 and this
string has to be displayed on the
website and it will result in something
like we see here so we try this straight
out on our guestbook ok I will use my
guestbook on the on the localhost so I
go to the guestbook
and we try an HTML injection with h1 and
h2 and you write something here give
feedback and as we see we inject it some
HTML here ok this is pretty cool because
we can do some stuff and write in
somebody else's name for example I login
as admin a password is admin 1 2 3 4 and
we log in and go to the secret check ok
so then we take a look at the page
source so if we have some chat here and
we write something like my message and
then these tags closes that closing tags
get called automatically or edit
automatically within the PHP code so
let's try to do something to write a
message in somebody else's name so I try
to copy this code ok
and I post it inside of here so I can
write my message here hello
work hard this is the message which gets
shown as admin then we make a closing
tag two closing tags which is for these
two panels here so one for the div with
class column small nine and one for the
div with the class panel row ok then we
open a new div battle row difficult as
panel row and here we write a different
name like salmon then I say I hate my
job for example and we write a message
in somebody else's name which is pretty
evil so let's give it a try
and as you see I posted as admin hello
work hard and additionally I added a
second a second message in somebody
else's name Simon what I hate my job
so this is pretty evil and this should
not work in a secure web application so
how can we change this we need to delete
every HTML tag before we save it into
the database and how do we do this in H
in PHP this is a very very unsecure
application I have a video for the
secure version I I have written inside
of here
and I have a really really old MySQL
collection for for the unsecure version
to show you how it's not done and I can
show you the the comments in some of the
next videos but for now we go into the
send secret chat so we have a clean
string here and we say insert this okay
but what happens if we say strip tags
every HTML tag gets stripped away except
of every tag that I insert here a second
parameter so I can inject some latex in
my deck in my text but it will not work
the same way anymore so if I write Simon
and I hate my job again
will not work anymore in here work hard
work hard if I do this this will not
work anymore because every DIF will get
stripped away so if I post this it ends
up in admin work hard and Simon I hate
my job and there is something similar in
every in every programming language so
you simply have to delete every HTML
deck and then add only the HTML decks
that you allow so if we want to send a
link we're still allowed to send a link
for example I make a link H RAF BW /
Leslie google.com and if I post us as
you see we're still allowed to send a a
tag because we allowed it within here
within the strip text function the strip
tags function is especially for PHP but
there is a function that is that uses
the same principle in every HTML in
every programming language okay so but
how can we still send something in in
somebody else's name if we take a look
at the at this adda form that we have
here we have a hidden input field with a
value admin let's try to change this in
I don't know myself
for example let's see what's happened if
I post this form to the server Oh
hidden field is used 40 for the username
and this is also hackable as you see so
I'm still allowed to change this to
Simon and write something like I hate my
job and sent this and you see Simon
hates his job so this is still not a
pretty cool so what can we do as you see
we have a post username but when we log
in into our application we have a login
we make a session which is called
Vinnitsa which means a user in German
and set them to the name which is posted
in a login form so maybe we use this
session 4 for the username and not the
post parameter in the in the hidden
field because this is pretty unsecure so
let's dry what happens if I say session
B not sir and change this and I reload
my page and what happens if I still add
something like Simon and then I write I
hate my job
and give the feedback what happens you
see I don't write as Simon anymore I
write as admin because I take the
session for posting to the server which
is a bit more secure than using a hidden
field which is changeable by anybody
whom who moves HTML a little bit and
knew the inspect function so I guess
we're pretty safe here for now of course
we're not secure against any
against any SQL injection but we will
learn that's this in a little bit in a
later video so i have here some comments
that i will show to you when we talk
about SQL injections but i guess we're
finished and done with the HTML
injections and if you liked this video
don't forget to give me thumbs up to hit
the subscribe button and we see us in
the next video don't forget to share
this video everywhere bye