welcome ladies and gentlemen to this new
tutorial today we are talking about web
security and first everything you learn
here is for securing your own web
application and not to hack anybody
else's so I'm not liable for any special
direct or indirect damage or for any
other damage resulting from the use of
the information presented in this video
all right so afternoon this we're
learning about injections so I have
prepared a citation from Wikipedia and
an injection is used by an attacker and
hacker to introduce or inject code in do
vulnerable computer program and change
the course of execution so what does
this mean we need to have an input field
a text field
formula to post our code to the server
which saves our code inside of an
database and then this code has to be
shown on the web page for any visitor so
that this code can get executed on the
web page so we save something in the
database this string this code is
presented on the web page and executes
on a web page and changes our way how
our web application works so I have
prepared and web page it's a restaurant
a pizza restaurant and the website is
visible at WWF Suns Pizza e sy dot ES
and
of course you can try to hack this page
because it's created for educational
purposes so please start I can reset the
webpage every now and then so that it's
usable for others who want to learn a
bit about securing their web
applications so I'm working on my local
host because I want to change the code
in the back end so that I can show you
how to do it in the right way so that
the page is not hackable anymore so okay
this is a page a pizza restaurant we
have the opening hours we can order
pizza we have a little description here
and if we click on order or we click
here a path on order we get a menu with
some pizzas we can choose between
vegetarian pizza
and meat pizza so this is a formula
which gets posted on the web server I
guess so I created it of course it does
but if you're working and on your
securing your web applications you have
things like a hacker so this is an input
field and here we can post something on
the server we can inspect this here
because we see ok this is a formula it's
action there is something we could
inject probably so then we have a
guestbook which is pretty cool because
we can enter something here like lucas
lucas post this instantly and ok i've
posted lucas lucas often so maybe I type
in kg and posters and as you see the
name gets posted and the message gets
posted it saves something inside of the
database and displays this data on a
database so this is something where we
can inject something too
oh heck this page so if we look at this
we see that we have a form here and
action on something and it's a post
method so we can inject something here
probably then we have a login page and
of course this is a formula which posts
something on the web server so this is
probably injectable so if we knew the
username and password
we can log in we will we will learn how
to hack this page how to get the
usernames and passwords if your web
application is not secure enough and we
can login and then we can create a new
pizza here and we have a secret chat
where all the employees and the admin
and T boss could write something and
here's the difference between the
guestbook
that we can write a text here give
feedback and if we post this it takes
the name with which we logged in so
probably we can change this name to
somebody else's so that we can write in
somebody else's name so this would be
evil so maybe we can do this so that's
something we will learn in the next
video so that's the first video in the
next video we will learn about HTML
injection in the second video we will
learn about JavaScript injections and in
the last tutorial series videos of just
a tutorial series we will learn about
SQL injection so please give me thumbs
up if you like this video don't forget
to hit the subscribe button share this
video and try to hack the rule of sounds
pizza e sy dot es and we see us in the
next video bye