hi and welcome in this lesson I'm going
to teach you all the web works as an
overall process the web is a way of
transmitting data over the Internet
using the HTTP protocol and HTML to
access information from the web you need
a web browser such as Firefox Chrome
Internet Explorer Safari and so on the
web can be summarized as a series of
interactions between clients and servers
in this slide you can see how the web
works in a nutshell
first you request a web page in a web
browser and DNS check the domain name of
the website you entered and then the web
server sends back the data for the
requested web page a web server is just
a piece of software running on the
operating system of a server that allows
connections to access a web application
the most common web servers are Apache
and Tomcat these servers have normal
directory and structures like any other
computer now let's see what you need to
know about HTTP HTTP is a plain text
protocol so there is no security or
privacy when using HTTP HTTP is the
foundation of communication for web
pages and has various requests the most
importantly quests are get and paused
get requests retweets data so every time
you browse to a page you are performing
a get request post request it is used
for submission of web forms for example
login forms an important thing to
remember is that HTTP
was not created to handle web
transactions that requires a high degree
of security and privacy you can inspect
all the information of how HTTP operates
with tools such as Wireshark the
solution for this problem is HTTP
yes because uses an encrypted protocol
called Secure Sockets Layer commonly
known as SSL the S stands for secure
which means you are going to communicate
with the website over an encrypted
Channel HTTP is best suited for
preventing man-in-the-middle attacks and
is dropping from packet analyzes and
it's always better to use so that's it
for now thanks for watching and I will
see you next time
you