hi and welcome in this tutorial I'm
going to show you how to prepare your
web testing lab using zamp
and all wasp zamp is a local Apache
server which comes along with PHP my
sequel and a bunch of other good stuff
basically allows you to run a web server
on your local machine and os is a free
open source vulnerable web application
designed for beginners to learn web
application security and hacking so
let's go ahead and download these
applications by going to sourceforge.net
and search for exam and click the
download button I already downloaded the
program so I will skip ahead but don't
worry because the installation is very
basic once done with the installation
open the program and start Apache web
server and my sequel database now you
need to go to exam directory and look
for htdocs directory that's where os web
application is going to be installed to
download the vulnerable web application
search for OS and select version and
then download the zip file so again I
will skip ahead after the download has
finished extract the zip file and copy
all the files to examp htdocs directory
now open your browser and go to one to
seven zero zero one you may need to
reset the database by clicking reset the
DB link if there is a database error so
when you get into the system there is a
menu on the Left where you can see
different types of attacks like sequel
injection cross-site scripting and many
more but I will cover these attacks in
another tutorial so that's it for this
lecture thanks for watching and I'll see
you next
time
you