hi and welcome to the course my name is
Nikolai and I'll be teaching you how to
hack websites using multiple techniques
now the course is designed to take you
from scratch with no previous knowledge
about web security or hacking so let's
see what I'm going to cover during the
course first you'll begin by exploring
the basics of world wide web and how
HTTP protocol works using Wireshark
which is a network protocol analyzer
then I'm going to teach you how to
prepare your web testing lab by
installing always web hacking
environment and then how to use Vega
platform to test the security of web
applications once done with that I will
move to sequel injection in this part
you will learn how to bypass login forms
and how to write sequel queries to find
databases tables and sensitive
information such as user names and
passwords I'm also going to show you how
to use sequel map and how to prevent
your site from sequel injection then I
will show you how to hack WordPress
sites using WP scan which is the
security scanner that helps you to find
security weaknesses within WordPress
installations so after completing this
part I will move to cross-site scripting
attacks where you will learn the stored
and reflected attacks you will also
learn how to take full control over the
victim machine using be framework and
weave Lee and lastly I'm going to cover
some social engineering attacks like
cross-site request forgery and phishing
after completing this course you will
understand common web hacking techniques
used by hackers and you will have a
practical knowledge about
vulnerabilities that affect web
applications now please remember that
all information exposed in this course
is for educational purpose and shall
only be used to expand knowledge and not
for causing malicious or damaging the
types
okay so now let's see who is this course
for this course is for beginners or
anyone who wants to learn about web
application hacking so that's it for now
thanks for watching and I will see you
inside
you