hi and welcome back in this lesson I'm
going to teach you how to use Vega Vega
the free web security scanner for
testing the security of web applications
this tool can help you find
vulnerabilities such as sequel injection
cross-site scripting blind sequel
injection and a lot more Vega is written
in Java and runs on Linux and Windows
but for this tutorial I'm going to use
the Windows version so let's go ahead
and download this tool by going to
subgraph dot-com slash Vega and click
the download button and then select the
version I already done this so I will
skip ahead after the installation has
completed you should see the Vega icon
on your desktop
open the program and you will see this
simple interface which is very easy to
use now in order to scan with Vega
you will click new scan and then enter
the rest of the website you want to scan
and in here you need to select the
different types of modules that you will
be scanning for so I will scan only for
sequel injection for that I need to turn
everything off by unchecking the ones I
don't want to scan and scroll down and
find all sequel injection and then click
Next now here is the identity but you
don't need to worry too much about these
so click finish to start the scan this
process can take some time so I will
skip ahead to where the scan is complete
okay now the scan is complete as you can
see I have some sequel injection of
vulnerabilities here and on the left is
the scan alerts now click to drop it
down and here are all the pages that
have high risk to sequel injection and
to get more information just click the
link and you will see detailed
information about
the alert in this panel if you scroll
down you will see important information
about the problem some discussion the
impact and the suggested remediation
this information helps you to write your
report very easily if you are doing web
penetration testing for a company that's
why Vega is a great free tool to use so
that's it for now thanks for watching
and I will see you next time
you