hi and welcome back in this tutorial I'm
going to show you the difference between
HTTP and HTTPS using wireshark which is
the network analyzer Wireshark is
available for free at Wireshark website
and you can download for Windows and
Linux so let's get started
the tool is really easy to use actually
all you have to do is go up here and
click capture options and then select
the interface which you want to use in
my case I have internet connection from
my wireless interface now press Start to
capture all the traffic on that
interface first I will demonstrate why
HTTP is unsecured when browsing the
Internet by going to a site which uses
HTTP and now I will try to log in using
new user for the username and let me in
for the password ok so let's do it
another site with HTTPS to see the
difference and if you look at the
address box you can see a lock this
means that the secure socket layer has
been established on this page so again I
will log in using my user name and
password and let's switch back to
Wireshark and change the filter to HTTP
and here you can see the get and
response package which contains
information like my MAC address route
address IP source destination address
and so on now let's find the post packet
which contains the username and password
for the HTTP site so go ahead and change
the filter to HTTP request method equal
equal and in caps post and click on HTML
4 as you can see here is the login name
and the password if you don't see this
HTML form use right click and select
follow TCP stream and you will see the
username and password as well okay so
now I'm going to see the traffic from
HTTP site for that I need to change the
filter to SSL and here you can see the
packets are encrypted using transport
layer security protocol or TLS basically
you are communicating over an encrypted
channel with the website which we all
want this type of connection is
necessary if you do web transaction
using your credit card or any other
sensitive information so that's it for
now
thanks for watching and I will see you
next time
you