okay so welcome back in this video I'm
going to teach you a basic understanding
of sequel injection sequel is short for
structured query language and it's
language used for database management in
short sequel tells databases what to do
so before we start if you know what
sequel injection and databases are
sequel injection is one of the most
common web hacking technique used for
accessing the database of the website an
attacker can get all the details from
the database by accessing data bypassing
logins or shut down the sequel server
now let's understand what is a database
databases are basically a structure of
tables where each table contains user
IDs passwords web page details and more
so I will switch to my computer and show
you how a database looks like by going
to one two seven zero zero one slash PHP
my admin' i forgot to mention that examp
also comes with PHP myadmin
which is a database management tool and
on the left you can see some databases
for example I'm going to select NOAA's
database but please remember I'm not
hacking anything in this tutorial this
is just to give you a basic
understanding to see how database works
behind the scene as you can see here we
have all the tables to select a table
just click the one you want to retrieve
information in my case I'm going to
select accounts and you can see the
username and the password for all the
accounts on the database you can edit
change the rights or delete a specific
account now let's learn some basic
queries for sequel so go ahead and click
sequel up here and let's retrieve
data from the table using select
statement so type select Asterix from
which means everything from the table
and the table name and the way you end
the sequel query is by putting a
semicolon and let's go ahead and execute
the query by pressing ctrl + Enter and
you can see all the data from the table
let's say you want to check who is admin
from accounts for that you need to type
select username coma is admin from
accounts and the user names we true have
admin rights
another important sequel query is where
statement for example imagine if you
want to get all users who have the same
password you can use the where statement
by typing select username password from
accounts where password equal password
and if you execute the query you will
see the usernames with the same password
but for that you need to know the
password now let's say you have an
account with username John and password
is password so when you try to log in to
a website
the sequel syntax will be like this
select username coma password from table
name where username equals own and
password equal password if the username
and password are correct then you will
successfully log in ok so now I believe
that you have a basic understanding of
sequel databases so that's it for now
thanks for watching and I will see you
next time
you