okay so welcome back in this tutorial
I'm going to show you how to bypass
login screens using sequel injection
sequel injection is the code injection
technique used to hack data applications
in which malicious sequel statements are
inserted into an entry field for
execution so let's get started by going
first to user info sequel and extract
the county tales from the database
sometimes it is better to know how the
sequel query looks like for that you can
type a single quote in the name field
and press Enter and you can see the
query down here which is select from
accounts where username is what you have
passed in and password whatever you have
passed in now in order to view the
account details you need to type in
single quote or one equal one this one
equal one is a true statement so you can
type any true statement like 4 equal 4 6
equals 6 and so on and to escape from
the password field
use the comment symbol this common
symbol will ignore the password field
when the query is executed on the server
so go ahead and press view account
details and you can see all the
usernames and passwords from the
database you can also use the same
statement single quote 1 equal 1 and the
comment symbol to log in and you can see
I have successfully logged as admin ok
now let's look out and see another
example let's say you know the user name
is John but you don't know the password
for that you need to type John single
quote and the comment symbol to ignore
the password field for John in my case
and press login
and up here you can see I'm logged as
John now let's understand the sequel
query behind the scene
and this is how the sequel query will
look like when you are trying to login
to a web application select from table
name this can be any name where username
is whatever name you have typed if the
username is in the database for example
John then this will be true and the
trick here is when you put 1 equal 1 or
4 equal 4 this will also validate as
true and to bypass the password field I
have used the comment symbol which will
ignore the last part of the query that's
why you are able to log in without using
a password so that's it for now thanks
for watching and I will see you next
time
you